<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30112158</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2008-3289</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Iranian journal of microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Iran J Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enteroviruses and Adenoviruses in stool specimens of paralytic children- can they be the cause of paralysis?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>194</StartPage><EndPage>201</EndPage><MedlinePgn>194-201</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Acute flaccid paralysis (AFP) is a complicated clinical syndrome with a wide range of potential etiologies. Several infectious agents including different virus families have been isolated from AFP cases. In most surveys, Non-polio Enteroviruses (NPEVs) have been detected as main infectious agents in AFP cases; however, there are also some reports about <i>Adenovirus</i> isolation in these patients. In this study, NPEVs and <i>Adenoviruses</i> in stool specimens of AFP cases with or without Residual Paralysis (RP) with negative results for poliovirus are investigated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Nucleic acid extractions from 55 AFP cases were examined by nested PCR or semi-nested PCR with specific primers to identify NPEVs or <i>Adenoviruses</i>, respectively. VP1 (for <i>Enteroviruses</i>) and hexon (for <i>Adenoviruses</i>) gene amplification products were sequenced and compared with available sequences in the GenBank.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">From 55 fecal (37 RP+ and 18 RP-) specimens, 7 NPEVs (12.7%) (2 cases in RP+) and 7 <i>Adenoviruses</i> (12.7%) (4 cases in RP+) were identified. <i>Echovirus</i> types 3, 17 and 30, <i>Coxsackie virus</i> A8, and <i>Enterovirus</i> 80 were among NPEVs and <i>Adenoviruses</i> type 2 and 41 were also identified.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our finding shows that NPEVs and <i>Adenoviruses</i> may be isolated from the acute flaccid paralyses but there is no association between the residual paralyses and virus detection.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yousefi</LastName><ForeName>Maryam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Virology Department, School of Public Health, International Campus, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nejati</LastName><ForeName>Ahmad</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Virology Department, School of Public Health, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zahraei</LastName><ForeName>Seyed Mohsen</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Preventable Diseases Department, Center or Communicable Diseases Control, Ministry of Health and Medical Education, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahmoudi</LastName><ForeName>Sussan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Preventable Diseases Department, Center or Communicable Diseases Control, Ministry of Health and Medical Education, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parhizgari</LastName><ForeName>Najmeh</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Virology Department, School of Public Health, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farsani</LastName><ForeName>Seyed Mohammad Jazayeri</ForeName><Initials>SMJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Experimental Virology, Department of Medical Microbiology, Center for Infection and Immunity Amsterdam Academic Medical Center, University of Amsterdam, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahmoodi</LastName><ForeName>Mahmood</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nategh</LastName><ForeName>Rakhshandeh</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Virology Department, School of Public Health, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahmahmoodi</LastName><ForeName>Shohreh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Virology Department, School of Public Health, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Food Microbiology Research Center, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Iran J Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518404</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2008-3289</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute flaccid paralysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adenovirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-polio Enterovirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Residual paralysis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30112158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6087694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation Polio laboratory manual. 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israeli E, Agmon-Levin N, Blank M, Chapman J, Shoenfeld Y. Guillain&#x2013;Barr&#xe9; syndrome&#x2014;a classical autoimmune disease triggered by infection or vaccination. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol 2012;42:121&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20890797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx A, Glass JD, Sutter RW. Differential diagnosis of acute flaccid paralysis and its role in poliomyelitis surveillance. Epidemiol Rev 2000;22:298&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11218380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahmahmoodi S, Mehrabi Z, Eshraghian MR, Azad TM, Tabatabaie H, Yousefi M, et al. First detection of Enterovirus 71 from an acute flaccid paralysis case with residual paralysis in Iran. J Clin Virol 2008;42:409&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18403258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasian F, Saberbaghi T, Moosapour A. Role of Non-polioviruses in acute flaccid paralysis (AFP). J Gastroenterol Hepatol Res 2012;1:44&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) Laboratory surveillance for wild and vaccine-derived polioviruses--worldwide, January 2006&#x2013;June 2007. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2007;56:965&#x2013;969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17882127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoja ZO, Tabatabie H, Shahmahmoudi S, Nategh R. Comparison of cell culture with RT-PCR for Enterovirus detection in stool specimens from patients with acute flaccid paralysis. J Clin Lab Anal 2007;21:232&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6649082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17621362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolanaki E, Kottaridi C, Dedepsidis E, Kyriakopoulou Z, Pliaka V, Pratti A, et al. Direct extraction and molecular characterization of Enteroviruses genomes from human faecal samples. Mol Cell Probes 2008; 22: 156&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18378420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knipe D, Howley P, Cohen J, Griffin D, Lamb R, Martin M, et al. Fields virology, vol I Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; Philadelphia, PA: 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhole TN, Ayyagari A, Chowdhary R, Shakya AK, Shrivastav N, Datta T, et al. Non-polio Enteroviruses in acute flaccid paralysis children of India: Vital assessment before polio eradication. J Paediatr Child Health 2009;45:409&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19712176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghebremedhin B. Human adenovirus: Viral pathogen with increasing importance. Eur J Microbiol Immunol (Bp) 2014;4:26&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3955829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24678403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wold W, Ison M. (2013). Fields virology: Adenoviruses. 6th ed Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer New-York.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuang Y, Chiu C-H, Wong K-S, Huang J-G, Huang Y-C, Chang L-Y, et al. Severe Adenovirus infection in children. J Microbiol Immunol Infect 2003;36:37&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12741731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faulkner R, Van Rooyen C. Adenovirus types 3 and 5 isolated from the cerebrospinal fluid of children. Can Med Assoc J 1962;87:1123&#x2013;1125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1849838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13944538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simil&#xe4; S, Jouppila R, Salmi A, Pohjonen R. Encephalomeningitis in children associated with an Adenovirus type 7 epidemic. Acta Paediatr Scand 1970;59:310&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4315516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohtsuki N, Kimura S, Nezu A. Three cases with acute encephalopathy related with Adenovirus type 7 infection. No To Hattatsu 2000;32:68&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10655755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Clear D, Perera D, Krishnan S, Preston T, et al. Adenovirus type 21&#x2014;associated acute flaccid paralysis during an outbreak of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Sarawak, Malaysia. Clin Infect Dis 2003;36:550&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12594634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste MS, Maher K, Kilpatrick DR, Flemister MR, Brown BA, Pallansch MA. Typing of human Enteroviruses by partial sequencing of VP1. J Clin Microbiol 1999;37:1288&#x2013;1293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC84754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10203472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nejati A, Farahmand M, Tabatabaie H, Yousefi M, Mollaei-Kandelous Y, Shahmahmoodi S. Molecular typing of Non-polio Enteroviruses isolated from acute flaccid paralysis cases in Iran from 2010 to 2015. Virol Sin 2017;32:249&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6598875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28593536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingjun T, Yoshida H, Yan W, Lin L, Tsuji T, Shimizu H, et al. Molecular typing and epidemiology of non-polio Enteroviruses isolated from Yunnan province, the people&#x2019;s republic of China. J Med Virol 2008;80:670&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18297723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patti A, Santi A, Fiore L, Vellucci L, De Stefano D, Bellelli E, et al. Enterovirus surveillance of Italian healthy children. Eur J Epidemiol 2000;16:1035&#x2013;1038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11421472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuramitsu M, Kuroiwa C, Yoshida H, Miyoshi M, Okumura J, Shimizu H, et al. Non-polio Enterovirus isolation among families in Ulaanbaatar and Tov province, Mongolia: prevalence, intrafamilial spread, and risk factors for infection. Epidemiol Infect 2005;133:1131&#x2013;1142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2870349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16274512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gear J. Non-polio causes of polio-like paralytic syndromes. Rev Infect Dis 1984;6 Suppl 2:S379&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6740077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayward JC, Gillespie SM, Kaplan KM, Packer R, Pallansch M, Plotkin S, et al. Outbreak of poliomyelitis-like paralysis associated with Enterovirus 71. Pediatr Infect Dis J 1989;8:611&#x2013;616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2797956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apostol LN, Suzuki A, Bautista A, Galang H, Paladin FJ, Fuji N, et al. Detection of non-polio Enteroviruses from 17 years of virological surveillance of acute flaccid paralysis in the Philippines. J Med Virol 2012;84:624&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3500505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22337302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adewumi M, Japhet M, David O, Oluyege A, Adeniji J, Famurewa O. Non-polio Enteroviruses in faeces of children diagnosed with acute flaccid paralysis in Nigeria. Virol J 2017;14:175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5596853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28899411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao Z, Wang H, Liu Y, Li Y, Jiang P, Liu G, et al. Non-polio Enteroviruses from acute flaccid paralysis surveillance in Shandong province, China, 1988&#x2013;2013. Sci Rep 2014;4:6167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4141246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25145609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi P, Tabatabaie H, Gouya MM, Mahmudi M, Musavi T, Rad KS, et al. Direct identification of non-polio Enteroviruses in residual paralysis cases by analysis of VP 1 sequences. J Clin Virol 2009;45:139&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19394264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sriwanna P, Chieochansin T, Vuthitanachot C, Vuthitanachot V, Theamboonlers A, Poovorawan Y. Molecular characterization of human Adenovirus infection in Thailand, 2009&#x2013;2012. Virol J 2013;10:193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3693972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23758792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherry JD, Jahn CL. Herpangina: the etiologic spectrum. Pediatrics 1965;36:632&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5834068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart R, Miller D. Echovirus-17 infections in Britain 1969&#x2013;71. Lancet 1973;2:661&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4125630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Au GG, Beagley LG, Haley ES, Barry RD, Shafren DR. Oncolysis of malignant human melanoma tumors by Coxsackieviruses A13, A15 and A18. Virol J 2011;8:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3033357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21241513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laxmivandana R, Yergolkar P, Gopalkrishna V, Chitambar SD. Characterization of the non-polio Enterovirus infections associated with acute flaccid paralysis in South-Western India. PLoS One 2013;8:e61650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3632520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23630606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzara S, Muscillo M, La Rosa G, Marianelli C, Cattani P, Fadda G. Molecular identification and typing of Enteroviruses isolated from clinical specimens. J Clin Microbiol 2002;40:4554&#x2013;4560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC154598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12454151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivanova OE, Yurashko OV, Eremeeva TP, Baikova OY, Morozova NS, Lukashev AN. Adenovirus isolation rates in acute flaccid paralysis patients. J Med Virol 2012;84:75&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22052705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>