<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30483379</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2008-3289</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Iranian journal of microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Iran J Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Echovirus 30 and coxsackievirus A9 infection among young neonates with sepsis in Iran.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>258</StartPage><EndPage>265</EndPage><MedlinePgn>258-265</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Human enteroviruses (EV) are the most common causes of neonatal sepsis-like disease. The frequencies of EV including coxsackievirus A, coxsackievirus B and Echovirus serotypes have been studied in young infants (younger than three months) with sepsis. So far, the role of enteroviruses among neonates with sepsis was not determined in Ahvaz, Iran. Therefore, this study was aimed to evaluate the frequency of EV among hospitalized young infants with clinical signs and symptoms of sepsis in Ahvaz.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Blood specimens from 128 neonates (younger than 90 days), including 56 (43.75%) girls and 72 (56.25%) boys, were collected from hospitalized neonates with clinical signs and symptoms of sepsis-like symptoms. All blood samples were negative for bacterial culture. RNA was extracted from all sera and tested for detection of 5'UTR (Untranslated Region) of the EV by RT-PCR. To determine specific strains of EV, positive 5'UTR samples were further tested for detection of the VP1 region of EV by RT-PCR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Overall, 50/128 (39.06%) specimens, including 24 (48%) girls and 26 (52%) boys, were positive for EV. 21/50 (42%) specimens were positive for the VP1 region. Randomly, 8 positive VP1 were selected and sequenced. Analysis of sequencing data showed 7/21 (33.33%) samples were positive for Echovirus 30 and 1/21 (4.76%) samples were positive for CVA9.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results of this survey indicate high prevalence of 39.06% of EV among young neonates with sepsis. A high prevalence of 33.3% Echoviruses 30 and a low rate of 4.76% coxsackievirus A9 infection has been observed in neonatal patients with viral sepsis. This outbreak is probably one of the first Enterovirus outbreaks to be reported in Ahvaz, Iran. The results of this survey will help to minimize unneeded use of antimicrobial drugs and reduce unnecessary hospitalization.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shabani</LastName><ForeName>Abdolnabi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious and Tropical Diseases Research Center, Health Research Institute, Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Makvandi</LastName><ForeName>Manoochehr</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious and Tropical Diseases Research Center, Health Research Institute, Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Samarbafzadeh</LastName><ForeName>Alireza</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious and Tropical Diseases Research Center, Health Research Institute, Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teimoori</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious and Tropical Diseases Research Center, Health Research Institute, Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rasti</LastName><ForeName>Mojtaba</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious and Tropical Diseases Research Center, Health Research Institute, Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karami</LastName><ForeName>Chiman</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious and Tropical Diseases Research Center, Health Research Institute, Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rastegarvand</LastName><ForeName>Nasteran</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious and Tropical Diseases Research Center, Health Research Institute, Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases, Abozar Hospital, Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nikfar</LastName><ForeName>Roya</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious and Tropical Diseases Research Center, Health Research Institute, Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shamsizadeh</LastName><ForeName>Ahmad</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases, Abozar Hospital, Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salehi</LastName><ForeName>Azam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Parasitology Department, Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Angali</LastName><ForeName>Kambiz Ahmadi</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biostatistic Department, School of Health, Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Iran J Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518404</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2008-3289</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coxsackievirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Echovirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enteroviruses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sepsis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30483379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6243150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Knowles NJ., Hovi T., Hyypi&#xe4; T., King AMQ., Lindberg AM., Pallansch MA., Palmenberg AC., Skern T., Stanway G., Yamashita T., Zell R. Picornaviridae. In: King AMQ., Adams MJ., Carstens EB., Lefkowitz EJ., editors. Virus taxonomy: classification and nomenclature of viruses: ninth report of the international committee on Taxonomy of viruses. Elsevier; San Diego: 2011. p. 855&#x2013;880.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowles NJ, Hovi T, Hyypi T, King AM, Lindberg AM, Pallansch MA, et al. Picornaviridae. In: King AM, Adams MJ, Carstens EB, Lefkowitz EJ, editors. Virus Taxonomy: Classification and Nomenclature of Viruses. Ninth Report of the International Committee on Taxonomy of Viruses. San Diego: Elsevier; 2012. p. 855&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad S, Dalwai A, Al-Nakib W. Frequency of enterovirus detection in blood samples of neonates admitted to hospital with sepsis-like illness in Kuwait. J Med Virol 2013;85:1280&#x2013;1285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23918545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvala H, Calvert J, Van Nguyen D, Clasper L, Gadsby N, Molyneaux P, et al. Comparison of diagnostic clinical samples and environmental sampling for enterovirus and parechovirus surveillance in Scotland, 2010 to 2012. Euro Surveill 2014;19(15):20772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24762664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maguire HC, Atkinson P, Sharland M, Bendig J. Enterovirus infections in England and Wales: laboratory surveillance data: 1975 to 1994. Commun Dis Public Health 1999;2:122&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10402747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharp J, Harrison CJ, Puckett K, Selvaraju SB, Penaranda S, Nix WA, et al. Characteriscs of young infants in whom whom human parechovirus, enterovirus, or neither were detected in cerebrospinal &#xfb02;uid during sepsis evaluation. Pediatr Infect Dis J 2013;32:213&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4637937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23042051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhow TL, Hung YY, Herz AM. Changing epidemiology of bacteremia in infants aged 1 week to 3 months. Pediatrics 2012;129(3):e590&#x2013;596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22371459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumaidi K, Al-Jawabreh A. Molecular detection and genotyping of enteroviruses from CSF samples of patients with suspected sepsis-like illness and/or aseptic meningitis from 2012 to 2015 in West Bank, Palestine. PLoS One 2017;12(2): e0172357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5321419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28225788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racaniello Vincent R. Picornaviridae: the viruses and their replication. In: Knipe DM, Howley PM, editors. Fields virology. 6th ed., vol. 1 Philadelphia: Lippincott Williams and Wilkins; 2013. p. 610e64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapusinszky B, Szomor KN, Farkas &#xc1;, Tak&#xe1;cs M, Berencsi G. Detection of non-polio enteroviruses in Hungary 2000&#x2013;2008 and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71, coxsackievirus A16, and echovirus 30. Virus Genes 2010;40:163&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20044791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verboon-Maciolek M, Nijhuis M, Van Loon A, Van Maarssenveen N, Van Wieringen H, Pekelharing-Berghuis M, et al. Diagnosis of enterovirus infection in the first 2 months of life by real-time polymerase chain reaction. Clin Infect Dis 2003;37:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12830402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byington CL, Enriquez FR, Hoff C, Tuohy R, Taggart EW, Hillyard DR, et al. Serious bacterial infections in febrile infants 1 to 90 days old with and without viral infections. Pediatrics 2004;113:1662&#x2013;1666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15173488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito S, Rahamat-Langendoen J, Ascolese B, Senatore L, Castellazzi L, Niesters HG. Pediatric parecho-virus infections. J Clin Virol 2014;60:84&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24690382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolthers KC, Benschop KS, Schinkel J, Molenkamp R, Bergevoet RM, Spijkerman IJ, et al. Human parechoviruses as an important viral cause of sepsis like illness and meningitis in young children. Clin Infect Dis 2008;47:358&#x2013;363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18558876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baek K, Park K, Jung E, Chung E, Park J, Choi H, et al. Molecular and epidemiological characterization of enteroviruses isolated in Chungnam, Korea from 2005 to 2006. J Microbiol Biotechnol 2009;19:1055&#x2013;1064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19809266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirand A, Henquell C, Archimbaud C, Chambon M, Charbonne F, Peigue-Lafeuille H, et al. Prospective identification of enteroviruses involved in meningitis in 2006 through direct genotyping in cerebrospinal fluid. J Clin Microbiol 2008;46:87&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2224282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17977989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamadpoor T, Nabavinia M, Gholoobi A, Alavi M, Meshkat Z. Enteroviruses in acute myocardial infarction. Iran J Public Health 2012;41:71&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3469030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23113227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J, Yoshida H, Ding Z, Tao Z, Zhang J, Tian B, et al. Molecular epidemiology and recombination of human Enteroviruses from AFP surveillance in Yunnan, China from 2006 to 2010. Sci Rep 2014;4: 6058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5377527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25317568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verboon-Maciolek MA, Nijhuis M, van Loon AM, van Maarssenveen N, van Wieringen H, Pekelharing-Berghuis MA, et al. Diagnosis of enterovirus infection in the first 2 months of life by real-time polymerase chain reaction. Clin Infect Dis 2003; 37:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12830402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khetsuriani N, Lamonte-Fowlkes A, Oberste S, Pallansch MA. Enterovirus surveillance--United States, 1970&#x2013;2005. MMWR Surveill Summ 2006;55:1&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16971890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jord&#xe1;n I, Esteva C, Esteban E, Noguera A, Garc&#xed;a JJ, Mu&#xf1;oz-Almagro C. Severe enterovirus disease in febrile neonates. Enferm Infecc Microbiol Clin 2009;27:399&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19409661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo Ji-Hyun, Yeom Jung Sook, Youn Hee-Shang, Han Tae-Hee, Chung Ju-Young. Prevalence of human parechovirus and enterovirus in cerebrospinal fluid samples in children in Jinju, Korea. Korean J Pediatr 2015;58:102&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4388971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25861333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvala H, McLeish N, Kondracka J, McIntyre CL, McWilliam, Leitch EC, et al. Comparison of human parechovirus and enterovirus detection frequencies in cerebrospinal fluid samples collected over a 5-year period in Edinburgh: HPeV type 3 identified as the most common picornavirus type. J Med Virol 2011;83:889&#x2013;896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21412796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han TH, Chung JY, You SJ, Youn JL, Shim GH. Human parechovirus-3 infection in children, South Korea. J Clin Virol 2013;58:194&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23800693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walters B, Penaranda S, Nix WA, Oberste MS, Todd KM, Katz BZ, et al. Detection of human parechovirus (HPeV)-3 in spinal fluid specimens from pediatric patients in the Chicago area. J Clin Virol 2011;52:187&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21813319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahroodi MJG, Ghazvini K, Sadeghi R, Sasan MS. Enteroviral meningitis in neonates and children of Mashhad, Iran. Jundishapur J Microbiol 2016; 9(5):e19955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4950267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27478556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi P, Mahdian Naser H, Sohrabi A. The association of non-polio Enteroviruses with aseptic meningitis in children in Iran. JoMMID 2014;2:56&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mojtaba R, AliReza S-Z, Manoochehr M, Ahmad S-Z. Relative frequency of enteroviruses in children with aseptic meningitis referred to Aboozar hospital in Ahvaz. Jundishapur J Microbiol 2012;5:456&#x2013;459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JW, Holmes CW, Elsanousi FA, Patel A, Adam F, Speight R, et al. Cluster of human parechovirus infections as the predominant cause of sepsis in neonates and infants, Leicester, United Kingdom, 8 May to 2 August 2016. Euro Surveill 2016;21(34):30326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5144936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27589339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braccio S, Kapetanstrataki M, Sharland M, Ladhani SN. Intensive care admissions for children with enterovirus and human parechovirus infections in the United Kingdom and the Republic of Ireland, 2010&#x2013;2014. Pediatr Infect Dis J 2017;36:339&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27977558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolehmainen Pekka, Siponen Anu, Smura Teemu, Kallio-Kokkoc Hannimari, Vapalahti Olli, J&#xe4;&#xe4;skel&#xe4;inen Anne, et al. Intertypic recombination of human parechovirus 4 isolated frominfants with sepsis-like disease. J Clin Virol 2017;88:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28081453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>