<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30612304</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2019</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1867-0342</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Food and environmental virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Food Environ Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of Secondary Concentration Methods for Poliovirus Detection in Wastewater.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20</StartPage><EndPage>31</EndPage><MedlinePgn>20-31</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12560-018-09364-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Effective surveillance of human enteric viruses is critical to estimate disease prevalence within a community and can be a vital supplement to clinical surveillance. This study sought to evaluate simple, effective, and inexpensive secondary concentration methods for use with ViroCap&#x2122; filter eluate for environmental surveillance of poliovirus. Wastewater was primary concentrated using cartridge ViroCap filters, seeded with poliovirus type 1 (PV1), and then concentrated using five secondary concentration methods (beef extract-Celite, ViroCap flat disc filter, InnovaPrep&#xae; Concentrating Pipette, polyethylene glycol [PEG]/sodium chloride [NaCl] precipitation, and skimmed-milk flocculation). PV1 was enumerated in secondary concentrates by plaque assay on BGMK cells. Of the five tested methods, PEG/NaCl precipitation and skimmed-milk flocculation resulted in the highest PV1 recoveries. Optimization of the skimmed-milk flocculation method resulted in a greater PV1 recovery (106&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;24.8%) when compared to PEG/NaCl precipitation (59.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;19.4%) (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.004, t-test). The high PV1 recovery, short processing time, low reagent cost, no required refrigeration, and requirement for only standard laboratory equipment suggest that the skimmed-milk flocculation method would be a good candidate to be field-validated for secondary concentration of environmental ViroCap filter samples containing poliovirus.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Falman</LastName><ForeName>Jill C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental &amp; Occupational Health Sciences, University of Washington, 4225 Roosevelt Way NE, Suite 100, Seattle, WA, 98195, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fagnant-Sperati</LastName><ForeName>Christine S</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental &amp; Occupational Health Sciences, University of Washington, 4225 Roosevelt Way NE, Suite 100, Seattle, WA, 98195, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kossik</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental &amp; Occupational Health Sciences, University of Washington, 4225 Roosevelt Way NE, Suite 100, Seattle, WA, 98195, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boyle</LastName><ForeName>David S</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PATH, 2201 Westlake Avenue, Suite 200, Seattle, WA, 98121, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meschke</LastName><ForeName>John Scott</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8983-9042</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental &amp; Occupational Health Sciences, University of Washington, 4225 Roosevelt Way NE, Suite 100, Seattle, WA, 98195, USA. jmeschke@uw.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>OPP1170548</GrantID><Acronym>GATES</Acronym><Agency>Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Food Environ Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101483831</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1867-0334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012722">Sewage</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004784" MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental Monitoring</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005427" MajorTopicYN="N">Flocculation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017955" MajorTopicYN="N">Poliovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012722" MajorTopicYN="N">Sewage</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014773" MajorTopicYN="N">Virology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014871" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water Microbiology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enteric viruses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental surveillance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Poliovirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skimmed-milk flocculation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wastewater</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>CONFLICT OF INTEREST: The authors declare that they have not conflict of interest. RESEARCH INVOLVING HUMAN PARTICIPANTS AND/OR ANIMALS: This article does not contain any studies with human participants or animals performed by any of the authors. INFORMED CONSENT: Informed consent was not required, as no human participants or individuals were included in this study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30612304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6394643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12560-018-09364-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12560-018-09364-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbaszadegan M, Huber MS, Gerba CP, Pepper IL. Detection of enteroviruses in groundwater with the polymerase chain reaction. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 1993;59:1318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC182083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7685998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asghar H, Diop OM, Weldegebriel G, et al. Environmental surveillance for polioviruses in the Global Polio Eradication Initiative. Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2014;210(Suppl 1):S294&#x2013;S303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10578309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25316848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aw TG, Gin KY, -H Environmental surveillance and molecular characterization of human enteric viruses in tropical urban wastewaters. Journal of Applied Microbiology. 2010;109:716&#x2013;730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20233263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blacklow NR, Greenberg HB. Viral gastroenteritis. The New England Journal of Medicine. 1991;325:252&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1647494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calgua B, Fumian T, Rusi&#xf1;ol M, et al. Detection and quantification of classic and emerging viruses by skimmed-milk flocculation and PCR in river water from two geographical areas. Water Research. 2013;47:2797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23535378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calgua B, Mengewein A, Grunert A, et al. Development and application of a one-step low cost procedure to concentrate viruses from seawater samples. Journal of Virological Methods. 2008;153:79&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18765255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cliver DO, Yeatman J. Ultracentrifugation in the concentration and detection of enteroviruses. Applied Microbiology. 1965;13:387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1058261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14325278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahling DR, Wright BA. Recovery of viruses from water by a modified flocculation procedure for second-step concentration. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 1986;51:1326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC239066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3015024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahling DR, Wright BA. Optimization of the BGM cell line culture and viral assay procedures for monitoring viruses in the environment. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 1986;51:790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC238965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3010860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahling DR, Wright BA. A comparison of recovery of virus from wastewaters by beef extract-Celite, ferric chloride, and filter concentration procedures. Journal of Virological Methods. 1988;22:337&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3220927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagnant C, Beck N, Yang M-F, et al. Development of a novel bag-mediated filtration system for environmental recovery of poliovirus. Journal of Water and Health. 2014;12:747&#x2013;754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25473984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagnant CS, Kossik AL, Zhou NA, et al. Use of preservative agents and antibiotics for increased poliovirus survival on positively charged filters. Food and Environmental Virology. 2017;9:383&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5668339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28616833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagnant CS, S&#xe1;nchez-Gonzalez LM, Zhou NA, et al. Improvement of the bag-mediated filtration system for sampling wastewater and wastewater-impacted waters. Food and Environmental Virology. 2018;10:72&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5823955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28674934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrah SR, Gerba CP, Goyal SM, et al. Regeneration of pleated filters used to concentrate enteroviruses from large volumes of tap water. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 1977;33:308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC170682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">192145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fattal B, Katzenelson E, Hostovsky T, Shuval HI. Comparison of adsorption-elution methods for concentration and detection of viruses in water. Water Research. 1977;11:955&#x2013;958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong T-T, Lipp EK. Enteric viruses of human and animals in aquatic environments: Health risks, detection, and potential water quality assessment tools. Microbiology and Molecular Biology Reviews. 2005;69:357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1197419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15944460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fumian TM, Gagliardi Leite JP, Rose TL, et al. One year environmental surveillance of rotavirus specie A (RVA) genotypes in circulation after the introduction of the Rotarix&#xae; vaccine in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Water Research. 2011;45:5755&#x2013;5763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21917289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galasso GJ, Sharp DG. Virus particle aggregation and the plaque-forming unit. Journal of Immunology (Baltimore, MD: 1950) 1962;88:339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13896316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerba CP, Betancourt WQ. Viral Aggregation: Impact on Virus Behavior in the Environment. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 2017;51:7318&#x2013;7325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28599109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson KE, Opryszko MC, Schissler JT, et al. Evaluation of human enteric viruses in surface water and drinking water resources in southern Ghana. The American journal of tropical medicine and hygiene. 2011;84:20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3005515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21212196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson KE, Schwab KJ, Spencer SK, Borchardt MA. Measuring and mitigating inhibition during quantitative real time PCR analysis of viral nucleic acid extracts from large-volume environmental water samples. Water Research. 2012;46:4281&#x2013;4291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22673345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzales-Gustavson E, C&#xe1;rdenas-Youngs Y, Calvo M, da Silva MF, Hundesa A, Amor&#xf3;s I, et al. Characterization of the efficiency and uncertainty of skimmed milk flocculation for the simultaneous concentration and quantification of water-borne viruses, bacteria and protozoa. Journal of Microbiological Methods. 2017;134:46&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28093213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grabow W. The virology of waste-water treatment. Water Research. 1968;2:675&#x2013;701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellmer M, Paxeus N, Magnius L, et al. Detection of pathogenic viruses in sewage provided early warnings of hepatitis a virus and norovirus outbreaks. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2014;80:6771&#x2013;6781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4249052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25172863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill W, Akin E, Benton W. Detection of viruses in water: A review of methods and application. Water Research. 1971;5:967&#x2013;995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill WF, Akin EW, Benton WH, Metcalf TG. Virus in water. II. Evaluation of membrane cartridge filters for recovering low multiplicities of poliovirus from water. Journal of Applied Microbiology. 1972;23:880&#x2013;888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC380465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4338005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill WF, Jakubowski W, Akin EW, Clarke NA. Detection of virus in water: Sensitivity of the tentative standard method for drinking water. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 1976;31:254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC169756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">187116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hovi T, Cantell K, Huovilainen A, et al. Outbreak of paralytic poliomyelitis in Finland: Widespread circulation of antigenically altered poliovirus type 3 in a vaccinated population. Lancet. 1986;1:1427&#x2013;1432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2872526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hovi T, Shulman LM, Van Der Avoort H, et al. Role of environmental poliovirus surveillance in global polio eradication and beyond. Epidemiology and Infection. 2012;140:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21849095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ijzerman MM, Dahling DR, Fout GS. A method to remove environmental inhibitors prior to the detection of waterborne enteric viruses by reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction. Journal of Virological Methods. 1997;63:145&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9015285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikner L, Gerba C, Bright K. Concentration and recovery of viruses from water: a comprehensive review. Food and Environmental Virology. 2012;4:41&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23412811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikner LA, Soto-Beltran M, Bright KR. New method using a positively charged microporous filter and ultrafiltration for concentration of viruses from tap water. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2011;77:3500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3126471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21441329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karim MR, Rhodes ER, Brinkman N, et al. New electropositive filter for concentrating enteroviruses and noroviruses from large volumes of water. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2009;75:2393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2675229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19218410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzenelson E, Fattal B, Hostovesky T. Organic flocculation: an efficient second-step concentration method for the detection of viruses in tap water. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 1976;32:638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC170320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazama S, Miura T, Masago Y, et al. Environmental surveillance of norovirus genogroups I and II for sensitive detection of epidemic variants. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5394333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28213546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leclerc H, Schwartzbrod L, Dei-Cas E. Microbial agents associated with waterborne diseases. Critical Reviews in Microbiology. 2002;28:371&#x2013;409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12546197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levlin, E., &amp; Hultman, B. (2008) Konduktivitetsm&#xe4;tningar som m&#xe4;t- och kontrollmetod vid kommunala avloppsanl&#xe4;ggningar.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodder WJ, Buisman AM, Rutjes SA, et al. Feasibility of quantitative environmental surveillance in poliovirus eradication strategies. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2012;78:3800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3346415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22447593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma JF, Naranjo J, Gerba CP. Evaluation of MK filters for recovery of enteroviruses from tap water. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 1994;60:1974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC201589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8031090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangal TD, Aylward RB, Grassly NC. The potential impact of routine immunization with inactivated poliovirus vaccine on wild-type or vaccine-derived poliovirus outbreaks in a posteradication setting. American Journal of Epidemiology. 2013;178:1579&#x2013;1587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24100955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manor Y, Shulman L, Kaliner E, et al. Intensified environmental surveillance supporting the response to wild poliovirus type 1 silent circulation in Israel, 2013. Eurosurveillance. 2014;19:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24576473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masachessi G, Pisano MB, Prez VE, et al. Enteric viruses in surface waters from Argentina: Molecular and viable virus detection. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5812940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29269500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matrosovich M, Matrosovich T, Garten W, Klenk H-D. New low-viscosity overlay medium for viral plaque assays. Virology Journal. 2006;3:63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1564390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16945126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maunula L, Klemola P, Kauppinen A, et al. Enteric viruses in a large waterborne outbreak of acute gastroenteritis in Finland. Food and Environmental Virology. 2009;1:31&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick JL. Current status of poliovirus infections. Clinical Microbiology Reviews. 1996;9:293&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC172894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8809461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minor PD. Growth, assay, and purification of picornaviruses. In: Mahy BWJ, editor. Virology: A practical approach. Oxford: IRL Press; 1985. pp. 25&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minor, P. D. (2016). An introduction to poliovirus: Pathogenesis, vaccination, and the endgame for global eradication. Methods in Molecular Biology, 1387, 1&#x2013;10. 10.1007/978-1-4939-3292-4_1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26983727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nupen EM. Virus studies on the windhoek waste-water reclamation plant (South-West Africa) Water Research. 1970;4:661&#x2013;672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrinca AR, Donia D, Pierangeli A, et al. Presence and environmental circulation of enteric viruses in three different wastewater treatment plants. Journal of Applied Microbiology. 2009;106:1608&#x2013;1617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19226391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao NU, Labzoffsky NA. A simple method for the detection of low concentration of viruses in large volumes of water by the membrane filter technique. Canadian Journal of Microbiology. 1969;15:399&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4306769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhodes ER, Hamilton DW, See MJ, Wymer L. Evaluation of hollow-fiber ultrafiltration primary concentration of pathogens and secondary concentration of viruses from water. Journal of Virological Methods. 2011;176:38&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21664379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riddle MS, Chen WH, Kirkwood CD, Maclennan CA. Update on vaccines for enteric pathogens. Clinical Microbiology and Infection. 2018;24:1039&#x2013;1045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29964231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salim AFM, Phillips AD, Farthing MJG. Pathogenesis of gut virus infection. Bailliere&#x2019;s Clinical Gastroenterology. 1990;4:593&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1962725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrader C, Schielke A, Ellerbroek L, Johne R. PCR inhibitors&#x2014;Occurrence, properties and removal. J Appl Microbiol. 2012;113:1014&#x2013;1026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22747964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab KJ, De Leon R, Sobsey MD. Concentration and purification of beef extract mock eluates from water samples for the detection of enteroviruses, hepatitis A virus, and Norwalk virus by reverse transcription-PCR. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 1995;61:531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7574592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuval HI, Cymbalista BFS, Goldblum N. The phase-separation method for the concentration and detection of viruses in water. Water Research. 1969;3:225&#x2013;240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuval HJ, Cymbalista S, Fatal B, Goldblum N. Concentration of enteric viruses in water by hydro-extraction and two phase separation. In: Berg G, editor. Transmission of viruses by the water route. London: Interscience; 1967. pp. 45&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinclair RG, Jones EL, Gerba CP. Viruses in recreational water-borne disease outbreaks: A review. Journal of Applied Microbiology. 2009;107:1769&#x2013;1780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19486213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobsey MD, Carrick RJ, Jensen HR. Improved methods for detecting enteric viruses in oysters. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 1978;36:121&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobsey MD, Jones BL. Concentration of poliovirus from tap water using positively charged microporous filters. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 1979;37:588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobsey MD, Moore RS, Glass JS. Evaluating adsorbent filter performance for enteric virus concentrations in tap water. Journal (American Water Works Association) 1981;73:542&#x2013;548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strebel PM, Sutter RW, Cochi SL, et al. Epidemiology of poliomyelitis in the United States one decade after the last reported case of indigenous wild virus-associated disease. Clinical Infectious Diseases. 1992;14:568&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1554844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teunis PFM, Lodder WJ, Heisterkamp SH, de Roda Husman AM. Mixed plaques: Statistical evidence how plaque assays may underestimate virus concentrations. Water Research. 2005;39:4240&#x2013;4250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16202439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Zyl WB, Page NA, Grabow WOK, et al. Molecular epidemiology of group A rotaviruses in water sources and selected raw vegetables in southern Africa. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2006;72:4554&#x2013;4560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1489384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16820443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallis C, Melnick J, Fields J. Detection of viruses in large volumes of natural waters by concentration insoluble polyelectrolytes. Water Research. 1970;4:787&#x2013;796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Kvaal K, Ratnaweera H. Characterization of influent wastewater with periodic variation and snow melting effect in cold climate area. Computers and Chemical Engineering. 2017;106:202&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen Li J, Wei Wang X, Yi Rui Q, et al. A new and simple method for concentration of enteric viruses from water. Journal of Virological Methods. 1998;74:99&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9763133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO . The polio eradication &amp; endgame strategic plan 2013&#x2013;2018. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO . Guidelines on environmental surveillance for detection of polioviruses, working draft. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO . Global polio eradication initiative polio environmental surveillance expansion plan: Global expansion plan under the endgame strategy 2013&#x2013;2018. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO . Circulating vaccine-derived poliovirus. Geneva: WHO; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO . Global wild poliovirus 2013&#x2013;2018. Geneva: WHO; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyn-Jones AP, Sellwood J. Enteric viruses in the aquatic environment. Journal of Applied Microbiology. 2001;91:945&#x2013;962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11851802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto KR, Alberts BM, Benzinger R, et al. Rapid bacteriophage sedimentation in the presence of polyethylene glycol and its application to large-scale virus purification. Virology. 1970;40:734&#x2013;744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4908735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanez LA, Lucero NS, Barril PA, et al. Evidence of hepatitis a virus circulation in central Argentina: Seroprevalence and environmental surveillance. Journal of Clinical Virology. 2014;59:38&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24332411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou N, Lv D, Wang S, et al. Continuous detection and genetic diversity of human rotavirus A in sewage in eastern China, 2013&#x2013;2014. Virology Journal. 2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5022235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27623961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou NA, Fagnant-Sperati CS, Shirai JH, et al. Evaluation of the bag-mediated filtration system as a novel tool for poliovirus environmental surveillance: Results from a comparative field study in Pakistan. PLoS ONE. 2018;13:e0200551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6047795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30011304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>