<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31799495</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2515-1355</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>7</Volume><PubDate><Year>2019</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Therapeutic advances in vaccines and immunotherapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ther Adv Vaccines Immunother</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Insights into innate and adaptive immune responses in vaccine development against EV-A71.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2515135519888998</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2515135519888998</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2515135519888998</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/2515135519888998</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus A71 (EV-A71) is one of the major causative agents of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) in the world, infecting mostly infants and young children (&lt;5&#x2009;years of age) in Asia. Approximately 2&#x2009;million cases of HFMD were reported in China each year, of which approximately 45-50% were due to EV-A71. Most of the HFMD infections caused by EV-A71 usually result in mild symptoms with rashes and ulcers in the mouth. However, virulent strains of EV-A71 can infect the central nervous system and cause severe neurologic diseases, leading to reduced cognitive ability, acute flaccid paralysis and death. The lack of understanding of cellular immunity for long-term protection from the HFMD disease represents a major obstacle for vaccine development. In particular, the role of innate and T cell immunity during HFMD infection remains unclear and there is evidence suggesting the importance of CD4<sup>+</sup> and CD8<sup>+</sup> T cells for protective immunity. Currently, no US FDA-approved vaccine is available for EV-A71. Although the inactivated vaccines produced in China are highly effective (vaccine efficacy &gt;95%), they lack the cellular immunity required for long-term protection. In this review, we discuss the findings that support the protective roles of innate and T cell immunity against EV-A71 infection, which will provide the knowledge needed for the urgent development of efficacious vaccines that will confer long-term protection.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), 2019.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lim</LastName><ForeName>Hui Xuan</ForeName><Initials>HX</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Virus and Vaccine Research, School of Science and Technology, Sunway University, Bandar Sunway, Kuala Lumpur, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poh</LastName><ForeName>Chit Laa</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8475-6291</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Virus and Vaccine Research, School of Science and Technology, Sunway University, Bandar Sunway, Kuala Lumpur, Selangor 47500, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Ther Adv Vaccines Immunother</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101718382</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2515-1355</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EV-A71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HFMD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cellular immunity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">innate immunity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vaccines</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest statement: The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31799495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6873268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2515135519888998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_2515135519888998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mogensen TH. Pathogen recognition and inflammatory signaling in innate immune defenses. Clin Microbiol Rev 2009; 22: 240&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2668232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19366914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton AH, Cardani A, Braciale TJ. The host immune response in respiratory virus infection: balancing virus clearance and immunopathology. Semin Immunopathol 2016; 38: 471&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4896975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26965109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y, Zhang R, Wu W, et al. Innate immunity evasion by enteroviruses linked to epidemic hand&#x2013;foot&#x2013;mouth disease. Front Microbiol 2018; 9: 2422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6186807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30349526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Q, Langereis MA, Lork M, et al. Enterovirus 2Apro targets MDA5 and MAVS in infected cells. J Virol 2014; 88: 3369&#x2013;3378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3957915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24390337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Xi X, Lei X, et al. Enterovirus 71 protease 2Apro targets MAVS to inhibit anti-viral type I interferon responses. PLoS Pathog 2013; 9: e1003231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3605153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23555247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rui Y, Su J, Wang H, et al. Disruption of MDA5-mediated innate immune responses by the 3C proteins of coxsackievirus A16, coxsackievirus A6, and enterovirus D68. J Virol 2017; 91: pii: e00546-17 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5469270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28424289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei X, Sun Z, Liu X, et al. Cleavage of the adaptor protein TRIF by enterovirus 71 3C inhibits antiviral responses mediated by Toll-like receptor 3. J Virol 2011; 85: 8811&#x2013;8818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3165803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21697485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Xiao F, Wan P, et al. EV71 3D protein binds with NLRP3 and enhances the assembly of inflammasome complex. PLoS Pathog 2017; 13: e1006123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5245909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28060938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J, Yi L, Zhao J, et al. Enterovirus 71 disrupts interferon signaling by reducing the level of interferon receptor 1. J Virol 2012; 86: 3767&#x2013;3776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3302529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22258259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Sun M, Yuan X, et al. Enterovirus 71 suppresses interferon responses by blocking Janus kinase (JAK)/signal transducer and activator of transcription (STAT) signaling through inducing karyopherin-alpha1 degradation. J Biol Chem 2017; 292: 10262&#x2013;10274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5473229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28455446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu ML, Lee YP, Wang YF, et al. Type I interferons protect mice against enterovirus 71 infection. J Gen Virol 2005; 86(Pt 12): 3263&#x2013;3269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16298971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadler AJ, Williams BRG. Interferon-inducible antiviral effectors. Nat Rev Immunol 2008; 8: 559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2522268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18575461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YP, Wang YF, Wang JR, et al. Enterovirus 71 blocks selectively type I interferon production through the 3C viral protein in mice. J Med Virol 2012; 84: 1779&#x2013;1789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22997081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y, Shimojima M, Tano Y, et al. Human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is a functional receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat Med 2009; 15: 794&#x2013;797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Yamashita Y, Li J, et al. Scavenger receptor B2 is a cellular receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat Med 2009; 15: 798&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujii K, Nagata N, Sato Y, et al. Transgenic mouse model for the study of enterovirus 71 neuropathogenesis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2013; 110: 14753&#x2013;14758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3767555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23959904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YW, Yu SL, Shao HY, et al. Human SCARB2 transgenic mice as an infectious animal model for enterovirus 71. PLoS One 2013; 8: e57591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3581494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23451246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B, Chuang H, Yang KD. Sialylated glycans as receptor and inhibitor of enterovirus 71 infection to DLD-1 intestinal cells. Virol J 2009; 6: 141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2751754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19751532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan CW, Poh CL, Sam IC, et al. Enterovirus 71 uses cell surface heparan sulfate glycosaminoglycan as an attachment receptor. J Virol 2013; 87: 611&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3536405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23097443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su PY, Wang YF, Huang SW, et al. Cell surface nucleolin facilitates enterovirus 71 binding and infection. J Virol 2015; 89: 4527&#x2013;4538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4442404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25673703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen KR, Yu CK, Kung SH, et al. Toll-like receptor 3 is involved in detection of enterovirus A71 infection and targeted by viral 2A protease. Viruses 2018; 10: pii: E689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6315976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30563052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung ML, Jia L, Yip CCY, et al. Human tryptophanyl-tRNA synthetase is an IFN-gamma-inducible entry factor for Enterovirus. J Clin Invest 2018; 128: 5163&#x2013;5177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6205371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Hsiung CA, Lu CY, et al. Status of cellular rather than humoral immunity is correlated with clinical outcome of enterovirus 71. Pediatr Res 2006; 60: 466&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7086547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16940249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Deng C, Wan J, et al. Neutralizing antibody response in the patients with hand, foot and mouth disease to enterovirus 71 and its clinical implications. Virol J 2011; 8: 306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3142239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21679417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Cui D, Yang X, et al. Increased frequency of circulating follicular helper T cells in children with hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by enterovirus 71 infection. J Immunol Res 2014; 2014: 651872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4071862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25013818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui D, Zhong F, Lin J, et al. Changes of circulating Th22 cells in children with hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by enterovirus 71 infection. Oncotarget 2017; 8: 29370&#x2013;29382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5438737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28030850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke Y, Liu WN, Her Z, et al. Enterovirus A71 infection activates human immune responses and induces pathological changes in humanized mice. J Virol 2019; 93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6340035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30429352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YW, Chang KC, Kao CM, et al. Lymphocyte and antibody responses reduce enterovirus 71 lethality in mice by decreasing tissue viral loads. J Virol 2009; 83: 6477&#x2013;6483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2698549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19386699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issaro N, Wu F, Weng L, et al. Induction of immune responses by a novel recombinant fusion protein of enterovirus A71 in BALB/c mice. Mol Immunol 2019; 105: 1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30465931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan S, Tan X, Sun X, et al. VP2 dominated CD4+ T cell responses against enterovirus 71 and cross-reactivity against coxsackievirus A16 and polioviruses in a healthy population. J Immunol 2013; 191: 1637&#x2013;1647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23863902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung YC, Ho MS, Wu JC, et al. Immunization with virus-like particles of enterovirus 71 elicits potent immune responses and protects mice against lethal challenge. Vaccine 2008; 26: 1855&#x2013;1862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18329759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S-L, Ying X-L, Han X, et al. Characterization of the enterovirus 71 VP1 protein as a vaccine candidate. J Med Virol 2015; 87: 256&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25043151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Cai C, Feng J, et al. Peripheral T lymphocyte subset imbalances in children with enterovirus 71-induced hand, foot and mouth disease. Virus Res 2014; 180: 84&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24316007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Meng FY, Li JX, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunology of an inactivated alum-adjuvant enterovirus 71 vaccine in children in China: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet 2013; 381: 2024&#x2013;2032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23726161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Liu L, Mo Z, et al. An inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy children. N Engl J Med 2014; 370: 829&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yee PTI, Tan SH, Ong KC, et al. Development of live attenuated Enterovirus 71 vaccine strains that confer protection against lethal challenge in mice. Sci Rep 2019; 9: 4805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6423319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30886246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu F, Xu W, Xia J, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in China. N Engl J Med 2014; 370: 818&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu JT, Jit M, Zheng Y, et al. Routine pediatric enterovirus 71 vaccination in China: a cost-effectiveness analysis. PLoS Med 2016; 13: e1001975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4792415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26978565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi EJ, Shin YJ, Kim JH, et al. Enterovirus 71 infection and vaccines. Clin Exp Vaccine Res 2017; 6: 4&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5292356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28168168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu W, Jin P, Li J-X, et al. Correlates of protection for inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine: the analysis of immunological surrogate endpoints. Expert Rev Vaccines 2017; 16: 945&#x2013;949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28548626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou AH, Liu CC, Chang JY, et al. Formalin-inactivated EV71 vaccine candidate induced cross-neutralizing antibody against subgenotypes B1, B4, B5 and C4A in adult volunteers. PLoS One 2013; 8: e79783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3836818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24278177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Q, Cheng T, Zhu F, et al. The cross-neutralizing activity of enterovirus 71 subgenotype C4 vaccines in healthy Chinese infants and children. PLoS One 2013; 8: e79599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3834186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24260259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, An D, Liu W, et al. Analysis of cross-reactive neutralizing antibodies in human HFMD serum with an EV71 pseudovirus-based assay. PLoS One 2014; 9: e100545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4070950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24964084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M, Nagata N, Iwata N, et al. An attenuated strain of enterovirus 71 belonging to genotype A showed a broad spectrum of antigenicity with attenuated neurovirulence in Cynomolgus monkeys. J Virol 2007; 81: 9386&#x2013;9395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1951441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17567701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Hao C, Zhang S, et al. Oral immunization with recombinant enterovirus 71 VP1 formulated with chitosan protects mice against lethal challenge. Virol J 2014; 11: 80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4022980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24885121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Zhang C. Human IgG Fc promotes expression, secretion and immunogenicity of enterovirus 71 VP1 protein. J Biomed Res 2016; 30: 209&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4885169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27533931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YI, Song JH, Kwon BE, et al. Pros and cons of VP1-specific maternal IgG for the protection of Enterovirus 71 infection. Vaccine 2015; 33: 6604&#x2013;6610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26529069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiener TK, Premanand B, Kwang J. Immune responses to baculovirus-displayed enterovirus 71 VP1 antigen. Expert Rev Vaccines 2013; 12: 357&#x2013;364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23560917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CN, Lin YC, Fann C, et al. Protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by passive immunization with subunit VP1 vaccines and inactivated virus. Vaccine 2001; 20(5&#x2013;6): 895&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo DG, Alonso S, Phoon MC, et al. Identification of neutralizing linear epitopes from the VP1 capsid protein of Enterovirus 71 using synthetic peptides. Virus Res 2007; 125: 61&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17222936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y-X, Zhao H, Cao R-Y, et al. Recombinant tandem multi-linear neutralizing epitopes of human enterovirus 71 elicited protective immunity in mice. Virol J 2014; 11: 79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4030048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24885030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Y, Ku Z, Liu Q, et al. A combination vaccine comprising of inactivated enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 elicits balanced protective immunity against both viruses. Vaccine 2014; 32: 2406&#x2013;2412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24657161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S, Jiang L, Liang Z, et al. Evaluation of monovalent and bivalent vaccines against lethal Enterovirus 71 and Coxsackievirus A16 infection in newborn mice. Hum Vaccin Immunother 2014; 10: 2885&#x2013;2895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5443096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25483672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong M, Zhu H, Zhou J, et al. Cryo-electron microscopy study of insect cell-expressed enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 virus-like particles provides a structural basis for vaccine development. J Virol 2014; 88: 6444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4093858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24672036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ku Z, Liu Q, Ye X, et al. A virus-like particle based bivalent vaccine confers dual protection against enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 infections in mice. Vaccine 2014; 32: 4296&#x2013;4303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24950363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Tong X, Huang Z. Towards broadly protective polyvalent vaccines against hand, foot and mouth disease. Microbes Infect 2015; 17: 155&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25449959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Zhu R, Huo D, et al. An outbreak of coxsackievirus A6-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease in a kindergarten in Beijing in 2015. BMC Pediatr 2018; 18: 277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6103857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30131060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caine EA, Fuchs J, Das SC, et al. Efficacy of a trivalent hand, foot, and mouth disease vaccine against enterovirus 71 and coxsackieviruses A16 and A6 in mice. Viruses 2015; 7: 5919&#x2013;5932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4664989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26593938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Guo MS, Wu SR, et al. Immunological and biochemical characterizations of coxsackievirus A6 and A10 viral particles. Antiviral Res 2016; 129: 58&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26899790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Dai W, Zhang C, et al. A virus-like particle-based tetravalent vaccine for hand, foot, and mouth disease elicits broad and balanced protective immunity. Emerg Microbes Infect 2018; 7: 94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5959873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29777102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Li HY, Han JF, et al. Novel recombinant chimeric virus-like particle is immunogenic and protective against both enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 in mice. Sci Rep 2015; 5: 7878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4297979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25597595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anasir MI, Poh CL. Advances in antigenic peptide-based vaccine and neutralizing antibodies against viruses causing hand, foot, and mouth disease. Int J Mol Sci 2019; 20: pii: E1256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6471744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30871133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham BS, Sullivan NJ. Emerging viral diseases from a vaccinology perspective: preparing for the next pandemic. Nat Immunol 2018; 19: 20&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29199281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>