<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31811676</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1654</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Reviews in medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rev Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A review and meta-analysis of the epidemiology and clinical presentation of coxsackievirus A6 causing hand-foot-mouth disease in China and global implications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2087</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2087</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/rmv.2087</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Coxsackievirus A6 (CV-A6) has been associated with increasingly occurred sporadic hand-foot-mouth disease (HFMD) cases and outbreak events in many countries. In order to understand epidemiological characteristics of CV-A6, we collected the information describing HFMD caused by CV-A6 to describe the detection rate, severe rate and onychomadesis rate, which is defined as one or more nails defluvium, caused by CV-A6 from 2007 to 2017. The results showed that there was an outbreak of CV-A6 every other year, and overall trend of the epidemic of CA6-associated HFMD was increasing in China. The detection rate of CV-A6 in other countries was 32.0% (95% CI: 25.0%~40.0%) before 2013 and 28.0% (95% CI: 20.0%~36.0%) after 2013, respectively. Although the severe rate of HFMD caused by CV-A6 was low (0.10%, 95% CI: 0.01%~0.20%), CV-A6 can cause a high incidence of onychomadesis (28.0%, 95%CI: 21.9%-34.3%). Thus, it would be worthwhile to research and develop an effective multivalent vaccine for CV-A6 to achieve a more powerful prevention of HMFD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Tian-Shuo</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratorial Science and Technology, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Research Center, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Du</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratorial Science and Technology, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Research Center, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Da-Peng</ForeName><Initials>DP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Viral Disease Control and Prevention, Shandong Provincial Key Laboratory of Communicable Disease Control and Prevention, Shandong Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Jinan, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Quan-Rong</ForeName><Initials>QR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratorial Science and Technology, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Research Center, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Lin-Yi</ForeName><Initials>LY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratorial Science and Technology, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Research Center, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratorial Science and Technology, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Research Center, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shuai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratorial Science and Technology, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Research Center, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Ya-Qiong</ForeName><Initials>YQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratorial Science and Technology, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Research Center, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Fuqiang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratorial Science and Technology, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Research Center, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Qing-Bin</ForeName><Initials>QB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2804-0827</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratorial Science and Technology, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Research Center, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Rev Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9112448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1052-9276</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015897" MajorTopicYN="N">Comorbidity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004196" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Outbreaks</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004198" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Susceptibility</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014943" MajorTopicYN="N">Global Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017720" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Epidemiology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062486" MajorTopicYN="N">Public Health Surveillance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coxsackievirus A6</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hand-foot-mouth disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">human enteroviruses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">onychomadesis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31811676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rmv.2087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Esposito S, Principi N. Hand, foot and mouth disease: current knowledge on clinical manifestations, epidemiology, aetiology and prevention. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2018;37(3):391-398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qing-Bin L, Xiao-Ai Z, Ying W, et al. Circulation of Coxsackievirus A10 and A6 in hand-foot-mouth disease in China, 2009-2011. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(12):e52073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Lewthwaite P, Cardosa MJ, Solomon T. Clinical features, diagnosis, and management of enterovirus 71. Lancet Neurol. 2010;9(11):1097-1105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seiff A. Cambodia unravels cause of mystery illness. Lancet. 2012;380(9838):205-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tom S, Penny L, David P, Mary Jane C, Peter MM, Mong HO. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. Lancet Infect Dis. 2010;10(11):778-790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weijia X, Qiaohong L, C&#xe9;cile V, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in China, 2008-12: an epidemiological study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2014;14(4):308-318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiaoling Z, Yunwen H. Research Progress on Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease Caused by Coxsackievirus A6. Med Rec. 2016;22(20):3953-3956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lianlian B, Yiping W, Xin Y, Qunying M, Miao X, Zhenglun L. Coxsackievirus A6: a new emerging pathogen causing hand, foot and mouth disease outbreaks worldwide. Expert Rev Anti-Infe. 2015;13(9):1061-1071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanri Z, Jing L, Hui L, et al. Epidemic and genetic characteristics of coxsackievirus A6 strains isolated in Guangdong province from year 2008 to 2013. Chin J Microbiol Immun. 2014(10):742-746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soile B, P&#xe4;Ivi K, Svetlana K, et al. Co-circulation of coxsackieviruses A6 and A10 in hand, foot and mouth disease outbreak in Finland. J Clin Virol. 2010;48(1):49-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jian-Feng H, Shuang X, Yu Z, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak caused by coxsackievirus A6, China, 2013. J Infect. 2014;69(3):303-305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Yeo A, Phoon MC, et al. The largest outbreak of hand; foot and mouth disease in Singapore in 2008: the role of enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A strains. Int J Infect Dis. 2010;14(12):e1076-e1081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clementz GC, Mancini AJ. Nail matrix arrest following hand-foot-mouth disease: a report of five children. Pediatr Dermatol. 2000;17(1):7-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaunt E, Harvala H, Osterback R, et al. Genetic characterization of human coxsackievirus A6 variants associated with atypical hand, foot and mouth disease: a potential role of recombination in emergence and pathogenicity. J Gen Virol. 2015;96(Pt 5):1067-1079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying-Ying L, Qiu-Li Y, Wen-Na Z, Xun X, Shun-Xiang Q, Qi L. An analysis of the molecular characteristics of hand, foot, and mouth disease with onychomadesis in Hebei Province. J Pathog Bio. 2015;10(6):520-524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Dai W, Zhang C, et al. A virus-like particle-based tetravalent vaccine for hand, foot, and mouth disease elicits broad and balanced protective immunity. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2018;7(1):94-106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aswathyraj S, Arunkumar G, Alidjinou EK, Hober D. Hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD): emerging epidemiology and the need for a vaccine strategy. Med Microbiol Immunol. 2016;205(5):397-407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi EJ, Shin YJ, Kim JH, Kim TG, Chang SY. Enterovirus 71 infection and vaccines. Clin Exp Vaccine Res. 2017;6(1):4-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J, Dong Y, Chen X, et al. Prevalence of suicide attempts among Chinese adolescents: A meta-analysis of cross-sectional studies. Compr Psychiatry. 2015;61:78-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei SH, Huang YP, Liu MC, et al. An outbreak of coxsackievirus A6 hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with onychomadesis in Taiwan, 2010. BMC Infect Dis. 2011;11:346-352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juan LJ, Xiao WY, Jing ZM, et al. Epidemiological characteristics and correlative factors of hand -foot-mouth disease with onychomadesis caused by COXA6, Baoding. Mod Prev Med. 2017;44(05):778-781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Chang Z, Wu P, et al. Emerging Enteroviruses Causing Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease, China, 2010-2016. Emerg Infect Dis. 2018;24(10):1902-1906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abedi GR, Watson JT, Pham H, Nix WA, Oberste MS, Gerber SI. Enterovirus and Human Parechovirus Surveillance - United States, 2009-2013. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2015;64(34):940-943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomqvist S, Klemola P, Kaijalainen S, et al. Co-circulation of coxsackieviruses A6 and A10 in hand, foot and mouth disease outbreak in Finland. J Clin Virol. 2010;48(1):49-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osterback R, Vuorinen T, Linna M, Susi P, Hyypia T, Waris M. Coxsackievirus A6 and hand, foot, and mouth disease, Finland. Emerg Infect Dis. 2009;15(9):1485-1488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopalkrishna V, Patil PR, Patil GP, Chitambar SD. Circulation of multiple enterovirus serotypes causing hand, foot and mouth disease in India. J Med Microbiol. 2012;61(Pt 3):420-425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirand A, Henquell C, Archimbaud C, et al. Outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease/herpangina associated with coxsackievirus A6 and A10 infections in 2010, France: a large citywide, prospective observational study. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2012;18(5):E110-E118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto A, Hirata R, Ishimoto K, et al. An outbreak of hand-foot-and-mouth disease mimicking chicken pox, with a frequent association of onychomadesis in Japan in 2009: a new phenotype caused by coxsackievirus A6. Eur J Dermatol. 2014;24(1):103-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montes M, Artieda J, Pineiro LD, Gastesi M, Diez-Nieves I, Cilla G. Hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak and coxsackievirus A6, northern Spain, 2011. Emerg Infect Dis. 2013;19(4):676-678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathes EF, Oza V, Frieden IJ, et al. "Eczema coxsackium" and unusual cutaneous findings in an enterovirus outbreak. Pediatrics. 2013;132(1):e149-e157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puenpa J, Chieochansin T, Linsuwanon P, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by coxsackievirus A6, Thailand, 2012. Emerg Infect Dis. 2013;19(4):641-643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayman R, Shepherd M, Tarring C, Best E. Outbreak of variant hand-foot-and-mouth disease caused by coxsackievirus A6 in Auckland, New Zealand. J Paediatr Child Health. 2014;50(10):751-755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying Z, Ruo-nan Z, Hua-ping X, Chun C. Surveillancefor hand foot and mouth disease pathogens Cox A6, Cox A4 and Cox A10 in Guangzhou. Dis Surveill. 2016;31(10):817-823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han JF, Xu S, Zhang Y, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak caused by coxsackievirus A6, China, 2013. J Infect. 2014;69(3):303-305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenyu H, Hailong C, Yan L, Yiwei L, Quanli D. Epidemiological and etiological analysis of 16964 cases of hand, foot and mouth disease. Shaanxi Med J. 2014;5:626-628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng X, Guan W, Guo Y, et al. A novel recombinant lineage's contribution to the outbreak of coxsackievirus A6-associated hand, foot and mouth disease in Shanghai, China, 2012-2013. Sci Rep. 2015;5:11700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li-kun L, Li L, Dong-jing Y. Pathogens and their genetic characteristics of hand-foot-mouth disease in Tianjin city, 2013. Chin J Public Health. 2016;32(1):21-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo-feng W, Hong-yan C, Li-min Z, et al. Epidemiological characteristics on hand-foot-mouth disease in Daxing District of Beijing from 2009-2017. Occup Health. 2019;(05):626-628+632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YJ, Chang SC, Tsao KC, et al. Comparative genomic analysis of coxsackievirus A6 strains of different clinical disease entities. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(12):e52432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto T, Iizuka S, Enomoto M, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by coxsackievirus A6, Japan, 2011. Emerg Infect Dis. 2012;18(2):337-339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puenpa J, Mauleekoonphairoj J, Linsuwanon P, et al. Prevalence and characterization of enterovirus infections among pediatric patients with hand foot mouth disease, herpangina and influenza like illness in Thailand, 2012. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(6):e98888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou HT, Guo YH, Chen MJ, et al. Changes in enterovirus serotype constituent ratios altered the clinical features of infected children in Guangdong Province, China, from 2010 to 2013. BMC Infect Dis. 2016;16:399-406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo SH, Huang YC, Huang CG, et al. Clinical and epidemiologic features of Coxsackievirus A6 infection in children in northern Taiwan between 2004 and 2009. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2011;44(4):252-257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Sun Y, Du Y, et al. Characterization of Coxsackievirus A6- and Enterovirus 71-Associated Hand Foot and Mouth Disease in Beijing, China, from 2013 to 2015. Front Microbiol. 2016;7:391-403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di B, Zhang Y, Xie H, et al. Circulation of Coxsackievirus A6 in hand-foot-mouth disease in Guangzhou, 2010-2012. Virol J. 2014;11:157-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhenxi Z, Xiaoli Z, Xiao Z, Dongli W. Analysis of Clinical Features of Type CVA6 Hand-Foot-Mouth Disease. Clin Med Eng. 2015;22(07):858-859+862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LiuQi ZW, XiaChan CY. Clinical characteristics and molecular epidemiology of coxsackievirus A 6 hand, foot, and mouth disease in Wenzhou, 2014. Chin J Infect Dis. 2016;34(11):655-659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo-tao LIU, Min LIU. Comparison of clinical features in hand, foot and mouth disease caused by coxsackievirus A6 and enterovirus 71. Int J Virol. 2017;24(2):127-130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao-xiao L, Yan-hui C, Jian R, Di Q, Zheng KQ, Yong-quan W. Comparison of epidemiology and clinical features of hand, food, and mouth disease caused by coxsackievirus A 6, enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A 16 in Beijing. J of Pub Health and Prev Med. 2016;27(05):8-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao-li Z, Yi-fan REN, Fang C, Hai-yan YAN. Clinical characteristics of 69 cases of hand, foot and mouth disease and factors associated with nail abnormalities. Chin J Health Lab Tec. 2017;27(2):250-252,255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi M, Makino T, Hanaoka N, et al. Clinical manifestations of coxsackievirus A6 infection associated with a major outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan. Jpn J Infect Dis. 2013;66(3):260-261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upala P, Apidechkul T, Suttana W, Kullawong N, Tamornpark R, Inta C. Molecular epidemiology and clinical features of hand, foot and mouth disease in northern Thailand in 2016: a prospective cohort study. BMC Infect Dis. 2018;18(1):630-644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yangjun G. Comparative Analysis Of Clinic Characteristics Of Severe Hand-foot -mouth Diseases Caused By Coxsackievirus A6 And Enterovirus 71 [Master], Chongqing Medical University; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A guide to clinical management and public health response for hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD). World Health Organization. In:2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji H, Fan H, Lu P-X, et al. Surveillance for severe hand, foot, and mouth disease from 2009 to 2015 in Jiangsu province: epidemiology, etiology, and disease burden. BMC Infect Dis. 2019;19(1):79-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiaojuan T, Li L, Baomin Z, et al. Molecular epidemiology of coxsackievirus A6 associated with outbreaks of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Tianjin, China, in 2013. Arch Virol. 2015;160(4):1097-1104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogi M, Yano Y, Chikahira M, et al. Characterization of genome sequences and clinical features of coxsackievirus A6 strains collected in Hyogo, Japan in 1999-2013. J Med Virol. 2017;89(8):1395-1403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tianman W, Jihong H, Haixia L, et al. The tracing observation of hand, foot and mouth disease patients with onychomadesis. J Med Pest Control. 2014;30(9):1046-1047.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fangfang Z. An analysis of the epidemiology of the hand, foot and mouth disease with onychomadesis in Hebei Province [Master], Hebei Medical University; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang ZC, Kou ZQ, Bai YJ, et al. Epidemiological Research on Hand, Foot, and Mouth Disease in Mainland China. Viruses. 2015;7(12):6400-6411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing W, Liao Q, Viboud C, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in China, 2008-12: an epidemiological study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2014;14(4):308-318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Pan H, Wang X, et al. Epidemiological surveillance of hand, foot and mouth disease in Shanghai in 2014-2016, prior to the introduction of the enterovirus 71 vaccine. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2018;7(1):37-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng H, Lu J, Yang F, et al. The increasing epidemic of hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by coxsackievirus-A6, Guangdong, China, 2017. J Infect. 2018;76(2):220-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He S, Chen M, Wu W, et al. An emerging and expanding clade accounts for the persistent outbreak of Coxsackievirus A6-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease in China since 2013. Virology. 2018;518:328-334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Zhang Q, Hu Z. Profiles of Human Enteroviruses Associated with Hand, Foot, and Mouth Disease in Nanjing, China. Disaster Med Public Health Prep. 2019;1-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Q, Wang Y, Bian L, Xu M, Liang Z. EV-A71 vaccine licensure: a first step for multivalent enterovirus vaccine to control HFMD and other severe diseases. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2016;5(7):e75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, An Z, Huo D, et al. Enterovirus A71 vaccine effectiveness in preventing enterovirus A71 infection among medically-attended hand, foot, and mouth disease cases, Beijing, China. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2019;1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Meng FY, Li JX, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunology of an inactivated alum-adjuvant enterovirus 71 vaccine in children in China: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2013;381(9882):2024-2032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang YK, Chen KH, Chen KT. Hand, foot and mouth disease and herpangina caused by enterovirus A71 infections: a review of enterovirus A71 molecular epidemiology, pathogenesis, and current vaccine development. Rev Inst Med Trop Sao Paulo. 2018;60:e70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horsten HH, Kemp M, Fischer TK, Lindahl KH, Bygum A. Atypical Hand, Foot, and Mouth Disease Caused by Coxsackievirus A6 in Denmark: A Diagnostic Mimicker. Acta Derm Venereol. 2018;98(3):350-354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirand A, le Sage FV, Pereira B, et al. Ambulatory Pediatric Surveillance of Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease as Signal of an Outbreak of Coxsackievirus A6 Infections, France, 2014-2015. Emerg Infect Dis. 2016;22(11):1884-1893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinclair C, Gaunt E, Simmonds P, et al. Atypical hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with coxsackievirus A6 infection, Edinburgh, United Kingdom, January to February 2014. Euro Surveill. 2014;19(12):20745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshitomi H, Ashizuka Y, Ichihara S, et al. Molecular epidemiology of coxsackievirus A6 derived from hand, foot, and mouth disease in Fukuoka between 2013 and 2017. J Med Virol. 2018;90(11):1712-1719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu QB, Zhang XA, Wo Y, et al. Circulation of Coxsackievirus A10 and A6 in hand-foot-mouth disease in China, 2009-2011. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(12):e52073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Yu W, Xu T, Li Y, Wang X, Sun M. Molecular characteristic analysis for the VP1 region of coxsackievirus A6 strains isolated in Jiujiang area, China, from 2012 to 2013. Medicine (Baltimore). 2019;98(14):e15077.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puenpa J, Vongpunsawad S, Osterback R, et al. Molecular epidemiology and the evolution of human coxsackievirus A6. J Gen Virol. 2016;97(12):3225-3231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buttery VW, Kenyon C, Grunewald S, Oberste MS, Nix WA. Atypical Presentations of Hand, Foot, and Mouth Disease Caused by Coxsackievirus A6--Minnesota, 2014. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2015;64(29):805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feder HM Jr, Bennett N, Modlin JF. Atypical hand, foot, and mouth disease: a vesiculobullous eruption caused by Coxsackie virus A6. Lancet Infect Dis. 2014;14(1):83-86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Fort MK, Downing C, Doan HQ, et al. Coxsackievirus A6 associated hand, foot and mouth disease in adults: clinical presentation and review of the literature. J Clin Virol. 2014;60(4):381-386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita T, Ito M, Taniguchi A, Sakae K. Prevalence of coxsackievirus A5, A6, and A10 in patients with herpangina in Aichi Prefecture, 2005. Jpn J Infect Dis. 2005;58(6):390-391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan H, Liu A-P, Xie Q, Fu M, Chen B-T, Chen B-L. Study on the pathogenic spectrum changes of HFMD in Chenzhou, Hunan from 2010 to 2014. Chin J Health Lab Tec. 2015;25(24):4304-4309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hongyan G, Chengjie M, Qiaozhi Y, et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease caused by coxsackievirus A6, Beijing, 2013. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2014;33(12):1302-1303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logotheti M, Pogka V, Horefti E, et al. Laboratory investigation and phylogenetic analysis of enteroviruses involved in an aseptic meningitis outbreak in Greece during the summer of 2007. J Clin Virol. 2009;46(3):270-274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter J, Koptides D, Tryfonos C, Christodoulou C. Molecular typing of enteroviruses associated with viral meningitis in Cyprus, 2000-2002. J Med Microbiol. 2006;55(Pt 8):1035-1041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He YQ, Chen L, Xu WB, et al. Emergence, circulation, and spatiotemporal phylogenetic analysis of coxsackievirus a6- and coxsackievirus a10-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease infections from 2008 to 2012 in Shenzhen, China. J Clin Microbiol. 2013;51(11):3560-3566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei C, Yu-Wei W, Wen-xiang H, et al. Molecular Epidemiology of HFMD - associated Pathogen Coxsackievirus A6 in Fujian Province, 2011-2013. Chin J Virol. 2014;30(06):624-629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue-Wei H. Investigation and nalysis of hand foot and mouth disease complicated with onychomadesis and its countermeasures. Chin Prac Med. 2018;13(23):29-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng-e H, Xian-ping M, Li-ying Y, Jian-rong Y, Hai-bo Z, Jian Z. Clinical analysis of 83 cases of onychosis caused by hand foot and mouth disease. Chin J Prac Pediatr. 2016;3:233-234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haneke E. Onychomadesis and hand, foot and mouth disease--is there a connection? Euro Surveill. 2010;15(37):19664.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>