<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32163193</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-3016</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Paediatric and perinatal epidemiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Paediatr Perinat Epidemiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association between rotavirus vaccination and intussusception in Australian children: A record linkage study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>583</StartPage><EndPage>589</EndPage><MedlinePgn>583-589</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ppe.12669</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Post-licensure surveillance studies have shown a small but increased risk of intussusception among infants in the days following rotavirus vaccination (RV).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">We assessed the temporal trends of intussusception-coded hospitalisations before and after the commencement of a universal rotavirus vaccination programme in Western Australia (WA) in 2007. We also assessed the perinatal factors and pathogens associated with these hospitalisations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Intussusception-coded hospitalisations occurring in a cohort of 367&#xa0;476 WA-born children (2000-2012) aged &lt;5&#xa0;years were probabilistically linked to perinatal and pathology records. Age-specific incidence rates for overall and pathogen-specific intussusception-coded hospitalisations were calculated before (2000-2006) and after (2008-2012) RV introduction. Adjusted Cox proportional hazards models were used to assess perinatal risk factors for intussusception.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The overall rate of intussusception-coded hospitalisation was 26.4 per 100&#xa0;000 child-years (95% confidence interval [CI] 24.0, 29.0) among children aged &lt;5&#xa0;years, with rates being 70% higher (95% CI 39, 107) in the RV period than in the pre-RV period. Compared with the pre-RV period, rates were higher among those aged 12-23&#xa0;months (by 55%, 95% CI 5, 127) and 2-4&#xa0;years (by 84%, 95% CI 20, 182) in the RV period. However, the risk of intussusception-coded hospitalisations associated with intussusception management-related procedure code(s) was similar among all age groups in both birth periods. Among infants aged &lt;12&#xa0;months, male sex, non-Aboriginal status, birth to multiparous mothers, and birth in RV era were independent risk factors associated with intussusception-coded hospitalisations. Adenovirus was strongly associated with intussusception (6.7 per 100&#xa0;000 child-years, 95% CI 5.3, 9.3).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The risk of intussusception-coded hospitalisations was higher post-RV introduction, but not for intussusception-coded hospitalisations associated with procedure code(s). The increase was no higher in the vaccine-eligible age group than in older age groups, suggesting that the apparent increase is likely to be attributable to causes other than vaccination.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fathima</LastName><ForeName>Parveen</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4516-4127</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wesfarmers Centre of Vaccines and Infectious Diseases, Telethon Kids Institute, The University of Western Australia, Perth, WA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moore</LastName><ForeName>Hannah C</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6434-8290</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wesfarmers Centre of Vaccines and Infectious Diseases, Telethon Kids Institute, The University of Western Australia, Perth, WA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blyth</LastName><ForeName>Christopher C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2017-0683</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wesfarmers Centre of Vaccines and Infectious Diseases, Telethon Kids Institute, The University of Western Australia, Perth, WA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, The University of Western Australia, Perth, WA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases, Perth Children's Hospital, Perth, WA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PathWest Laboratory Medicine WA, QEII Medical Centre, Perth, WA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Snelling</LastName><ForeName>Thomas L</ForeName><Initials>TL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4670-0638</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wesfarmers Centre of Vaccines and Infectious Diseases, Telethon Kids Institute, The University of Western Australia, Perth, WA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases, Perth Children's Hospital, Perth, WA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Menzies School of Health Research and Charles Darwin University, Darwin, NT, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Curtin University, Perth, WA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Paediatr Perinat Epidemiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8709766</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0269-5022</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D022243">Rotavirus Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000258" MajorTopicYN="N">Adenovirus Infections, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001315" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Australia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017250" MajorTopicYN="N">Caliciviridae Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005759" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastroenteritis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016247" MajorTopicYN="N">Information Storage and Retrieval</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007443" MajorTopicYN="N">Intussusception</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016016" MajorTopicYN="N">Proportional Hazards Models</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012400" MajorTopicYN="N">Rotavirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D022243" MajorTopicYN="N">Rotavirus Vaccines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012480" MajorTopicYN="N">Salmonella Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intussusception</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pathogen-specific</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">record linkage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rotavirus vaccine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vaccine safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vaccine surveillance</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32163193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ppe.12669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Waseem M, Rosenberg HK. Intussusception. Pediatr Emerg Care. 2008;24(11):793-800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang J, Jiang B, Parashar U, Nguyen T, Bines J, Patel MM. Childhood intussusception: a literature review. Plos ONE. 2013;8(7):e68482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsicovetere P, Ivatury SJ, White B, Holubar SD. Intestinal intussusception: etiology, diagnosis, and treatment. Clin Colon Rectal Surg. 2017;30(01):30-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bines JE, Liem NT, Justice FA, et al. Risk factors for intussusception in infants in Vietnam and Australia: adenovirus implicated, but not rotavirus. J Pediatr. 2006;149(4):452-460.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okimoto S, Hyodo S, Yamamoto M, Nakamura K, Kobayashi M. Association of viral isolates from stool samples with intussusception in children. Int J Infect Dis. 2011;15(9):e641-e645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minney-Smith CA, Levy A, Hodge M, et al. Intussusception is associated with the detection of adenovirus C, enterovirus B and rotavirus in a rotavirus vaccinated population. J Clin Virol. 2014;61(4):579-584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker CLF, Rudan I, Liu L, et al. Global burden of childhood pneumonia and diarrhoea. Lancet. 2013;381(9875):1405-1416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanardi LR, Haber P, Mootrey GT, Niu MT, Wharton M, The VAERS Working Group. Intussusception among recipients of rotavirus vaccine: reports to the vaccine adverse event reporting system. Pediatrics. 2001;107(6):E97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz-Palacios GM, Perez-Schael I, Velazquez FR, et al. Safety and efficacy of an attenuated vaccine against severe rotavirus gastroenteritis. N Engl J Med. 2006;354(1):11-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vesikari T, Matson DO, Dennehy P, et al. Safety and efficacy of a pentavalent human-bovine (WC3) reassortant rotavirus vaccine. N Engl J Med. 2006;354(1):23-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hull BP, Dey A, Menzies RI, Brotherton JM, McIntyre PB. Immunisation coverage, 2012. Commun Dis Intell. 2014;38(3):E208-E231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tate JE, Yen C, Steiner CA, Cortese MM, Parashar UD. Intussusception rates before and after the introduction of rotavirus vaccine. Pediatrics. 2016;138(3):e20161082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn HE, Wood NJ, Cannings KL, et al. Intussusception after monovalent human rotavirus vaccine in Australia: severity and comparison of using healthcare database records versus case confirmation to assess risk. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2014;33(9):959-965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buttery JP, Standish J, Bines JE. Intussusception and rotavirus vaccines: consensus on benefits outweighing recognized risk. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2014;33(7):772-773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leino T, Ollgren J, Str&#xf6;mberg N, Elonsalo U. Evaluation of the intussusception risk after pentavalent rotavirus vaccination in Finnish infants. PloS ONE. 2016;11(3):e0144812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holman CAJ, Bass AJ, Rouse IL, Hobbs MS. Population-based linkage of health records in Western Australia: development of a health services research linked database. Aust NZ J Public Health. 1999;23(5):453-459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen D, Davis G, Draper G, et al. Evidence for the use of an algorithm in resolving inconsistent and missing Indigenous status in administrative data collections. Aust J Soc Issues. 2014;49(4):423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathima P, Snelling TL, Lehmann D, Blyth C, Waddington C, Moore H. Perinatal risk factors associated with gastroenteritis hospitalizations in Aboriginal and non-Aboriginal children in Western Australia (2000-2012): a record linkage cohort study. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2018;38:169-175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkwood CD, Ma L-F, Carey ME, Steele AD. The rotavirus vaccine development pipeline. Vaccine. 2017;37:7328-7335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hungerford D, Smith K, Tucker A, et al. Population effectiveness of the pentavalent and monovalent rotavirus vaccines: a systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. BMC Infect Dis. 2017;17(1):569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey A, Wang H, Menzies R, Macartney K. Changes in hospitalisations for acute gastroenteritis in Australia after the national rotavirus vaccination program. Med J Aust. 2012;197(8):453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathima P, Snelling TL, Gibbs RA. Effectiveness of rotavirus vaccines in an Australian population: a case-control study. Vaccine. 2019;37(41):6048-6053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field EJ, Field H, Vally K, Grimwood SB, Lambert SB. Pentavalent rotavirus vaccine and prevention of gastroenteritis hospitalizations in Australia. Pediatrics. 2010;126(3):e506-e512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maguire JE, Glasgow K, Glass K, et al. Rotavirus epidemiology and monovalent rotavirus vaccine effectiveness in Australia: 2010-2017. Pediatrics. 2019;144:e20191024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snelling TL, Schultz R, Graham J, et al. Rotavirus and the indigenous children of the Australian outback: monovalent vaccine effective in a high-burden setting. Clin Infect Dis. 2009;49(3):428-431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles T, Penninga L, Reurings J, Berry M. Intussusception in children: a clinical review. Acta Chir Belg. 2015;115(5):327-333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palupi-Baroto R, Lee KJ, Carlin JB, Bines JE. Intussusception in Australia: epidemiology prior to the introduction of rotavirus vaccine. Aust NZ J Public Health. 2015;39(1):11-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webby RJ, Bines JE, Barnes GL, Tindall H, Krause V, Patel M. Intussusception in the Northern Territory: the incidence is low in Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander children. J Paediatr Child Health. 2006;42(5):235-239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bines J, Ivanoff B. Acute intussusception in infants and children: incidence, clinical representation and management: a global perspective. Steering Committee on Diarrhoeal Disease Vaccines, Vaccine Development, Vaccines and Biologicals, World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland. Available from https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/67720/WHO_V-B_02.19_eng.pdf. 2002:33</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>