<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32352994</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Application of molecular source tracking and mass balance approach to identify potential sources of fecal indicator bacteria in a tropical river.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0232054</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0232054</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0232054</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0232054</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Microbial source tracking and a mass balance approach were used to identify sources of fecal indicator bacteria (FIB) in the Hanalei River, Kaua'i, Hawai'i. Historically, concentrations enterococci and Clostridium perfringens were significantly higher during storm flows compared to non-storm flows in the Hanalei River, and correlated to total suspended solids in the river. During targeted dry weather studies, the Hanalei River bed sediments and streambank soils were documented to harbor E. coli, enterococci, and the human- and pig-specific fecal markers in Bacteroidales, suggesting that sediments and soils may be potential sources of these microorganisms to the Hanalei river. The human-specific marker in Bacteroidales was four times as likely to be detected in sediment and soil samples as in water samples. Furthermore, the occurrence of host-specific source tracking markers is indicative that a portion of FIB present in the Hanalei River are of fecal origin. A mass balance approach was used to explore causes of observed FIB loadings and losses along different reaches of the river. Resuspension or deposition of FIB-laden river sediments cannot account for changes in E. coli and enterococci concentrations along the river during dry weather. Additionally, losses due to bacterial inactivation were insignificant. Groundwater and ditches draining agricultural and urban lands were shown to provide sufficient FIB fluxes to account for the observed loads along some river reaches. The presence of the human-specific Bacteroidales marker in the river water, sediments and adjacent soils, as well as the presence of the human enterovirus marker in the water, suggests that there is widespread human fecal contamination in the Hanalei River that is likely a result of nearby wastewater disposal systems.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamahara</LastName><ForeName>Kevan M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil &amp; Environmental Engineering, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keymer</LastName><ForeName>Daniel P</ForeName><Initials>DP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil &amp; Environmental Engineering, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Layton</LastName><ForeName>Blythe A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil &amp; Environmental Engineering, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walters</LastName><ForeName>Sarah P</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil &amp; Environmental Engineering, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thompson</LastName><ForeName>Rachelle S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil &amp; Environmental Engineering, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosener</LastName><ForeName>Matt</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Waip&#x101; Foundation, Hanalei, Kaua'i, Hawai'i, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boehm</LastName><ForeName>Alexandria B</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8162-5090</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil &amp; Environmental Engineering, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001419" MajorTopicYN="N">Bacteria</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D041963" MajorTopicYN="N">Bacteroidetes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016983" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterococcus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004784" MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental Monitoring</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005243" MajorTopicYN="N">Feces</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006254" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Hawaii</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045483" MajorTopicYN="N">Rivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="N">Water</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014871" MajorTopicYN="N">Water Microbiology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014876" MajorTopicYN="N">Water Pollution</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32352994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7192491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0232054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-19-33837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>USEPA (United States Environmental Protection Agency). National Summary of State Information in the Assessment and Total Maximum Daily Load Tracking and Implementation System (ATTAINS). 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashbolt NJ, Grabow WOK, Snozzi M. Risk assessment and management for water-related infectious disease: Indicators of microbial water quality In: Fewtrell L, Bartram J, editors. Water Quality: Guidelines, Standards and Health. London: IWA Publishing; 2001. pp. 289&#x2013;315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harwood VJ, Whitlock J, Withington V. Classification of antibiotic resistance patterns of indicator bacteria by discriminant analysis: use in predicting the source of fecal contamination in subtropical waters. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2000;66: 3698&#x2013;3704. 10.1128/aem.66.9.3698-3704.2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/aem.66.9.3698-3704.2000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10966379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layton BA, Walters SP, Lam L, Boehm AB. Enterococcus species distribution among human and animal hosts using multiplex PCR. Journal of Applied Microbiology. 2010;109: 539&#x2013;547. 10.1111/j.1365-2672.2010.04675.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2672.2010.04675.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20132375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parveen S, Portier KM, Robinson K, Edmiston L, Tamplin ML. Discriminant analysis of ribotype profiles of Escherichia coli for differentiating human and nonhuman sources of fecal pollution. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 1999;65: 3142&#x2013;3147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC91468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10388715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardina CM, Fujioka RS. Soil: the environmental source of Escherichia coli and enterococci in Hawai&#x2018;i&#x2019;s streams. Environmental Toxicology and Water Quality: An International Journal. 1991;6: 185&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamahara KM, Layton BA, Santoro AE, Boehm AB. Beach sands along the California coast are diffuse sources of fecal bacteria to coastal waters. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 2007;41: 4515&#x2013;4521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soller JA, Schoen ME, Bartrand T, Ravenscroft JE, Ashbolt NJ. Estimated human health risks from exposure to recreational waters impacted by human and non-human sources of faecal contamination. Water Research. 2010;44: 4674&#x2013;4691. 10.1016/j.watres.2010.06.049</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2010.06.049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20656314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujioka RS, Tenno K, Kansako S. Naturally-Occurring Fecal Coliforms and Fecal Streptococci in Hawaiis Fresh-Water Streams. Toxicity Assessment. 1988;3: 613&#x2013;630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byappanahalli MN, Fujioka RS. Evidence that tropical soil environment can support the growth of Escherichia coli. Water Science and Technology. 1998;38: 171&#x2013;174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui H, Yang K, Pagaling E, Yan T. Spatial and temporal variations of enterococci abundance and its relationship with microbial community in Hawai&#x2019;i beach sand and water. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2013;79: 3601&#x2013;3609. 10.1128/AEM.00135-13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.00135-13</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3675952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23563940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boehm AB, Fuhrman JA, Mrse RD, Grant SB. Tiered approach for identification of a human fecal pollution source at a recreational beach: case study at Avalon Bay, Catalina Island, California. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 2003;37: 673&#x2013;680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12636264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santoro AE, Boehm AB. Frequent occurrence of the human-specific Bacteroides fecal marker at an open coast marine beach: Relationship to waves, tides, and traditional indicators. Environmental Microbiology. 2007;9: 2038&#x2013;2049. 10.1111/j.1462-2920.2007.01319.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1462-2920.2007.01319.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17635548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosario K, Symonds EM, Sinigalliano C, Stewart J, Breitbart M. Pepper mild mottle virus as an indicator of fecal pollution. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2009;75: 7261&#x2013;7267. 10.1128/AEM.00410-09</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.00410-09</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2786529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19767474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanks OC, Nietch C, Simonich M, Younger M, Reynolds D, Field KG. Basin-wide analysis of the dynamics of fecal contamination and fecal source identification in Tillamook Bay, Oregon. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2006;72: 5537&#x2013;5546. 10.1128/AEM.03059-05</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.03059-05</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1538696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16885307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viau EJ, Goodwin KD, Yamahara KM, Layton BA, Sassoubre LM, Burns S, et al. Human bacterial pathogens and fecal indicators in tropical streams discharging to Hawaiian coastal waters. Water Research. 2011;45: 3279&#x2013;3290. 10.1016/j.watres.2011.03.033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2011.03.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21492899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boehm AB, Yamahara KM, Walters SP, Layton BA, Keymer DP, Strickfaden RM, et al. Dissolved inorganic nitrogen, soluble reactive phosphorous, and microbial pollutant loading from tropical rural watersheds in Hawai&#x2019;i to the coastal ocean during non-storm conditions. Estuaries and Coasts. 2011;34: 925&#x2013;936.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gawler AH, Beecher JE, Brandao J, Carroll NM, Falcao L, Gourmelon M, et al. Validation of host-specific Bacteriodales 16S rRNA genes as markers to determine the origin of faecal pollution in Atlantic Rim countries of the European Union. Water Research. 2007;41: 3780&#x2013;3784. 10.1016/j.watres.2007.01.028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2007.01.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17346765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffith GF, Weisberg SB, McGee CD. Evaluation of microbial source tracking methods using mixed fecal sources in aqueous test samples. Journal of Water and Health. 2003; 141&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15382720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boehm AB, Van De Werfhorst LC, Griffith JF, Holden PA, Jay JA, Shanks OC, et al. Performance of forty-three microbial source tracking methods: A twenty-seven lab evaluation study. Water Research. 2013;47: 6812&#x2013;6828. 10.1016/j.watres.2012.12.046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2012.12.046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23880218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernhard AE, Field KG. A PCR assay to discriminate human and ruminant feces on the basis of host differences in Bacteroides-Prevotella genes encoding 16S rRNA. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2000;66: 4571&#x2013;4574. 10.1128/aem.66.10.4571-4574.2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/aem.66.10.4571-4574.2000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11010920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanks OC, White K, Kelty CA, Hayes S, Sivaganesan M, Jenkins M, et al. Performance assessment PCR-based assays targeting Bacteroidales genetic markers of bovine fecal pollution. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2010;76: 1359&#x2013;1366. 10.1128/AEM.02033-09</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.02033-09</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2832389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20061457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dick LK, Bernhard AE, Brodeur TJ, Domingo JWS, Simpson J. M., Walters SP, et al. Host distributions of uncultivated fecal Bacteroides bacteria reveal genetic markers for fecal source identification. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2005;71: 3184&#x2013;3191. 10.1128/AEM.71.6.3184-3191.2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.6.3184-3191.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1151806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15933020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kildare BJ, Leutenegger CM, McSwain BS, Bambic DG, Rajal VB, Wuertz S. 16S rRNA-based assays for quantitative detection of universal, human-, cow-, and dog-specific fecal Bacteroidales: A Bayesian approach. Water Research. 2007;41: 3701&#x2013;3715. 10.1016/j.watres.2007.06.037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2007.06.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17644149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble RT, Fuhrman JD. Enteroviruses detected by reverse transcriptase polymerase chain reaction from the coastal waters of Santa Monica Bay, California: low correlation to bacterial indicator levels. Hydrobiologia. 2001;460: 175&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moc&#xe9;-Llivina L, Lucena F, Jofre J. Enteroviruses and bacteriophages in bathing waters. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2005;71: 6838&#x2013;6844. 10.1128/AEM.71.11.6838-6844.2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.11.6838-6844.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1287676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16269717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boehm AB, Yamahara KM, Love DC, Peterson BM, McNeill K, Nelson KL. Covariation and photoinactivation of traditional and novel indicator organisms and human viruses at a sewage-impacted marine beach. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 2009;43: 8046&#x2013;8052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19924921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boehm AB, Griffith J, McGee C, Edge TA, Solo-Gabriele HM, Whitman R, et al. Faecal indicator bacteria enumeration in beach sand: a comparison study of extraction methods in medium to coarse sands. Journal of applied microbiology. 2009;107: 1740&#x2013;50. 10.1111/j.1365-2672.2009.04440.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2672.2009.04440.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2810257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19659700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>TetraTech Inc., State of Hawaii Department of Health. EPA National Summary of Impaired Waters and TMDL Information&#x2014;TMDL ID: 35294. 2010. Available: http://oaspub.epa.gov/tmdl/waters_list.tmdl_report?p_tmdl_id=35294</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walters SP, Field KG. Persistence and growth of fecal Bacteroidales assessed by bromodeoxyuridine immunocapture. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2006;72: 4532&#x2013;9. 10.1128/AEM.00038-06</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.00038-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1489324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16820440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walters SP, Field KG. Survival and persistence of human and ruminant-specfiic fecal Bacteroidales in freshwater microcosms. Environmental Microbiology. 2009;11: 1410&#x2013;1421. 10.1111/j.1462-2920.2009.01868.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1462-2920.2009.01868.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19397677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuhrman JA, Liang X, Noble RT. Rapid detection of enteroviruses in small volumes of natural waters by real-time quantitative reverse transcriptase PCR. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2005;71: 4523&#x2013;4530. 10.1128/AEM.71.8.4523-4530.2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.8.4523-4530.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1183282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16085845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walters SP, Yamahara KM, Boehm AB. Persistence of nucleic acid markers of health-relevant organisms in seawater microcosms: Implications for their use in assessing risk in recreational waters. Water Research. 2009;43: 4929&#x2013;4939. 10.1016/j.watres.2009.05.047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2009.05.047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19616273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley MA, Roscoe ME. Automated statistical analysis of microbial enumeration by dilution series. Journal of Applied Bacteriology. 1983;55: 159&#x2013;164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boehm AB, Keymer DP, Shellenbarger GG. An analytical model of enterococci inactivation, grazing, and transport in the surf zone of a marine beach. Water Research. 2005;39: 3565&#x2013;3578. 10.1016/j.watres.2005.06.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2005.06.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16095656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinton LW, Hall CH, Lynch PA, Davies-Colley RJ. Sunlight inactivation of fecal indicator bacteria and bacteriophages from waste stabilization pond effluent in fresh and saline waters. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2002;68: 1122&#x2013;1131. 10.1128/AEM.68.3.1122-1131.2002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.68.3.1122-1131.2002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC123754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11872459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustard A, Bullock A, Dixon JM. Low flow estimation in the United Kingdom. Institute of Hydrology; 1992. Report No.: 108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan TE, Correll DL, Weller DE. Relating nutrient discharges from watersheds to land use and streamflow variability. Water Resources Research. 1997;33: 2579&#x2013;2590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byappanahalli M, Fujioka R. Indigenous soil bacteria and low moisture may limit but allow faecal bacteria to multiply and become a minor population in tropical soils. Water Science and Technology. 2004;50: 27&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15318482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roll BM, Fujioka RS. Sources of faecal indicator bacteria in a brackish, tropical stream and their impact on recreational water quality. Water Science and Technology. 1997;35: 179&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oshiro R, Fujioka R. Sand, soil, and pigeon droppings: Sources of indicator bacteria in the waters of Hanauma Bay, Oahu, Hawaii. Water Science and Technology. 1995;31: 251&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olapade OA, Depas MM, Jensen ET, McLellan SL. Microbial communities and fecal indicator bacteria associated with Cladophora mats on beach sites along Lake Michigan shores. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2006;72: 1932&#x2013;1938. 10.1128/AEM.72.3.1932-1938.2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.72.3.1932-1938.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1393218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16517640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macfarlane S, Macfarlane GT. Composition and metabolic activities of bacterial biofilms colonizing food residues in the human gut. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2006;72: 6204&#x2013;6211. 10.1128/AEM.00754-06</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.00754-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1563644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16957247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Probert HM, Gibson GR. Bacterial biofilms in the human gastrointestinal tract. Current Issues In Intestinal Microbiology. 2002;3: 23&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12400635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landry EF, Vaughn JM, Thomas MZ, Beckwith CA. Adsorption of enteroviruses to soil cores and their subsequent elution by artificial rainwater. Appl Environ Microbiol. 1979;38: 680&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">231936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straub TM, Pepper IL, Abbaszadegan M, Gerba CP. A method to detect enteroviruses in sewage sludge-amended soil using the PCR. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 1994;60: 1014&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC201425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8161168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surbeck CQ, Jiang SC, Ahn JH, Grant SB. Flow Fingerprinting Fecal Pollution and Suspended Solids in Stormwater Runoff from an Urban Coastal Watershed. Environmental Science and Technology. 2006;40: 4435&#x2013;4441. 10.1021/es060701h</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/es060701h</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16903282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huey GM, Meyer ML. Turbidity as an Indicator of Water Quality in Diverse Watersheds of the Upper Pecos River Basin. Water. 2010;2: 273&#x2013;284. 10.3390/w2020273</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w2020273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradford SA, Morales VL, Zhang W, Harvey RW, Packman AI, Mohanram A, et al. Transport and Fate of Microbial Pathogens in Agricultural Settings. Critical Reviews in Environmental Science and Technology. 2013;43: 775&#x2013;893. 10.1080/10643389.2012.710449</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10643389.2012.710449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knee KL, Layton BA, Street J, Boehm AB, Paytan A. Sources of nutrients and fecal indicator bacteria to nearshore waters on the North Shore of Kaua`i. Estuaries and Coasts. 2008;31: 607&#x2013;622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fries JS, Characklis GW, Noble RT. Attachment of Fecal Indicator Bacteria to Particles in the Neuse River Estuary, N.C. Journal of Environmental Engineering. 2006;132: 1338&#x2013;1345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characklis GW, Dilts MJ, Simmons OD, Likirdopulos CA, Krometis LAH, Sobsey MD. Microbial partitioning to settleable particles in stormwater. Water Research. 2005;39: 1773&#x2013;1782. 10.1016/j.watres.2005.03.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2005.03.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15899275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>