<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32410230</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>92</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of rotavirus vaccine implementation on the prevalence of coinfections with enteric viruses in Norway.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3151</StartPage><EndPage>3156</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3151-3156</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.26013</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Acute gastroenteritis (AGE) is a common illness in both adults and children worldwide and is caused by several microorganisms including viruses, bacteria, and parasites. Rotavirus (RV), which is the main cause of AGE, can occur as a mixed infection with other viruses. The aim of this study is to assess the molecular epidemiology of viral enteric viruses and assess RV coinfections with other enteric viruses and their influence on disease severity before and after RV vaccine introduction in children under 5 years of age. A total of 600 samples collected from children hospitalized for AGE in five large hospitals in Norway, and were analyzed for viral gastroenteritis agents by enzyme immunoassay and quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR). Positive results confirmed either by Sanger sequencing or genotyped by multiplex semi-nested RT-PCR. In total, 243 of the 300 (81%) samples, collected from the prevaccine cohort, were positive for at least one of the four viruses tested in this study. RV was most frequently identified in 82.6% of the samples. In the postvaccine cohort, 114 of the 300 (38%) samples were positive for at least one of the viruses tested. RV found in 36.5% of the samples. Coinfections found less frequently in the postvaccine cohort. Among circulating enteric viruses in Norway, RV is the most important cause of viral gastrointestinal infection. As expected, there were fewer RV positive and fewer coinfections after RV vaccine implementation. The results provide valuable data that can aid in further evaluation of the vaccine impact.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The Authors. Journal of Medical Virology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gibory</LastName><ForeName>Moustafa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3561-8460</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Medicine, Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Oslo, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology, Norwegian Institute of Public Health, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dembinski</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9259-9572</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology, Norwegian Institute of Public Health, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Flem</LastName><ForeName>Elmira</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5099-1960</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infection Epidemiology and Modeling, Norwegian Institute of Public Health, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haltbakk</LastName><ForeName>Ildri</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology, Norwegian Institute of Public Health, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dudman</LastName><ForeName>Susanne G</ForeName><Initials>SG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5047-4982</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Medicine, Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Oslo, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Norwegian Institute of Public Health</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D022243">Rotavirus Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009664" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Norway</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060085" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coinfection</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D022243" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rotavirus Vaccines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005759" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastroenteritis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012400" MajorTopicYN="N">Rotavirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005243" MajorTopicYN="N">Feces</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012401" MajorTopicYN="N">Rotavirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017720" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Epidemiology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005838" MajorTopicYN="N">Genotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060888" MajorTopicYN="N">Real-Time Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AGE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coinfections</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">norovirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qRT-PCR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rotavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vaccine shedding</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32410230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Weekly Epidemiological Record. 32. Geneva, Switzerland: WHO; 2007:285-296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Oza S, Hogan D, et al. Global, regional, and national causes of child mortality in 2000-13, with projections to inform post-2015 priorities: an updated systematic analysis. Lancet. 2015;385(9966):430-440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopman BA, Steele D, Kirkwood CD, Parashar UD. The vast and varied global burden of norovirus: prospects for prevention and control. PLoS Med. 2016;13(4):e1001999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow CM, Leung AK, Hon KL. Acute gastroenteritis: from guidelines to real life. Clin Exp Gastroenterol. 2010;3:97-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webb A, Starr M. Acute gastroenteritis in children. Aust Fam Physician. 2005;34(4):227-231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braeckman T, Van Herck K, Meyer N, et al. Effectiveness of rotavirus vaccination in prevention of hospital admissions for rotavirus gastroenteritis among young children in Belgium: case-control study. BMJ. 2012;345:e4752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chhabra P, de Graaf M, Parra GI, et al. Updated classification of norovirus genogroups and genotypes. J Gen Virol. 2019;100(10):1393-1406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo HL, Ajami N, Atmar RL, DuPont HL. Noroviruses: the leading cause of gastroenteritis worldwide. Discov Med. 2010;10(50):61-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Beek J, de Graaf M, Xia M, et al. Comparison of norovirus genogroup I, II and IV seroprevalence among children in the Netherlands, 1963, 1983 and 2006. J Gen Virol. 2016;97(9):2255-2264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Platts-Mills JA, Juma J, et al. Use of quantitative molecular diagnostic methods to identify causes of diarrhoea in children: a reanalysis of the GEMS case-control study. Lancet. 2016;388(10051):1291-1301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaral MSC, Estevam GK, Penatti M, et al. The prevalence of norovirus, astrovirus and adenovirus infections among hospitalised children with acute gastroenteritis in Porto Velho, state of Rond&#xf4;nia, western Brazilian Amazon. Mem Inst Oswaldo Cruz. 2015;110(2):215-221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moyo SJ, Hanevik K, Blomberg B, et al. Prevalence and molecular characterisation of human adenovirus in diarrhoeic children in Tanzania; a case control study. BMC Infect Dis. 2014;14:666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong HS, Jeong A, Cheon D-S. Epidemiology of astrovirus infection in children. Korean J Pediatr. 2012;55(3):77-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Jia R, Zhong H, et al. Molecular characterization and multiple infections of rotavirus, norovirus, sapovirus, astrovirus and adenovirus in outpatients with sporadic gastroenteritis in Shanghai, China, 2010-2011. Arch Virol. 2015;160(5):1229-1238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Rotavirus vaccines WHO position paper: January 2013-Recommendations. Vaccine. 2013;31(52):6170-6171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen Edwards C, de Blasio BF, Salamanca BV, Flem E. Re-evaluation of the cost-effectiveness and effects of childhood rotavirus vaccination in Norway. PLoS One. 2017;12(8):e0183306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruun TMD, Salamanca BVMP, Bekkevold TMP, et al. Burden of rotavirus disease in Norway: using National Registries for Public Health Research. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2016;35:396-400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis K. Vesikari Clinical Severity Scoring System Manual. Path website. 2011. http://online.fliphtml5.com/xdoe/reem/. Accessed February 28, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jothikumar N, Lowther JA, Henshilwood K, Lees DN, Hill VR, Vinj&#xe9; J. Rapid and sensitive detection of noroviruses by using TaqMan-based one-step reverse transcription-PCR assays and application to naturally contaminated shellfish samples. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2005;71(4):1870-1875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinje J, Vennema H, Maunula L, et al. International collaborative study to compare reverse transcriptase PCR assays for detection and genotyping of noroviruses. J Clin Microbiol. 2003;41(4):1423-1433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkbeiner SR, Le BM, Holtz LR, Storch GA, Wang D. Detection of newly described astrovirus MLB1 in stool samples from children. Emerging Infect Dis. 2009;15(3):441-444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarantis H, Johnson G, Brown M, Petric M, Tellier R. Comprehensive detection and serotyping of human adenoviruses by PCR and sequencing. J Clin Microbiol. 2004;42(9):3963-3969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee I, Ramani S, Primrose B, et al. Modification of rotavirus multiplex RT-PCR for the detection of G12 strains based on characterization of emerging G12 rotavirus strains from South India. J Med Virol. 2007;79(9):1413-1421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iturriza-G&#xf3;mara M, Kang G, Gray J. Rotavirus genotyping: keeping up with an evolving population of human rotaviruses. J Clin Virol. 2004;31(4):259-265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Challappa R, Saito M, Mejia C, et al. Burden of norovirus and rotavirus in children after rotavirus vaccine introduction, Cochabamba, Bolivia. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2016;94(1):212-217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos VS, Gurgel RQ, Cavalcante SMM, et al. Acute norovirus gastroenteritis in children in a highly rotavirus-vaccinated population in Northeast Brazil. J Clin Virol. 2017;88:33-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valentini D, Vittucci AC, Grandin A, et al. Coinfection in acute gastroenteritis predicts a more severe clinical course in children. Eur J Clin MicrobiolInfect Dis. 2013;32:909-915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S-X, Zhou Y-M, Xu W, et al. Impact of co-infections with enteric pathogens on children suffering from acute diarrhea in southwest China. Infect Dis Poverty. 2016;5(1):64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira Ferreira CE, Raboni SM, Aparecida Pereira L, Nogueira MB, Renaud Vidal LR, Almeida SM. Viral acute gastroenteritis: clinical and epidemiological features of co-infected patients. Braz J Infect Dis. 2012;16(3):267-272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson EJ. Rotavirus vaccines: viral shedding and risk of transmission. Lancet Infect Dis. 2008;8(10):642-649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J-s, Cao B, Gao H-c, et al. Faecal shedding of rotavirus vaccine in Chinese children after vaccination with Lanzhou lamb rotavirus vaccine. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):1001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran A, Talmud D, Lejeune B, et al. Prevalence of rotavirus, adenovirus, norovirus, and astrovirus infections and coinfections among hospitalized children in northern France. J Clin Microbiol. 2010;48(5):1943-1946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang XL, Koskenniemi E, Joensuu J, Vesikari T. Effect of rhesus rotavirus vaccine on enteric adenovirus-associated diarrhea in children. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 1999;29(3):366-369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang XL, Zeng SQ, Honma S, Nakata S, Vesikari T. Effect of rotavirus vaccine on Sapporo virus gastroenteritis in Finnish infants. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2001;20(3):295-300.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>