<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32681543</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2672</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>129</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of applied microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Appl Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ozone disinfection kinetics of poliovirus 1 determined by cell culture assay, RT-qPCR and ethidium monoazide qPCR reduction in a continuous quench-flow reactor.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1530</StartPage><EndPage>1540</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1530-1540</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jam.14787</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">A continuous quench-flow (CQF) reactor was developed to collect samples at the reaction times of less than one second. The reactor is applied to determine ozone disinfection kinetics of poliovirus and to study whether EMA-qPCR can assess the viral infectivity after ozone disinfection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Ozone disinfection of poliovirus was conducted in the developed CQF, and the disinfection kinetics were tested in the range of 0&#xb7;7-5&#xb7;0&#xa0;s at ozone concentration of 0&#xb7;08 and 0&#xb7;25&#xa0;mg&#xa0;l<sup>-1</sup> . Inactivation, damage on viral genome and damage on capsid integrity were determined by plaque assay, quantitative reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-qPCR) and ethidium monoazide treatment coupled with RT-qPCR (EMA-qPCR), respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">By using CQF, 2&#xb7;18 and 2&#xb7;76 log<sub>10</sub> reductions were observed at the reaction time of 0&#xb7;7&#xa0;s and ozone concentration of 0&#xb7;08 and 0&#xb7;25&#xa0;mg&#xa0;l<sup>-1</sup> , respectively, followed by tailing. Ozone disinfection kinetics of poliovirus 1 were better fit by the efficiency factor Hom model than by the Chick-Watson model, or the modified Chick-Watson model. Kinetics observed were similar between RT-qPCR and EMA-qPCR assays at the reaction times of &lt;2&#xb7;0&#xa0;s and ozone concentrations of 0&#xb7;08 and 0&#xb7;25&#xa0;mg&#xa0;l<sup>-1</sup> . At reaction times &gt;&#xa0;5&#xa0;s, viral concentration evaluated by EMA-qPCR was reduced in comparison to stable RT-qPCR results. Both assays still underestimated the virus inactivation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The simple developed reactor can be used to investigate viral ozone disinfection kinetics and to elucidate inactivation characteristics or mechanisms at very short exposure times.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SIGNIFICANCE AND IMPACT OF THE STUDY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The developed CQF reactor is beneficial for better understanding of virus inactivation by ozone, and the reactor can be used to better elucidate disinfection kinetics and mechanisms for future research. This work constitutes an important contribution to the existing knowledge of the application and limitation of the EMA/PMA-qPCR to assess virus infectivity after ozone disinfection.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The Society for Applied Microbiology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sangsanont</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7240-4416</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urban Engineering, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurisu</LastName><ForeName>F</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1567-4852</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Water Environment Technology, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Furumai</LastName><ForeName>H</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Water Environment Technology, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katayama</LastName><ForeName>H</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urban Engineering, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>The Bureau of Waterworks Tokyo Metropolitan Government</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>H28-Kenki-Ippan-005</GrantID><Agency>The Health Labor Sciences Research Grant</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Ministry of Health</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Appl Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9706280</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1364-5072</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001386">Azides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>66H7ZZK23N</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010126">Ozone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>69498-50-6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C014535">8-azidoethidium</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001386" MajorTopicYN="N">Azides</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002213" MajorTopicYN="N">Capsid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004203" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disinfection</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016679" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007700" MajorTopicYN="N">Kinetics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010126" MajorTopicYN="N">Ozone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017955" MajorTopicYN="N">Poliovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060888" MajorTopicYN="N">Real-Time Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010948" MajorTopicYN="N">Viral Plaque Assay</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D038301" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Inactivation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EMA-qPCR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">continuous quench-flow reactor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disinfection kinetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ozone disinfection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">viral infectivity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32681543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jam.14787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>American Public Health Association (1998) Standard Methods for the Examination of Water and Wastewater (20th edn). Washington DC: American Public Health Association.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosch, A., Lucena, F., Diez, J.M., Gajardo, R., Blasi, M. and Jofre, J. (1991) Waterborne viruses associated with hepatitis outbreak. J Am Water Works Assoc 83, 80-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buffle, M.O., Schumacher, J., Salhi, E., Jekel, M. and von Gunten, U. (2006) Measurement of the initial phase of ozone decomposition in water and wastewater by means of a continuous quench-flow system: application to disinfection and pharmaceutical oxidation. Water Res 40, 1884-1894.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canh, V.D., Kasuga, I., Furumai, H. and Katayama, H. (2019) Viability RT-qPCR combined with sodium deoxycholate pre-treatment for selective quantification of infectious viruses in drinking water samples. Food Environ Virol 11, 40-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currell, G. and Dowman, A. (2009) Essential Mathematics and Statistics for Science (2nd edn). Hoboken, NJ: Wiley-Blackwell.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding, N., Neumann, N.F., Price, L.M., Braithwaite, S.L., Balachandran, A., Mitchell, G., Belosevic, M. and El-Din, M.G. (2013) Kinetics of ozone inactivation of infectious prion protein. Appl Environ Microbiol 79, 2721-2730.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elizaqu&#xed;vel, P., Aznar, R. and S&#xe1;nchez, G. (2014) Recent developments in the use of viability dyes and quantitative PCR in the food microbiology field. J Appl Microbiol 116, 1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fittipaldi, M., Rodriguez, N.J.P., Codony, F., Adrados, B., Pe&#xf1;uela, G.A. and Morat&#xf3;, J. (2010) Discrimination of infectious bacteriophage T4 virus by propidium monoazide real-time PCR. J Virol Methods 168, 228-232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuster, N., Pint&#xf3;, R.M., Fuentes, C., Beguiristain, N., Bosch, A. and Guix, S. (2016) Propidium monoazide RTqPCR assays for the assessment of hepatitis A inactivation and for a better estimation of the health risk of contaminated waters. Water Res 101, 226-232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes, A.C., Nunes, J.C. and Sim&#xf5;es, R.M.S. (2010) Determination of fast ozone oxidation rate for textile dyes by using a continuous quench-flow system. J Hazard Mater 178, 57-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas, C.N. and Joffe, J. (1994) Disinfection under dynamic conditions: modification of hom's model for decay. Environ Sci Technol 28, 1367-1369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harakeh, M.S. and Butler, M. (1984) Factors influencing the ozone inactivation of enteric viruses in effluent. Ozone Sci Eng 6, 235-243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoebe, C.J.P.A., Vennema, H., de Roda Husman, A.M. and van Duynhoven, Y.T.H.P. (2004) Norovirus outbreak among primary schoolchildren who had played in a recreational water fountain. J Infect Dis 189, 699-705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunt, N.K. and Mari&#xf1;as, B.J. (1997) Kinetics of Escherichia coli inactivation with ozone. Water Res 31, 1355-1362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzenelson, E., Koerner, G., Biedermann, N., Peleg, M. and Shuval, H.I. (1979) Measurement of the inactivation kinetics of poliovirus by ozone in a fast-flow mixer. Appl Environ Microbiol 37, 715-718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, C.K., Gentile, D.M. and Sproul, O.J. (1980) Mechanism of ozone inactivation of bacteriophage f2. Appl Environ Microbiol 39, 210-218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, K., Katayama, H., Kitajima, M., Tohya, Y. and Ohgaki, S. (2011) Development of a real-time RT-PCR assay combined with ethidium monoazide treatment for RNA viruses and its application to detect viral RNA after heat exposure. Water Sci Technol 63, 502-507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, S.Y. and Ko, G. (2012) Using propidium monoazide to distinguish between viable and nonviable bacteria, MS2 and murine norovirus. Lett Appl Microbiol 55, 182-188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leifels, M., Jurzik, L., Wilhelm, M. and Hamza, I.A. (2015) Use of ethidium monoazide and propidium monoazide to determine viral infectivity upon inactivation by heat, UV- exposure and chlorine. Int J Hyg Environ Health 218, 686-693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim, M.Y., Kim, J.M., Lee, J.E. and Ko, G. (2010) Characterization of ozone disinfection of murine norovirus. Appl Environ Microbiol 76, 1120-1124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno, L., Aznar, R. and S&#xe1;nchez, G. (2015) Application of viability PCR to discriminate the infectivity of hepatitis A virus in food samples. Int J Food Microbiol 201, 1-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oristo, S., Lee, H.J. and Maunula, L. (2018) Performance of pre-RT-qPCR treatments to discriminate infectious human rotaviruses and noroviruses from heat-inactivated viruses: applications of PMA/PMAxx, benzonase and RNase. J Appl Microbiol 124, 1008-1016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parshionikar, S., Laseke, I. and Fout, G.S. (2010) Use of propidium monoazide in reverse transcriptase PCR to distinguish between infectious and noninfectious enteric viruses in water samples. Appl Environ Microbiol 76, 4318-4326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevost, B., Goulet, M., Lucas, F.S., Joyeux, M., Moulin, L. and Wurtzer, S. (2016) Viral persistence in surface and drinking water: suitability of PCR pre-treatment with intercalating dyes. Water Res 91, 68-76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randazzo, W., L&#xf3;pez-G&#xe1;lvez, F., Allende, A., Aznar, R. and S&#xe1;nchez, G. (2016) Evaluation of viability PCR performance for assessing norovirus infectivity in fresh-cut vegetables and irrigation water. Int J Food Microbiol 229, 1-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed, J.W., Hansel, H.H. and Jolly, W.L. (1974) Chemical synthesis with a quenched flow reactor. Hydroxytrihydroborate and peroxynitrite. J Am Chem Soc 96, 4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez, R.A., Pepper, I.L. and Gerba, C.P. (2009) Application of PCR-based methods to assess the infectivity of enteric viruses in environmental samples. Appl Environ Microbiol 75, 297-307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy, D., Wong, P.K.Y., Engelbrecht, R.S. and Chian, E.S.K. (1981) Mechanism of enteroviral inactivation by ozone. Appl Environ Microbiol 41, 718-723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangsanont, J., Katayama, H., Kurisu, F. and Furumai, H. (2014) Capsid-damaging effects of UV irradiation as measured by quantitative PCR coupled with ethidium monoazide treatment. Food Environ Virol 6, 269-275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin, G.A. and Sobsey, M.D. (2003) Reduction of Norwalk virus, poliovirus 1, and bacteriophage MS2 by ozone disinfection of water. Appl Environ Microbiol 69, 3975-3978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer, P.C. (1994) Control of disinfection by-products in drinking water. J Environ Eng 120, 727-744.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subekti, D., Lesmana, M., Tjaniadi, P., Safari, N., Frazier, E., Simanjuntak, C., Komalarini, S., Taslim, J. et&#xa0;al (2002) Incidence of Norwalk-like viruses, rotavirus and adenovirus infection in patients with acute gastroenteritis in Jakarta, Indonesia. FEMS Immunol Med Microbiol 33, 27-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurston-Enriquez, J.A., Haas, C.N., Jacangelo, J. and Gerba, C.P. (2005) Inactivation of enteric adenovirus and feline calicivirus by ozone. Water Res 39, 3650-3656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yates, M.V., Malley, J., Rochelle, P. and Hoffman, R. (2006) Effect of adenovirus resistance on UV disinfection requirements: a report on the state of adenovirus science. J Am Water Work Assoc 98, 93-106.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>