<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32761735</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1654</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Reviews in medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rev Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enteroviruses in gastrointestinal diseases.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>12</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-12</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/rmv.2148</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Gastrointestinal diseases including diarrhoea constitute a major cause of morbidity and mortality in infants and young children especially in developing countries. Worldwide deaths among all ages due to diarrhoea during 2015 were estimated to be about 1.31 million, diarrhoeal deaths in children below 5&#x2009;years of age being 499&#x2009;000. Rotavirus accounted for about 200&#x2009;000 deaths. Although diarrhoeal deaths decreased significantly during the last two decades, they still represent the third largest cause of infantile deaths. Several bacterial, viral, parasitic, fungal and non-infectious diarrhoea causing agents have been identified, but 30% to 40% of diarrhoeal cases remain undiagnosed. Enteroviruses transmit by the faecal-oral route and replicate first in intestinal cells before spreading to the target organ. They have been associated with diarrhoea in a few studies, but their causative role in diarrhoea in humans has not been systematically demonstrated. In view of the recent demonstration that enteroviruses cause diarrhoea in newborn mice pups, thus validating Koch's postulates, the purpose of this review is to emphasise the importance of recognising enteroviruses as major gastrointestinal pathogens associated with acute and persistent diarrhoea and non-diarrhoeal increased frequency of bowel movements in infants, young children and adults. Our studies and several other subsequent studies reported from different countries should stimulate strategies to reduce the burden of infantile gastrointestinal disease, which has hitherto remained unaddressed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rao</LastName><ForeName>C Durga</ForeName><Initials>CD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6018-4847</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, SRM University, Amaravati, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Rev Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9112448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1052-9276</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003967" MajorTopicYN="N">Diarrhea</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005243" MajorTopicYN="N">Feces</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005767" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastrointestinal Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012401" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rotavirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32761735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rmv.2148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>King AMQ, Lefkowitz EJ, Mushegian AR, et al. Changes to taxonomy and the International Code of Virus Classification and Nomenclature ratified by the International Committee on Taxonomy of Viruses (2018). Arch Virol. 2018;163(9):2601-2631. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00705-018-3847-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker PJ, Siddell SG, Lefkowitz EJ, et al. Changes to virus taxonomy and the International Code of Virus Classification and Nomenclature ratified by the International Committee on Taxonomy of Viruses (2019). Arch Virol. 2019;164:2417-2429. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00705-019-04306-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIntyre CL, Knowles NJ, Simmonds P. Proposals for the classification of human rhinovirus species A, B and C into genotypically assigned types. J Gen Virol. 2013;94:1791-1806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enterovirus-Picornaviridae.com. https://www.picornaviridae.com/enterovirus/enterovirus.htm. Accessed on March 31, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee TC, Guo HR, Su HJ, et al. Diseases caused by enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2009;28:904-910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao CD, Naidu JR, Maiya PP, Ananda Babu A, Bailly J-L. Large-scale HFMD epidemics caused by coxsackievirus A16 in Bangalore, India during 2013 and 2015. Infect Genet Evol. 2017;55:228-235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Polio Eradication Initiative 2019. (Acccessed May 15, 2020http://www.polioeradication.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassidy H, Poelman R, Knoester M, van Leer-Buter CC, Niesters HGM. Enterovirus D68 - the new polio? Front Microbiol. 2018;9:2677. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2018.02677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm-Hansen CC, Midgley SE, Fischer TK. Global emergence of enterovirus D68: a systematic review. Lancet Infect Dis. 2016;16(5):e64-e75. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1473-3099(15)00543-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao CD, Yergolkar P, Shankarappa KS. Analysis of antigenic diversity of enteroviruses associated with nonpolio acute flaccid paralysis, India, 2007-2009. Emerg Infect Dis. 2012;18:1833-1840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao CD. Non-polio enteroviruses, the neglected, and emerging human pathogens: are we waiting for the sizzling enterovirus volcano to erupt? Proc Indian Natl Sci Acad. 2015;81:441-562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallansch M, Roos R. Enteroviruses: polioviruses, Coxsackieviruses, echoviruses, and newer enteroviruses. In: Knipe DM, Howley PM, Griffin DE, et al., eds. Fields Virology. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluver, Lippincott, Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2007:839-893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T-C, Shih S-R. (2011) Drug discovery in enteroviral infections. Infect Disord Drug Targets 2011; 11: 337-345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewthwaite P, Perera D, Ooi MH, et al. Enterovirus 75 encephalitisin children, southern India. Emerg Infect Dis. 2010;16:1780-1782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>el-Sageyer MM, Szendroi A, Hutter E, et al. Characterization of an echovirus type 11&#x2032; (prime) epidemic strain causing haemorrhagic syndrome in newborn babies in Hungary. Acta Virol. 1998;42:157-166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lashkevich VA, Koroleva GA, Lukashev AN, Denisova EV, Katargina LA (2004) Enterovirus uveitis Rev Med Virol 2004; 14: 241-254</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moldin JF. Fatal echovirus disease in premature neonates. Pediatrics. 1980;66:775-780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostoufizadeh M, Lack EE, Gang DL, Perez-Atayde AR, Driscoll SG. Postmortem manifestations of echovirus 11 sepsis in five newborn infants. Hum Pathol. 1983;14:818-823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T, Willison H. Infectious causes of acute flaccid paralysis. Curr Opin Infect Dis. 2003;16:375-381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukashev AN, Lashkevich VA, Koroleva GA, et al. Molecular epidemiology of enteroviruses causing uveitis and multisystem hemorrhagic disease of infants. Virology. 2003;307:45-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao CD, Ananda Babu M, Raghavendra A, Dhananjaya D, Sudheendra K, Maiya PP. Non-polio enteroviruses and their association with acute diarrhea in children in India. Infect Genet Evol. 2013;17:153-161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao DC, Reddy H, Sudheendra K, et al. Non-polio enterovirus association with persistent diarrhea in children as revealed by a follow-up study of an India cohort during the first two years of life. J Clin Virol. 2014;61:125-131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2016 Diarrhoeal Disease Collaborators. Estimates of the global, regional, and national morbidity, mortality, and aetiologies of diarrhoea in 195 countries: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2016. Lancet Infect Dis. 2018;18(11): 1211-1228. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(18)30362-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Who.int. Diarrhoeal disease. 2017. [online] https://www.who.int/news-2011;room/fact-sheets/detail/diarrhoeal-disease. Accessed 12 April, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawford SE, Ramani S, Tate JE, et al. Rotavirus infection. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2017;3:17083. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrdp.2017.83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark B, McKendrick M. A review of viral gastroenteritis. Curr Opin Infect Dis. 2004;17:461-469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamieson FB, Wang EE, Bain C, Good J, Duckmanton L, Petric M. Human torovirus: a new nosocomial gastrointestinal pathogen. J Infect Dis. 1998;178:1263-1269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y, Cheng WX, Xu ZQ, et al. Highprevalence of human bocavirus 2 and its role in childhood acute gastroenteritis in China. J Clin Virol. 2011;52:251-253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallimore CI, Appleton H, Lewis D, Green J, Brown DW. Detection and characterization of bisegmmented double-stranded RNA viruses (picobirnaviruses) in human fecal specimens. J Med Virol. 1995;45:135-140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapoor A, Victoria J, Simmonds P, et al. A highly prevalent and genetically diversified Picornaviridae genus in South Asian children. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2008;105:20482-20487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Z, Kong Y, Wang J, Wang Q, Huang A, Xu H. Etiological study of enteric viruses and the genetic diversity of norovirus, sapovirus, adenovirus, and astrovirus in children with diarrhea in Chongqing, China. BMC Infect Dis. 2013;13:412. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2334-13-412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denno DM, Klein EJ, Young VB, Fox JG, Wang D, Tarr PI. Explaining unexplained diarrhea and associating risks and infections. Anim Health Res Rev. 2007;8:69-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greniger AL, Runckel C, Chiu CY, et al. The complete genome of klassevirus-a novel picornavirus in pediatric stool. Virol J. 2009;6:82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtz LR, Finkbeiner SR, Kirkwood CD, Wang D. Identification of a novel picornavirus related to cosaviruses in a child with acute diarrhea. Virol J. 2008;5:159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtz LR, Finkbeiner SR, Zhao G, et al. Klassevirus I, a previously undescribed member of the family Picornaviridae, is globally widespread. Virology J. 2009;6:86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harada S, Okada M, Yahiro S, et al. Surveillance of pathogens in outpatients with gastroenteritis and characterization of sapovirus strains between 2002 and 2007 in Kumamoto Prefecture, Japan. J Med Virol. 2009;81:1117-1127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rachakonda G, Choudekar A, Parveen S, Bhatnagar S, Patwari A, Broor S. Genetic diversity of noroviruses and sapoviruses in children withacute sporadic gastroenteritis in New Delhi, India. J Clin Virol. 2008;43:42-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao CD, Gowda K, Reddy BSY. Sequence analysis of VP4 and VP7 genes of nontypeable strains identifies a new pair of outer capsid proteins representing novel P and G genotypes in bovine rotaviruses. Virology. 2000;276:104-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aijaz S, Gowda K, Jagannath MR, et al. Epidemiology of symptomatic human rotaviruses in Bangalore and Mysore, India, from 1988 to 1994 as determined by electropherotype, subgroup and serotype analysis. Arch Virol. 1996;141:715-726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichenwald HF, Ababio A, Arky AM, Hartman AP. Epidemic diarrhea in premature and older infants caused by ECHO virus type 18. JAMA. 1958;166:1563-1566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommerville RG. Enteroviruses and diarrhoea in young persons. Lancet. 1958;2(7061):1347-1349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berkovich S, Kibrick S. Echo ii outbreak in newborn infants and mothers. Pediatrics. 1964;33:534-540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelon W, Villarejos VM, Rhim JS, Payne FJ. Coxsackie group B virus infection and acute diarrhoea occurring among children in Costa Rica. Arch Dis Child. 1966;41:636-641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moffet HL, Shulenberger HK, Burkholder ER. Epidemiology and etiology of severe infantile diarrhea. J Pediatr. 1968;72:1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tai FH, Wang HC. Acute gastroenteritis associated with echovirus type 1. Southeast Asian J Trop Med Public Health. 1973;4:311-315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lake AM, Lauer BA, Clark JC, Wesenberg RL, McIntosh K. Enterovirus infections in neonates. J Pediatr. 1976;89:787-791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zavate O, Ivan A, Avram G, Cotor F, Vasiliu D, Irinescu A. Enteroviral etiology of some epidemic outbreaks in a zone of Romania. Virologie. 1976;27:55-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oishi I, Maeda A, Otsu K, Minekawa Y, Kitaura T. An outbreak of diarrhea in school children associated with Coxsackie virus B-3 infection. Biken J. 1979;22:21-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips CA, Aronson MD, Tomkow J, Phillips ME. Enteroviruses in Vermont, 1969-1978: an important cause of illness throughout the year. J Infect Dis. 1980;141:162-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madeley CR. Fatal diarrhoea and coxsackie A1 virus. Lancet. 1982;1(8279):1013-1014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;rmann W, Statz A, Mertens T, Gladtke E, Eggers HJ. Two cases of coxsackie B2 infection in neonates: clinical, virological, and epidemiological aspects. Eur J Pediatr. 1983;140:59-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain NC, Batra SK, Ram GC. Isolation and characterization of enterovirus from neonatal goats with diarrhoea. J Diarrhoeal Dis Res. 1984;2:43-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott MR, Cloonan MJ, Montgomery J, Smith DD. Pathogens detected in the faeces of children with diarrhoea in a Sydney hospital. Med J Aust. 1984;141:26-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel JR, Daniel J, Mathan VI. An epidemic of acute diarrhea in rural southern India associated with echovirus type 11 infection. J Hyg (Lond). 1985;95:483-492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wylie SL, Pass DA. Investigations of an enteric infection of cockatoos caused by an enterovirus-like agent. Aust Vet J. 1989;66:321-324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danes L. Are enteroviruses the causal agents of acute enteritis in humans? Cesk Epidemiol Mikrobiol Imunol. 1993;42:39-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrnst A, Eriksson M. Epidemiological features of type 22 echovirus infection. Scand J Infect Dis. 1993;25(3):275-281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrnst A, Eriksson M. Echovirus type 23 observed as a nosocomial infection in infants. Scand J Infect Dis. 1996;28:205-206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birenbaum E, Handsher R, Kuint J, et al. Echovirus type 22 outbreak associated with gastro-intestinal disease in a neonatal intensive care unit. Am J Perinatol. 1997;14:469-473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verboon-Maciolek MA, Krediet TG, van Loon AM, et al. Epidemiological survey of neonatal non-polio enterovirus infection in The Netherlands. J Med Virol. 2002;66:241-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin SC, Shyur SD, Ma YC, Huang LH, Lee WI. Hyper-IgM1 syndrome with interstitial pneumonia and diarrhea caused by coxsackievirus B4 in a 3-month-old infant. Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2005;95:93-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phan TG, Nguyen TA, Shimizu H, et al. Identification of enteroviral infection among infants and children admitted to hospital with acute gastroenteritis in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam. JMed Virol. 2005;77:257-264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyangao JW, Kingori P, Okoth FA. Detection and identification of echovirus 7 from a child with gastroenteritis. East Afr Med J. 2006;83:666-669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai BS, Wan Mansor H, Vasantha T, Norizah I, Chua KB. An outbreak of echovirus 11 amongst neonates in a confinement home in Panang, Malaysia. Med J Malaysia. 2007;62:223-226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste MS, Jiang X, Maher K, Nix WA, Jiang B. The complete genome sequences for three simian enteroviruses isolated from captive primates. Arch Virol. 2008;153:2117-2122. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00705-008-0225-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva PA, Stark K, Mockenhaupt FP, et al. Molecular characterization of enteric viral agents from children in northern region of Ghana. J Med Virol. 2008;80:1790-1798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil PR, Chitamber SD, Gopalakrishna V. Molecular detection of enteroviruses among children hospitalized with acute gastroenteritis from Pune, Maharashtra. Ind J Virol. 2009;20:P12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarcella C, Carsi S, Cadoria F, et al. (2009) An outbreak of viral gastroenteritis linked to municipal water supply, Lombardy, Italy, June 2009. Euro Surveill. 2009;14(29):19274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaimongkol N, Khamrin P, Suantai B, et al. A wide variety of diarrhea viruses circulating in pediatric patients in Thailand. Clin Lab. 2012;58:117-123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Chang J, Wang Q, Yu L. Isolation of two Chinese bovine enteroviruses and sequence analysis of their complete genomes. Arch Virol. 2012;157(12):2369-2375. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00705-012-1424-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao CD, Maiya PP, Ananda Babu M. Non-diarrhoeal increased frequency of bowel movements (IFoBM-ND): enterovirus association with the symptoms in children. BMJ Open Gastroenterol. 2014;1:e000011. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjgast-2014-000011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao CD, Reddy H, Naidu JR, Raghavendra A, Radhika NS, Karande A An enzyme-linked immune focus assay for rapid detection and enumeration, and a newborn mouse model for human non-polio enteroviruses associated with acute diarrhea. J Virol Methods 2015; 224: 47-52. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jviromet.2015.08.007, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MK, Chan PK, Ho II, Lai WM. Enterovirus infection among patients admitted to hospital in Hong Kong in 2010: epidemiology, clinical characteristics, and importance of molecular diagnosis. J Med Virol. 2013;85:1811-1817. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.23663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fauveau V, Henry FJ, Briend A, Yunus M, Chakraborty J. Persistent diarrhea as a cause of childhood mortality in rural Bangladesh. Acta Paediatr Suppl. 1992;381:12-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhan MK, Bhandari N, Bhatnagar S, Bhal R. Epidemiology &amp; management of persistent diarrhea in children of developing countries. Indian J Med Res. 1996;104:103-114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagundes-Neto U. Persistent diarrhea: still a serious public health problem in developing countries. Curr Gastroenterol Rep. 2013;15:345. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11894-013-0345-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DuPont HL. Persistent diarrhea: a clinical review. JAMA. 2016;315:2712-2723. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2016.7833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandsma RHJ, Sadiq K, Bhutta ZA. Persistent diarrhoea: current knowledge and novel concepts. Paediatr Int Child Health. 2019;39:41-47. https://doi.org/10.1080/20469047.2018.1504412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima AA, Fang G, Schorling JB, et al. Persistent diarrhea in Northeast Brazil: etiologies and interactions with malnutrition. Acta Paediatr Suppl. 1992;381:39-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarker SA, Ahmed T, Br&#xfc;ssow H. Persistent diarrhea: a persistent infection with enteropathogens or a gut commensal dysbiosis? Environ Microbiol. 2017;19:3789-3801. https://doi.org/10.1111/1462-2920.13873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstockt B, Deleenheer B, Sermon F, Van Der Steen K, Vandervoort J. An unusual cause of severe, persistent diarrhoea. Acta Gastroenterol Belg. 2017;80(3):416-418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronchetti AM, Henry B, Ambert-Balay K, et al. Norovirus-related chronic diarrhea in a patient treated with alemtuzumab for chronic lymphocytic leukemia. BMC Infect Dis. 2014;14:239. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2334-14-239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couturier BA, Hale DC, Couturier MR. Association of Campylobacter upsaliensis with persistent bloody diarrhea. J Clin Microbiol. 2012;50:3792-3794. https://doi.org/10.1128/JCM.01807-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okhuysen PC, Dupont HL. Enteroaggregative Escherichia coli (EAEC): a cause of acute and persistent diarrhea of worldwide importance. J Infect Dis. 2010;202:503-505. https://doi.org/10.1086/654895.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penny MF, Brown KH. Lactose feeding during persistent diarrhea. Acta Paediatr Suppl. 1992;381:133-138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore SR, Lima NL, Soares AM, et al. Prolonged episodes of acute diarrhea reduce growth and increase risk of persistent diarrhea in children. Gastroenterology. 2010;139(4):1156-1164. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2010.05.076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaton KW, Radvan J, Cripps H, Mountford RA, Braddon FE, Hughes AO. Defecation frequency and timing, stool form in the general population: a prospective study. Gut. 1992;33:818-824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osatakul S, Yossuk P, Mo-Suwan L. Bowel habits of normal Thai children. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 1995;20:339-342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noseworthy J. Frequent bowel movements. 2014. http://www.mayoclinic.com/health/frequent-bowel-movements/MY00786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukas I, Willet WC, Colditz GA, et al. Prospective study of bowel movement, laxative use, and risk of colorectal cancer among women. Am J Epidemiol. 2000;151:958-964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camilleri M, Lee JS, Viramontes B, Bharucha AE, Tangalos EG. Insights into the pathophysiology and mechanisms of constipation and diverticulosis in older people. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2000;48:1142-1150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukas I, Leitzmann MF, Willet WC, et al. Association of Bowel movement frequency and use of laxatives with occurrence of symptomatic gallstone disease in a prospective study of women. Am J Gastroenterol. 2001;96:715-721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitajima H, Ida S, Fujimura M. Daily bowel movements and Escherichia coli O157 infection. Arch Dis Child. 2002;87:335-336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lonstreth GF. Bowel patterns and anxiety. Demographic factors. J Clin Gastroenterol. 1993;17:128-132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chey WD, Kurlander J, Eswaran S. Irritable bowel syndrome: a clinical review. JAMA. 2015;313:949-958. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2015.0954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagannath MR, Kesavulu MM, Deepa R, et al. N- and C-terminal cooperation in rotavirus enterotoxin:novel mechanism of modulation of the properties of a multifunctional protein by a structurally and functionally overlapping conformational domain. J Virol. 2006;80:412-425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajasekaran D, Sastri NP, Jagannath MR, et al. The flexible C terminus of the rotavirus non-structural protein NSP4 is an important determinant of its biological properties. J Gen Virol. 2008;89:1485-1496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sastri P, Kiranmayee P, Jagannath MR, Suguna K, Rao CD. Conformational differences unfold the wide range of enterotoxigenic abilities exhibited by rNSP4 peptides from different rotavirus strains. The Open Virology J. 2011;5:113-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nzolo D, Ntetani Aloni M, Mpiempie Ngamasata T, et al. Adverse events following immunization with oral poliovirus in Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo: preliminary results. Pathog Glob Health. 2013;107(7):381-384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melica G, Langlois AL, Le Goff J, et al. Acute enteritis associated with Coxsackievirus A19 in a kidney transplant patient. Transpl Infect Dis. 2014;16:344-346. https://doi.org/10.1111/tid.12191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omatsu T, Tsuchiaka S, Hirata T, et al. Detection of enterovirus genome sequence from diarrheal feces of goat. Virus Genes. 2014;48:550-552. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11262-014-1057-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saikruang W, Khamrin P, Suantai B, et al. Detection of diarrheal viruses circulating in adult patients in Thailand. Arch Virol. 2014;159:3371-3375. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00705-014-2191-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun G, Yi M, Tian H, et al. A novel human enterovirus recombinant from a child with diarrhea. Arch Virol. 2014;159:333-337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B, Tang C, Yue H, Ren Y, Song Z. Viral metagenomics analysis demonstrates the diversity of viral flora in piglet diarrhoeic faeces in China. J Gen Virol. 2014;95(Pt7):1603-1611. https://doi.org/10.1099/vir.0.063743-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thongprachum A, Takanashi S, Kalesaran AF, et al. Four-year study of viruses that cause diarrhea in Japanese pediatric outpatients. J Med Virol. 2015;87:1141-1148. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.24155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei X, Xiao X, Wang J. Innate immunity evasion by enteroviruses: insights into virus-host interact. Ion. Viruses. 2016;8(1):22. https://doi.org/10.3390/v8010022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dung N, Anh PH, Van Cuong N, et al. Large-scale screening and characterization of enteroviruses and kobuviruses infecting pigs in Vietnam. J Gen Virol. 2016;97:378-388. https://doi.org/10.1099/jgv.0.000366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou HT, Yi HS, Guo YH, et al. Enterovirus-related diarrhoea in Guangdong, China: clinical features and implications in hand, foot and mouth disease and herpangina. BMC Infect Dis. 2016;16:128. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12879-016-1463-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chansaenroj J, Tuanthap S, Thanusuwannasak T, et al. Human enteroviruses associated with and without diarrhea in Thailand between 2010 and 2016. PLoS One. 2017;12(7):e0182078. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0182078.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez DE, Weese JS. Viral enteritis in calves. Can Vet J. 2017;58(12):1267-1274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumthip K, Khamrin P, Maneekarn N. Detection of poliovirus infection in children with acute gastroenteritis in Chiang Mai, Thailand. J Med Virol. 2017;89:775-781. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.24694.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumthip K, Khamrin P, Ushijima H, Maneekarn N. Multiple enterovirus genotypes circulating in children hospitalized with acute gastroenteritis in Thailand. Infect Genet Evol. 2017;55:324-331. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.meegid.2017.10.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moudjahed H, Pin&#xe7;on C, Alidjinou K, Dewilde A, Goffard A. Comparison of three molecular assays for detection of enteric viruses in stool samples. J Virol Methods. 2017;250:55-58. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jviromet.2017.09.026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, He J, Lu H, et al. A novel enterovirus species identified from severe diarrheal goats. PLoS One. 2017;12:e0174600. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0174600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcal&#xe1; AC, P&#xe9;rez K, Blanco R, et al. Molecular detection of human enteric viruses circulating among children with acute gastroenteritis in Valencia, Venezuela, before rotavirus vaccine implementation. Gut Pathog. 2018;10:6. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13099-018-0232-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham NTK, Thongprachum A, Trinh QD, et al. Detection and genetic characterization of enterovirus strains circulating among children with acute gastroenteritis in Japan during 2014-2016. Infect Genet Evol. 2018;61:16-19. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.meegid.2018.03.009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen XX, Qiu FZ, Li GX, et al. A case control study on the prevalence of enterovirus in children samples and its association with diarrhea. Arch Virol. 2018;164:63-68. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00705-018-4021-5.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>