<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32905647</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1754</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of paediatrics and child health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Paediatr Child Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Polio - The old foe and new challenges: An update for clinicians.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1527</StartPage><EndPage>1532</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1527-1532</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jpc.15140</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The Global Polio Eradication Initiative since 1988 has seen the impact of poliovirus decline from frequent global epidemics in the early 1900s to being now only endemic in two countries today. Global vaccination programmes and surveillance for the disease have resulted in the landmark eradication of two of the three poliovirus strains in the last 5&#x2009;years. Australia continues to contribute to global surveillance efforts for the disease via the Australian Paediatric Surveillance Unit and the Paediatric Active Enhanced Disease Surveillance Network, which aim to detect cases of acute flaccid paralysis in children, the key clinical feature of poliomyelitis. Today, in the era of the polio 'endgame', there is growing recognition of non-polio enteroviruses causing paralytic diseases that are polio-like, particularly in children, with an increased need for awareness and vigilance by paediatric clinicians.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Paediatrics and Child Health Division (The Royal Australasian College of Physicians).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bao</LastName><ForeName>Junchao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7124-0464</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sydney Medical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Medicine, The Children's Hospital at Westmead, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thorley</LastName><ForeName>Bruce</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Enterovirus Reference Laboratory, The Peter Doherty Institute for Infection and Immunity, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Isaacs</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9593-7378</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sydney Medical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases, The Children's Hospital at Westmead, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dinsmore</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Immunisation Research and Surveillance, Kid's Research, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elliott</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth J</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sydney Medical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Medicine, The Children's Hospital at Westmead, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Paediatric Surveillance Unit, Kid's Research, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McIntyre</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Medicine, The Children's Hospital at Westmead, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Immunisation Research and Surveillance, Kid's Research, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Women's and Children's Health, University of Otago, Dunedin, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Britton</LastName><ForeName>Philip N</ForeName><Initials>PN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2993-6000</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sydney Medical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases, The Children's Hospital at Westmead, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>J Paediatr Child Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9005421</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1034-4810</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001315" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Australia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018563" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Notification</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011051" MajorTopicYN="Y">Poliomyelitis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017955" MajorTopicYN="Y">Poliovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014944" MajorTopicYN="N">World Health Organization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acute flaccid paralysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enterovirus A71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enterovirus D68</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-polio enterovirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polio</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">poliomyelitis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32905647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jpc.15140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization WHO/V&amp;B/03.01. WHO-recommended standards for surveillance of selected vaccine-preventable diseases. Poliomyelitis 2003; 2008: 31-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan F, Datta SD, Quddus A et al. Progress towards polio eradication worldwide, January 2016-March 2018. Wkly. Epidemiol. Rec. 2018; 93: 241-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson C, D'Souza RM, Kennett M. Australia declared polio free. Commun. Dis. Intell. 2002; 26: 253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO Press Release WHO/71 (29 October 2000). Major milestone reached in global polio eradication: Western Pacific Region is certified polio-free. Commun. Dis. Intell. 2000; 24(10):8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes E, Dlop O, Chavan J, Tangermann R, Wassilak S. Surveillance systems to tract progress towards polio eradication worldwide, 2015-2016. Wkly. Epidemiol. Rec. 2017; 92: 165-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Souza RM, Watson C, Kennett M. Australia's contribution to global polio eradication initiatives. Aust. NZ. J. Publ. Heal. 1999; 23: 289-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nathanson N, Kew OM. From emergence to eradication: The epidemiology of poliomyelitis deconstructed. Am. J. Epidemiol. 2010 2010; 172: 1213-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modlin JF. Poliovirus. In: Mandell GL, Bennett JE, Dolin R, eds. Mandell, Douglas, and Bennett's Principles and Practice of Infectious Diseases, 6th edn. Philadelphia, PA: Elsevier; 2005; 2141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabin AB. Pathogenesis of poliomyelitis; reappraisal in the light of new data. Science 1956; 123: 1151-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nathanson N, Martin JR. The epidemiology of poliomyelitis: Enigmas surrounding its appearance, epidemicity, and disappearance. Am. J. Epidemiol. 1979; 110: 672-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche P, Spencer J. Editorial: Polio eradication in Australia and the world. Commun. Dis. Intell. 2002; 26: 113-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salk JE, Krech U, Youngner JS, Bennett BL, Lewis LJ, Bazeley PL. Formaldehyde treatment and safety testing of experimental poliomyelitis vaccines. Am. J. Public Health Nations Health 1954; 44: 563-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabin AB. Present position of immunization against poliomyelitis with live virus vaccines. Br. Med. J. 1959; 1: 663-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Vaccine-Associated Paralytic Polio (VAPP) and Vaccine-Derived Poliovirus (VDPV), February 2015. WHO. Available from: https://www.who.int/immunization/diseases/poliomyelitis/endgame_objective2/oral_polio_vaccine/VAPPandcVDPVFactSheet-Feb2015.pdf [accessed 15 October 2019].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Polio Eradication Initiative website, World Health Organization. Polio This Week as of 23rd January 2020. WHO. Available from: http://polioeradication.org/polio-today/polio-now/this-week/ [accessed 20 January 2019].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Academy of Pediatrics Committee on Infectious Diseases. Prevention of poliomyelitis: Recommendations for use of only inactivated poliovirus vaccine for routine immunisations. Pediatrics 1999; 104: 1404-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts J, Brussen KA, Ibrahim A, Thorley B. Annual report of the Australia National Poliovirus Reference Laboratory, 2006. Commun. Dis. Intell. 2006; 31: 263-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nathanson N. Eradication of poliomyelitis in the United States. Rev. Infect. Dis. 1982; 4: 940-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochmann S. Polio. Published online at OurWorldInData.org. Our World in Data; 2017. Available from: https://ourworldindata.org/polio [accessed 16 July 2020].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tebbens R, Pallansch M, Cochi S et al. Economic analysis of the global polio eradication initiative. Vaccine 2010; 29: 334-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson B, Durrheim D. Review of Australia's Polio Surveillance. Commun. Dis. Intell. 2013; 37: 149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Polio Eradication Initiative website, World Health Organization. Two Out of Three Wild Poliovirus Strains Eradicated, October 24, 2019. WHO. Available from: http://polioeradication.org/news-post/two-out-of-three-wild-poliovirus-strains-eradicated/ [accessed 31 October 2019].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampton L, Farrell M, Ramirez-Gonzalez A et al. Cessation of use of trivalent oral polio vaccine and introduction of inactivated poliovirus vaccine worldwide, 2016. Wkly. Epidemiol. Rec. 2016; 91: 421-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorba J, Diop OM, Iber J et al. Update on vaccine-derived polioviruses - Worldwide, January 2017-June 2018. Morb. Mortal. Wkly. Rep. 2018; 67: 1189-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization Regional Office for the Western Pacific. Papua New Guinea Polio Outbreak Response, 2018. Manila: The Organization; 2019. Licence: CC BY-NC-SA 3.0 IGO.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts JA, Hobday LK, Ibrahim A, Aitken T, Thorley BR. Australian National Enterovirus Reference Laboratory annual report, 2014. Commun. Dis. Intell. 2017; 41: E161-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris A, Elliott E, D'Souza R, Antony J, Kennett M, Longbottom H. Acute flaccid paralysis in Australian children. J. Paediatr. Child Health 2003; 39: 22-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai S, Smith T, Thorley BR et al. Performance of acute flaccid paralysis surveillance compared with World Health Organization standards. J. Paediatr. Child Health 2015; 51: 209-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Lewthwaite P, Cardosa MJ, Solmon T. Clinical features, diagnosis, and management of enterovirus 71. Lancet Neurol. 2010; 9: 1097-105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teoh H-L, Mohammad SS, Britton PN et al. Clinical characteristics and functional motor outcomes of enterovirus 71 neurological disease in children. JAMA Neurol. 2016; 73: 300-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regional Office for the Western Pacific, World Health Organization. A Guide to clinical management and public health response for hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD). Manila: The Office; 2011. Available from: http://iris.wpro.who.int/handle/10665.1/5521 [accessed 10 June 2019].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zander A, Britton PN, Navin T, Horsley E, Tobin S, McAnulty JM. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 in metropolitan Sydney: Enhanced surveillance and lessons learnt. Med. J. Aust. 2014; 201: 663-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm-Hansen CC, Midgley SE, Fischer TK. Global emergence of enterovirus D68: A systematic review. Lancet Infect. Dis. 2016; 16: e64-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayscue P, Haren KV, Sheriff H et al. Acute flaccid paralysis with anterior myelitis - California, June 2012-June 2014. Morb. Mortal. Wkly. Rep. 2014; 63: 903-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messacar K, Schreiner TL, Van Haren K et al. Acute flaccid myelitis: A clinical eeview of US cases 2012-2015. Ann. Neurol. 2016; 80: 326-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messacar K, Asturias EJ, Hixon AM et al. Enterovirus D68 and acute flaccid myelitis - Evaluating the evidence for causality. Lancet Infect. Dis. 2018; 18: E239-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyda A, Stelzer-Braid S, Adam D, Chughtai AA, MacIntyre CR. The association between acute flaccid myelitis (AFM) and Enterovirus D68 (EV-D68) - What is the evidence for causation. Euro. Surveill. 2018; 23: 17-00310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centres for Disease Control and Prevention. Case Definitions for AFM. CDC. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/acute-flaccid-myelitis/hcp/case-definitions.html [accessed 27 August 2020].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The United Kingdom Acute Flaccid Paralysis (AFP) Task Force. An increase in reports of acute flaccid paralysis (AFP) in the United Kingdom, 1 January 2018-21 January 2019: Early findings. Euro. Surveill. 2019; 24: 1-6. https://doi.org/10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2019.24.6.1900093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helfferich J, Knoester M, Van Leer-Butr CC et al. Acute flaccid myelitis and enterovirus D68: Lessons from the past and present. Eur. J. Pediatr. 2019; 178: 1305-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts J, Hobday L, Ibrahim A, Aitken T, Thorley B. Annual report of the Australian National Enterovirus Reference Laboratory 2012. Commun. Dis. Intell Q. Rep. 2013; 37: E97-E104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen EW, Kornberg AJ, Freeman JL, Leventer RJ, Ryan MM. Acute flaccid myelitis in childhood: A retrospective cohort study. Eur. J. Neurol. 2017; 24: 1077-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins SE, Elrick MJ, Messacar K. Acute flaccid myelitis-keys to diagnosis, questions about treatment, and future directions. JAMA Pediatr. 2019; 172: 117-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Government of Canada. Information for Canadians Regarding Reports of Acute Flaccid Myelitis. Government of Canada. Available from: https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/diseases/acute-flaccid-myelitis.html [accessed 28 March 2019].</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>