<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32997323</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1995-820X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Virologica Sinica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Virol Sin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>From Monovalent to Multivalent Vaccines, the Exploration for Potential Preventive Strategies Against Hand, Foot, and Mouth Disease (HFMD).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>167</StartPage><EndPage>175</EndPage><MedlinePgn>167-175</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12250-020-00294-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) recently emerged as a global public threat. The licensure of inactivated enterovirus A71 (EV-A71) vaccine was the first step in using a vaccine to control HFMD. New challenges arise from changes in the pathogen spectrum while vaccines directed against other common serotypes are in the preclinical stage. The mission of a broad-spectrum prevention strategy clearly favors multivalent vaccines. The development of multivalent vaccines was attempted via the simple combination of potent monovalent vaccines or the construction of chimeric vaccines comprised of epitopes derived from different virus serotypes. The present review summarizes recent advances in HFMD vaccine development and discusses the next steps toward a safe and effective HFMD vaccine that is capable of establishing a cross-protective antibody response.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Xiangchuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center and Institutes of Biomedical Science, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, 201508, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Miaomiao</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center and Institutes of Biomedical Science, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, 201508, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center and Institutes of Biomedical Science, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, 201508, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Peiyong</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Longhua Hospital, Shanghai University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shanghai, 200032, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoyan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3193-1401</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center and Institutes of Biomedical Science, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, 201508, China. zhangxiaoyan@shphc.org.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Jianqing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0896-9273</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center and Institutes of Biomedical Science, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, 201508, China. xujianqing@shphc.org.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Virol Sin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101514185</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1995-820X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017778">Vaccines, Combined</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014765">Viral Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017778" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccines, Combined</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014765" MajorTopicYN="Y">Viral Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chimeric vaccines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, foot, and mouth disease&#xa0;(HFMD)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inactivated whole virus vaccine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multivalent vaccines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Virus-like particles</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32997323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7525078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12250-020-00294-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12250-020-00294-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Anasir MI, Poh CL. Advances in antigenic peptide-based vaccine and neutralizing antibodies against viruses causing hand, foot, and mouth disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20:1256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6471744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30871133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur Huang KY, Chen MF, Huang YC, Shih SR, Chiu CH, Lin JJ, Wang JR, Tsao KC, Lin TY. Epitope-associated and specificity-focused features of EV71-neutralizing antibody repertoires from plasmablasts of infected children. Nat Commun. 2017;8:762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5624920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28970483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aw-Yong KL, NikNadia NMN, Tan CW, Sam IC, Chan YF. Immune responses against enterovirus A71 infection: implications for vaccine success. Rev Med Virol. 2019;29:e2073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31369184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian L, Gao F, Mao Q, Sun S, Wu X, Liu S, Yang X, Liang Z. Hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with coxsackievirus A10: more serious than it seems. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2019;17:233&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30793637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Y, Ku Z, Liu Q, Leng Q, Huang Z. A combination vaccine comprising of inactivated enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 elicits balanced protective immunity against both viruses. Vaccine. 2014;32:2406&#x2013;2412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24657161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caine EA, Fuchs J, Das SC, Partidos CD, Osorio JE. Efficacy of a trivalent hand, foot, and mouth disease vaccine against enterovirus 71 and coxsackieviruses A16 and A6 in mice. Viruses. 2015;7:5919&#x2013;5932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4664989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26593938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao RY, Dong DY, Liu RJ, Han JF, Wang GC, Zhao H, Li XF, Deng YQ, Zhu SY, Wang XY, Lin F, Zhang FJ, Chen W, Qin ED, Qin CF. Human IgG Subclasses against Enterovirus Type 71: neutralization versus Antibody Dependent Enhancement of Infection. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e64024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3659118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23700449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Zhang C, Zhou Y, Zhang X, Shen C, Ye X, Jiang W, Huang Z, Cong Y. A 3.0-angstrom resolution cryo-electron microscopy structure and antigenic sites of coxsackievirus A6-like particles. J Virol. 2018;92:e01257-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5752931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29093091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Xia Y, Zhu S, Xu F, Sun Y, Lu H, Gao M, Yang Z, Mao Z, Ge Q. Muscle destruction caused by coxsackievirus A10 in gerbils: construction of a novel animal model for antiviral evaluation. Virus Res. 2020;286:198067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32553610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung CY, Chen CY, Lin SY, Chung YC, Chiu HY, Chi WK, Lin YL, Chiang BL, Chen WJ, Hu YC. Enterovirus 71 virus-like particle vaccine: improved production conditions for enhanced yield. Vaccine. 2010;28:6951&#x2013;6957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20797455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai W, Xiong P, Zhang X, Liu Z, Chen J, Zhou Y, Ye X, Zhang C. Recombinant virus-like particle presenting a newly identified coxsackievirus A10 neutralization epitope induces protective immunity in mice. Antiviral Res. 2019;164:139&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30817941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan S, Liao Y, Jiang G, Jiang L, Wang L, Xu X, Feng M, Yang E, Zhang Y, Cui W, Li Q. Study of integrated protective immunity induced in rhesus macaques by the intradermal administration of a bivalent EV71-CA16 inactivated vaccine. Vaccine. 2020;38:2034&#x2013;2044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31982260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang CY, Liu CC. Recent development of enterovirus A vaccine candidates for the prevention of hand, foot, and mouth disease. Expert Rev Vaccines. 2018;17:819&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30095317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo DGW, Alonso S, Phoon MC, Ramachandran N, Chow VTK, Poh CL. Identification of neutralizing linear epitopes from the VP1 capsid protein of Enterovirus 71 using synthetic peptides. Virus Res. 2007;125:61&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17222936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujii K, Nagata N, Sato Y, Ong KC, Wong KT, Yamayoshi S, Shimanuki M, Shitara H, Taya C, Koike S. Transgenic mouse model for the study of enterovirus 71 neuropathogenesis. PNAS. 2013;110:14753&#x2013;14758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3767555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23959904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan X, Che Y, Wei S, Li S, Zhao Z, Tong Y, Wang L, Gong W, Zhang Y, Zhao Y. Effectiveness and safety of an inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in children aged 6&#x2013;71&#xa0;months in a phase IV study. Clin Infect Dis. 2019 doi: 10.1093/cid/ciz1114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciz1114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31734699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang LM, Chiu CH, Chiu NC, Lin CY, Li MT, Kuo TY, Weng YJ, Hsieh EF, Tai IC. Immunogenicity, safety, cross-reaction, and immune persistence of an inactivated enterovirus A71 vaccine in children aged from two months to 11&#xa0;years in Taiwan. Vaccine. 2019;37:1827&#x2013;1835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30803843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo C, Yang J, Lei L, Qiao L, Xin J, Pan Z. Hepatitis B virus core particles containing multiple epitopes confer protection against enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 infection in mice. Vaccine. 2017;35:7322&#x2013;7330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29129453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia Q, Ng Q, Chin W, Meng T, Chow VTK, Wang C-I, Kwang J, He F. Effective in vivo therapeutic IgG antibody against VP3 of enterovirus 71 with receptor-competing activity. Sci Rep. 2017;7:46402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5395816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28422137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L, Fan R, Sun S, Fan P, Su W, Zhou Y, Gao F, Xu F, Kong W, Jiang C. A new EV71 VP3 epitope in norovirus P particle vector displays neutralizing activity and protection in vivo in mice. Vaccine. 2015;33:6596&#x2013;6603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26529072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiener TK, Jia Q, Meng T, Chow VTK, Kwang J. A novel universal neutralizing monoclonal antibody against enterovirus 71 that targets the highly conserved &#x201c;knob&#x201d; region of VP3 protein. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2014;8:e2895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4038473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24875055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ku Z, Liu Q, Ye X, Cai Y, Wang X, Shi J, Li D, Jin X, An W, Huang Z. A virus-like particle based bivalent vaccine confers dual protection against enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 infections in mice. Vaccine. 2014;32:4296&#x2013;4303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24950363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H, Cifuente JO, Ashley RE, Conway JF, Makhov AM, Tano Y, Shimizu H, Nishimura Y, Hafenstein S. A strain-specific epitope of enterovirus 71 identified by cryo-electron microscopy of the complex with fab from neutralizing antibody. J Virol. 2013;87:11363&#x2013;11370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3807339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23946455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li HY, Han JF, Qin CF, Chen R. Virus-like particles for enterovirus 71 produced from Saccharomyces cerevisiae potently elicits protective immune responses in mice. Vaccine. 2013;31:3281&#x2013;3287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23726823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Chang J, Liu X, Yang J, Guo H, Wei W, Zhang W, Yu XF. Protection from lethal challenge in a neonatal mouse model by circulating recombinant form coxsackievirus A16 vaccine candidates. J Gen Virol. 2014;95:1083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3983757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24496826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Liu L, Mo Z, Wang X, Xia J, Liang Z, Zhang Y, Li Y, Mao Q, Wang J, Jiang L, Dong C, Che Y, Huang T, Jiang Z, Xie Z, Wang L, Liao Y, Liang Y, Nong Y, Liu J, Zhao H, Na R, Guo L, Pu J, Yang E, Sun L, Cui P, Shi H, Wang J, Li Q. An inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy children. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:829&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JX, Song YF, Wang L, Zhang XF, Hu YS, Hu YM, Xia JL, Li J, Zhu FC. Two-year efficacy and immunogenicity of Sinovac Enterovirus 71 vaccine against hand, foot and mouth disease in children. Expert Rev Vaccines. 2016;15:129&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26460695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim HX, Poh CL. Insights into innate and adaptive immune responses in vaccine development against EV-A71. Ther Adv Vaccines Immunother. 2019;7:2515135519888998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6873268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31799495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim H, In HJ, Lee JA, Sik Yoo J, Lee SW, Chung GT, Choi YK, Chung JK, Cho SJ, Lee JW. The immunogenicity and protection effect of an inactivated coxsackievirus A6, A10, and A16 vaccine against hand, foot, and mouth disease. Vaccine. 2018;36:3445&#x2013;3452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29739716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin JY, Kung YA, Shih SR. Antivirals and vaccines for Enterovirus A71. J Biomed Sci. 2019;26:65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6720414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31481071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Chou AH, Lien SP, Lin HY, Liu SJ, Chang JY, Guo MS, Chow YH, Yang WS, Chang KHW, Sia C, Chong P. Identification and characterization of a cross-neutralization epitope of Enterovirus 71. Vaccine. 2011;29:4362&#x2013;4372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21501643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Zhao H, Zhang Y, Wang J, Che Y, Dong C, Zhang X, Na R, Shi H, Jiang L. Neonatal rhesus monkey is a potential animal model for studying pathogenesis of EV71 infection. Virology. 2011;412:91&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21262515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Q, Wang Y, Bian L, Xu M, Liang Z. EV-A71 vaccine licensure: a first step for multivalent enterovirus vaccine to control HFMD and other severe diseases. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2016;5:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5141264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27436364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plevka P, Lim P-Y, Perera R, Cardosa J, Suksatu A, Kuhn RJ, Rossmann MG. Neutralizing antibodies can initiate genome release from human enterovirus 71. PNAS. 2014;111:2134&#x2013;2139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3926013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24469789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premanand B, Kiener TK, Meng T, Tan YR, Jia Q, Chow VT, Kwang J. Induction of protective immune responses against EV71 in mice by baculovirus encoding a novel expression cassette for capsid protein VP1. Antiviral Res. 2012;95:311&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22691220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi An W, Guo SuZ, Wen Pan R, Ping Yang B, Chao Zhang Y, Shi L, Li Q. The immunogenicity and protection effect of the BPL-inactivated CA16 vaccine in different animal systems. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2014;10:628&#x2013;639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4130287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24401488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somasundaram B, Chang C, Fan YY, Lim PY, Cardosa J, Lua L. Characterizing Enterovirus 71 and Coxsackievirus A16 virus-like particles production in insect cells. Methods. 2016;95:38&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26410190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y, Zhang Y, Ji T, Gu X, Yang Q, Zhu S, Xu W, Xu Y, Shi Y, Huang X, Li Q, Deng H, Wang X, Yan D, Yu W, Wang S, Yu D, Xu W. Persistent circulation of Coxsackievirus A6 of genotype D3 in mainland of China between 2008 and 2015. Sci Rep. 2017;7:5491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5511160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28710474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun YS, Li YJ, Xia Y, Xu F, Wang WW, Yang ZN, Lu HJ, Chen ZP, Miao ZP, Liang WF, Xu ZY, Dong HJ, Qiu DH, Zhu ZY, van der Veen S, Qian J, Zhou B, Yao PP, Zhu HP. Coxsackievirus A16 induced neurological disorders in young gerbils which could serve as a new animal model for vaccine evaluation. Sci Rep. 2016;6:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5035925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27667023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsou YL, Lin YW, Shao HY, Yu SL, Wu SR, Lin HY, Liu CC, Huang C, Chong P, Chow YH. Recombinant adeno-vaccine expressing enterovirus 71-like particles against hand, foot, and mouth disease. PLoS NTD. 2015;9:e0003692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4391779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25855976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YF, Yu CK. Animal models of enterovirus 71 infection: applications and limitations. J Biomed Sci. 2014;21:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4013435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24742252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang KT, Lin SJ, Wang HC, Chen PC, Lin JJ, Chiang JR, Chang CL, Shih DY, Lo CF, Wang DY. Establishment of an animal challenge model as a potency assay for an inactivated Enterovirus Type 71 vaccine. Biologicals. 2016;44:183&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27068365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Zhang Y, Zhang X, Hu Y, Dong C, Liu L, Yang E, Che Y, Pu J, Wang X. Pathologic and immunologic characteristics of coxsackievirus A16 infection in rhesus macaques. Virology. 2017;500:198&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27829175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Teng Z, Cui X, Li C, Pan H, Zheng Y, Mao S, Yang Y, Wu L, Guo X, Zhang X, Zhu Y. Epidemiological and serological surveillance of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Shanghai, China, 2012&#x2013;2016. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2018;7:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5837173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29362406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Ku Z, Zhang X, Ye X, Chen J, Liu Q, Zhang W, Zhang C, Fu Z, Jin X, Cong Y, Huang Z. Structure, immunogenicity, and protective mechanism of an Engineered Enterovirus 71-like particle vaccine mimicking 80S empty capsid. J Virol. 2018;92:e01330&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5730765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29070691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, He D, Yang L, Li Z, Ye X, Yu H, Zhao H, Li S, Yuan L, Qian H, Que Y, Shih JW, Zhu H, Li Y, Cheng T, Xia N. A broadly cross-protective vaccine presenting the neighboring epitopes within the VP1 GH loop and VP2 EF loop of enterovirus 71. Sci Rep. 2015;5:12973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4525384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26243660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Q, Wu L, Chen L, Qin Y, Pan Z, Chen M. Vesicular stomatitis virus-based vaccines expressing EV71 virus-like particles elicit strong immune responses and protect newborn mice from lethal challenges. Vaccine. 2016;34:4196&#x2013;4204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27373596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B, Chuang H, Yang KD. Sialylated glycans as receptor and inhibitor of enterovirus 71 infection to DLD-1 intestinal cells. Virol J. 2009;6:141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2751754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19751532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Liu Y, Li S, Zhao H, Lin Q, Yu H, Huang X, Zheng Q, Cheng T, Xia N. A novel inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine can elicit cross-protective immunity against coxsackievirus A16 in mice. Vaccine. 2016;34:5938&#x2013;5945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27771182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Gao F, Wang X, Shi L, Zhou Z, Jiang Y, Ma X, Zhang C, Zhou C, Zeng X, Liu G, Fan J, Mao Q, Shi L. Development and characterization of an enterovirus 71 (EV71) virus-like particles (VLPs) vaccine produced in Pichia pastoris. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2019 doi: 10.1080/21645515.2019.1649554:1-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21645515.2019.1649554:1-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7482752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31403352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao PP, Miao ZP, Xu F, Lu HJ, Sun YS, Xia Y, Chen C, Yang ZN, Xia SC, Jm Jiang. An adult gerbil model for evaluating potential coxsackievirus A16 vaccine candidates. Vaccine. 2019;37:5341&#x2013;5349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31351798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yee PTI, Poh CL. T Cell immunity to enterovirus 71 infection in humans and implications for vaccine development. Int J Med Sci. 2018;15:1143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6097258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30123051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi EJ, Shin YJ, Kim JH, Kim TG, Chang SY. Enterovirus 71 infection and vaccines. Clin Exp Vaccine Res. 2017;6:4&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5292356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28168168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu CK, Chen CC, Chen CL, Wang JR, Liu CC, Yan JJ, Su IJ. Neutralizing antibody provided protection against enterovirus type 71 lethal challenge in neonatal mice. J Biomed Sci. 2000;7:523&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11060501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Yang Y, Chi Y, Yin J, Yan L, Ku Z, Liu Q, Huang Z, Zhou D. Hexon-modified recombinant E1-deleted adenoviral vectors as bivalent vaccine carriers for Coxsackievirus A16 and Enterovirus 71. Vaccine. 2015;33:5087&#x2013;5094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26296491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Liu Q, Ku Z, Hu Y, Ye X, Zhang Y, Huang Z. Coxsackievirus A16-like particles produced in Pichia pastoris elicit high-titer neutralizing antibodies and confer protection against lethal viral challenge in mice. Antiviral Res. 2016;129:47&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26902108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Dong Z, Li J, Carr MJ, Zhuang D, Wang J, Zhang Y, Ding S, Tong Y, Li D. Protective efficacies of formaldehyde-inactivated whole-virus vaccine and antivirals in a murine model of coxsackievirus A10 infection. J Virol. 2017;91:e00333-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5469256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28424287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Dong Z, Wei Q, Carr MJ, Li J, Ding S, Tong Y, Li D, Shi W. A neonatal murine model of coxsackievirus A6 infection for evaluation of antiviral and vaccine efficacy. J Virol. 2017;91:e02450&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5391469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28250116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Dai W, Zhang C, Zhou Y, Xiong P, Wang S, Ye X, Liu Q, Zhou D, Huang Z. A virus-like particle-based tetravalent vaccine for hand, foot, and mouth disease elicits broad and balanced protective immunity. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2018;7:94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5959873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29777102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Dong Z, Wang Q, Carr MJ, Li J, Liu T, Li D, Shi W. Characterization of an inactivated whole-virus bivalent vaccine that induces balanced protective immunity against coxsackievirus A6 and A10 in mice. Vaccine. 2018;36:7095&#x2013;7104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30316529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Li HY, Han JF, Deng YQ, Li YX, Zhu SY, He YL, Qin ED, Chen R, Qin CF. Virus-like particles produced in Saccharomyces cerevisiae elicit protective immunity against Coxsackievirus A16 in mice. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol. 2013;97:10445&#x2013;10452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24085395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Li HY, Han JF, Deng YQ, Zhu SY, Li XF, Yang HQ, Li YX, Zhang Y, Qin ED, Chen R, Qin CF. Novel recombinant chimeric virus-like particle is immunogenic and protective against both enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 in mice. Sci Rep. 2015;5:7878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4297979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25597595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Shen C, Zhang C, Zhang W, Wang L, Lan K, Liu Q, Huang Z. Yeast-produced recombinant virus-like particles of coxsackievirus A6 elicited protective antibodies in mice. Antiviral Res. 2016;132:165&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27315772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Zhang C, Liu Q, Gong S, Geng L, Huang Z. A virus-like particle vaccine protects mice against coxsackievirus A10 lethal infection. Antiviral Res. 2018;152:124&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29470994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>