<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32995786</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2692-8205</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>bioRxiv : the preprint server for biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>bioRxiv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ebselen, disulfiram, carmofur, PX-12, tideglusib, and shikonin are non-specific promiscuous SARS-CoV-2 main protease inhibitors.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2020.09.15.299164</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1101/2020.09.15.299164</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>There is an urgent need for vaccines and antiviral drugs to combat the COVID-19 pandemic. Encouraging progress has been made in developing antivirals targeting SARS-CoV-2, the etiological agent of COVID-19. Among the drug targets being investigated, the viral main protease (M <sup>pro</sup> ) is one of the most extensively studied drug targets. M <sup>pro</sup> is a cysteine protease that hydrolyzes the viral polyprotein at more than 11 sites and it is highly conserved among coronaviruses. In addition, M <sup>pro</sup> has a unique substrate preference for glutamine in the P1 position. Taken together, it appears that M <sup>pro</sup> inhibitors can achieve both broad-spectrum antiviral activity and a high selectivity index. Structurally diverse compounds have been reported as M <sup>pro</sup> inhibitors, with several of which also showed antiviral activity in cell culture. In this study, we investigated the mechanism of action of six previously reported M <sup>pro</sup> inhibitors, ebselen, disulfiram, tideglusib, carmofur, shikonin, and PX-12 using a consortium of techniques including FRET-based enzymatic assay, thermal shift assay, native mass spectrometry, cellular antiviral assays, and molecular dynamics simulations. Collectively, the results showed that the inhibition of M <sup>pro</sup> by these six compounds is non-specific and the inhibition is abolished or greatly reduced with the addition of reducing reagent DTT. In the absence of DTT, these six compounds not only inhibit M <sup>pro</sup> , but also a panel of viral cysteine proteases including SARS-CoV-2 papain-like protease, the 2A <sup>pro</sup> and 3C <sup>pro</sup> from enterovirus A71 (EV-A71) and EV-D68. However, none of the compounds inhibits the viral replication of EV-A71 or EV-D68, suggesting that the enzymatic inhibition potency IC <sub>50</sub> values obtained in the absence of DTT cannot be used to faithfully predict their cellular antiviral activity. Overall, we provide compelling evidence suggesting that ebselen, disulfiram, tideglusib, carmofur, shikonin, and PX-12 are non-specific SARS-CoV-2 M <sup>pro</sup> inhibitors, and urge the scientific community to be stringent with hit validation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Chunlong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, College of Pharmacy, The University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona 85721, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yanmei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, College of Pharmacy, The University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona 85721, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Townsend</LastName><ForeName>Julia Alma</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry, The University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona 85721, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lagarias</LastName><ForeName>Panagiotis I</ForeName><Initials>PI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, Faculty of Pharmacy, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marty</LastName><ForeName>Michael Thomas</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry, The University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona 85721, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kolocouris</LastName><ForeName>Antonios</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, Faculty of Pharmacy, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4845-4621</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, College of Pharmacy, The University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona 85721, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AI147325</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R35 GM128624</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>T32 GM008804</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>bioRxiv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101680187</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2692-8205</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateIn"><RefSource>ACS Pharmacol Transl Sci. 2020 Oct 09;3(6):1265-1277. doi: 10.1021/acsptsci.0c00130</RefSource><PMID Version="1">33330841</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32995786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.09.15.299164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2020.09.15.299164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhou P.; Yang X.-L.; Wang X.-G.; Hu B.; Zhang L.; Zhang W.; Si H.-R.; Zhu Y.; Li B.; Huang C.-L.; Chen H.-D.; Chen J.; Luo Y.; Guo H.; Jiang R.-D.; Liu M.-Q.; Chen Y.; Shen X.-R.; Wang X.; Zheng X.-S.; Zhao K.; Chen Q.-J.; Deng F.; Liu L.-L.; Yan B.; Zhan F.-X.; Wang Y.-Y.; Xiao G.-F.; Shi Z.-L., A pneumonia outbreak associated with a new coronavirus of probable bat origin. Nature 2020, 579 (7798), 270&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen K. G.; Rambaut A.; Lipkin W. I.; Holmes E. C.; Garry R. F., The proximal origin of SARS-CoV-2. Nat Med 2020, 26 (4), 450&#x2013;452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32284615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funk C. D.; Laferriere C.; Ardakani A., A Snapshot of the Global Race for Vaccines Targeting SARS-CoV-2 and the COVID-19 Pandemic. Front Pharmacol 2020, 11, 937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7317023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32636754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C.; Zhou Q.; Li Y.; Garner L. V.; Watkins S. P.; Carter L. J.; Smoot J.; Gregg A. C.; Daniels A. D.; Jervey S.; Albaiu D., Research and Development on Therapeutic Agents and Vaccines for COVID-19 and Related Human Coronavirus Diseases. ACS Cent Sci 2020, 6 (3), 315&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10467574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32226821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang J.; Wan Y.; Luo C.; Ye G.; Geng Q.; Auerbach A.; Li F., Cell entry mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2020, 117 (21), 11727&#x2013;11734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7260975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32376634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M.; Kleine-Weber H.; Schroeder S.; Kruger N.; Herrler T.; Erichsen S.; Schiergens T. S.; Herrler G.; Wu N. H.; Nitsche A.; Muller M. A.; Drosten C.; Pohlmann S., SARS-CoV-2 Cell Entry Depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and Is Blocked by a Clinically Proven Protease Inhibitor. Cell 2020, 181 (2), 271&#x2013;280 e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T.; Luo S.; Libby P.; Shi G. P., Cathepsin L-selective inhibitors: A potentially promising treatment for COVID-19 patients. Pharmacol Ther 2020, 107587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7255230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32470470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheahan T. P.; Sims A. C.; Graham R. L.; Menachery V. D.; Gralinski L. E.; Case J. B.; Leist S. R.; Pyrc K.; Feng J. Y.; Trantcheva I.; Bannister R.; Park Y.; Babusis D.; Clarke M. O.; Mackman R. L.; Spahn J. E.; Palmiotti C. A.; Siegel D.; Ray A. S.; Cihlar T.; Jordan R.; Denison M. R.; Baric R. S., Broad-spectrum antiviral GS-5734 inhibits both epidemic and zoonotic coronaviruses. Sci Transl Med 2017, 9 (396).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5567817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28659436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheahan T. P.; Sims A. C.; Zhou S.; Graham R. L.; Pruijssers A. J.; Agostini M. L.; Leist S. R.; Schafer A.; Dinnon K. H. 3rd; Stevens L. J.; Chappell J. D.; Lu X.; Hughes T. M.; George A. S.; Hill C. S.; Montgomery S. A.; Brown A. J.; Bluemling G. R.; Natchus M. G.; Saindane M.; Kolykhalov A. A.; Painter G.; Harcourt J.; Tamin A.; Thornburg N. J.; Swanstrom R.; Denison M. R.; Baric R. S., An orally bioavailable broad-spectrum antiviral inhibits SARS-CoV-2 in human airway epithelial cell cultures and multiple coronaviruses in mice. Sci Transl Med 2020, 12 (541).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7164393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32253226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rut W.; Groborz K.; Zhang L.; Sun X.; Zmudzinski M.; Hilgenfeld R.; Drag M., Substrate specificity profiling of SARS-CoV-2 Mpro protease provides basis for anti-COVID-19 drug design. bioRxiv 2020, 2020.03.07.981928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma C.; Sacco M. D.; Hurst B.; Townsend J. A.; Hu Y.; Szeto T.; Zhang X.; Tarbet B.; Marty M. T.; Chen Y.; Wang J., Boceprevir, GC-376, and calpain inhibitors II, XII inhibit SARS-CoV-2 viral replication by targeting the viral main protease. Cell Res 2020, 30 (8), 678&#x2013;692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7294525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32541865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Z.; Du X.; Xu Y.; Deng Y.; Liu M.; Zhao Y.; Zhang B.; Li X.; Zhang L.; Peng C.; Duan Y.; Yu J.; Wang L.; Yang K.; Liu F.; Jiang R.; Yang X.; You T.; Liu X.; Yang X.; Bai F.; Liu H.; Liu X.; Guddat L. W.; Xu W.; Xiao G.; Qin C.; Shi Z.; Jiang H.; Rao Z.; Yang H., Structure of M(pro) from COVID-19 virus and discovery of its inhibitors. Nature 2020, 582, 289&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32272481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai W.; Zhang B.; Su H.; Li J.; Zhao Y.; Xie X.; Jin Z.; Liu F.; Li C.; Li Y.; Bai F.; Wang H.; Cheng X.; Cen X.; Hu S.; Yang X.; Wang J.; Liu X.; Xiao G.; Jiang H.; Rao Z.; Zhang L. K.; Xu Y.; Yang H.; Liu H., Structure-based design of antiviral drug candidates targeting the SARS-CoV-2 main protease. Science 2020, 369 (6497), 1331&#x2013;1335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7179937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32321856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L.; Lin D.; Sun X.; Curth U.; Drosten C.; Sauerhering L.; Becker S.; Rox K.; Hilgenfeld R., Crystal structure of SARS-CoV-2 main protease provides a basis for design of improved alpha-ketoamide inhibitors. Science 2020, 368 (6489), 409&#x2013;412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7164518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32198291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thenin-Houssier S.; de Vera I. M.; Pedro-Rosa L.; Brady A.; Richard A.; Konnick B.; Opp S.; Buffone C.; Fuhrmann J.; Kota S.; Billack B.; Pietka-Ottlik M.; Tellinghuisen T.; Choe H.; Spicer T.; Scampavia L.; Diaz-Griffero F.; Kojetin D. J.; Valente S. T., Ebselen, a Small-Molecule Capsid Inhibitor of HIV-1 Replication. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2016, 60 (4), 2195&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4808204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26810656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Munnik M.; Lohans C. T.; Lang P. A.; Langley G. W.; Malla T. R.; Tumber A.; Schofield C. J.; Brem J., Targeting the Mycobacterium tuberculosis transpeptidase LdtMt2 with cysteine-reactive inhibitors including ebselen. Chem Commun 2019, 55 (69), 10214&#x2013;10217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6984337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31380528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azad G. K.; Singh V.; Mandal P.; Singh P.; Golla U.; Baranwal S.; Chauhan S.; Tomar R. S., Ebselen induces reactive oxygen species (ROS)-mediated cytotoxicity in Saccharomyces cerevisiae with inhibition of glutamate dehydrogenase being a target. FEBS Open Bio 2014, 4 (1), 77&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3907691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24490132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender K. O.; Garland M.; Ferreyra J. A.; Hryckowian A. J.; Child M. A.; Puri A. W.; Solow-Cordero D. E.; Higginbottom S. K.; Segal E.; Banaei N.; Shen A.; Sonnenburg J. L.; Bogyo M., A small-molecule antivirulence agent for treating Clostridium difficile infection. Sci Transl Med 2015, 7 (306), 306ra148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6025901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26400909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goins C. M.; Dajnowicz S.; Thanna S.; Sucheck S. J.; Parks J. M.; Ronning D. R., Exploring Covalent Allosteric Inhibition of Antigen 85C from Mycobacterium tuberculosis by Ebselen Derivatives. ACS Infect Dis 2017, 3 (5), 378&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6126352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28285521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee S.; Weiner W. S.; Schroeder C. E.; Simpson D. S.; Hanson A. M.; Sweeney N. L.; Marvin R. K.; Ndjomou J.; Kolli R.; Isailovic D.; Schoenen F. J.; Frick D. N., Ebselen inhibits hepatitis C virus NS3 helicase binding to nucleic acid and prevents viral replication. ACS Chem Biol 2014, 9 (10), 2393&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4201343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25126694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leroux F.; Bosc D.; Beghyn T.; Hermant P.; Warenghem S.; Landry V.; Pottiez V.; Guillaume V.; Charton J.; Herledan A.; Urata S.; Liang W. G.; Sheng L.; Tang W. J.; Deprez B.; Deprez-Poulain R., Identification of ebselen as a potent inhibitor of insulin degrading enzyme by a drug repurposing screening. Eur J Med Chem 2019, 179, 557&#x2013;566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6718346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31276900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zmudzinski M.; Rut W.; Olech K.; Granda J.; Giurg M.; Burda-Grabowska M.; Zhang L.; Sun X.; Lv Z.; Nayak D.; Kesik-Brodacka M.; Olsen S.; Hilgenfeld R.; Drag M., Ebselen derivatives are very potent dual inhibitors of SARS-CoV-2 proteases - PLpro and Mpro in in vitro studies. bioRxiv 2020, 2020.08.30.273979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paranjpe A.; Zhang R.; Ali-Osman F.; Bobustuc G. C.; Srivenugopal K. S., Disulfiram is a direct and potent inhibitor of human O 6 -methylguanine-DNA methyltransferase (MGMT) in brain tumor cells and mouse brain and markedly increases the alkylating DNA damage. Carcinogenesis 2013, 35 (3), 692&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3941740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24193513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Sanchez A. G.; Alvarez-Parrilla E.; Martinez-Martinez A.; Aguirre-Reyes L.; Orozpe-Olvera J. A.; Ramos-Soto M. A.; Nunez-Gastelum J. A.; Alvarado-Tenorio B.; de la Rosa L. A., Inhibition of Urease by Disulfiram, an FDA-Approved Thiol Reagent Used in Humans. Molecules 2016, 21 (12).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6274061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27898047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galkin A.; Kulakova L.; Lim K.; Chen C. Z.; Zheng W.; Turko I. V.; Herzberg O., Structural basis for inactivation of Giardia lamblia carbamate kinase by disulfiram. J Biol Chem 2014, 289 (15), 10502&#x2013;10509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24558036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin M.-H.; Moses D. C.; Hsieh C.-H.; Cheng S.-C.; Chen Y.-H.; Sun C.-Y.; Chou C.-Y., Disulfiram can inhibit MERS and SARS coronavirus papain-like proteases via different modes. Antiviral Res 2018, 150, 155&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7113793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29289665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dementiev A.; Joachimiak A.; Nguyen H.; Gorelik A.; Illes K.; Shabani S.; Gelsomino M.; Ahn E. Y. E.; Nagar B.; Doan N., Molecular Mechanism of Inhibition of Acid Ceramidase by Carmofur. J Med Chem 2019, 62 (2), 987&#x2013;992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6863082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30525581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huber K.; Patel P.; Zhang L.; Evans H.; Westwell A. D.; Fischer P. M.; Chan S.; Martin S., 2-[(1-methylpropyl)dithio]-1H-imidazole inhibits tubulin polymerization through cysteine oxidation. Mol Cancer Ther 2008, 7 (1), 143&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18202017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xed;nguez J. M.; Fuertes A.; Orozco L.; del Monte-Mill&#xe1;n M.; Delgado E.; Medina M., Evidence for Irreversible Inhibition of Glycogen Synthase Kinase-3 by Tideglusib. J Biol Chem 2012, 287 (2), 893&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3256883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22102280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Z.; Zhao Y.; Sun Y.; Zhang B.; Wang H.; Wu Y.; Zhu Y.; Zhu C.; Hu T.; Du X.; Duan Y.; Yu J.; Yang X.; Yang X.; Yang K.; Liu X.; Guddat L. W.; Xiao G.; Zhang L.; Yang H.; Rao Z., Structural basis for the inhibition of SARS-CoV-2 main protease by antineoplastic drug carmofur. Nat Struct Mol Biol 2020, 27 (6), 529&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32382072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas B. T.; Durie I. A.; Murray J.; Longo J. E.; Miller H. C.; Crich D.; Hogan R. J.; Tripp R. A.; Pegan S. D., Characterization and Noncovalent Inhibition of the Deubiquitinase and deISGylase Activity of SARS-CoV-2 Papain-Like Protease. ACS Infect Dis 2020, 6 (8), 2099&#x2013;2109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32428392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma C.; Hu Y.; Zhang J.; Musharrafieh R.; Wang J., A Novel Capsid Binding Inhibitor Displays Potent Antiviral Activity against Enterovirus D68. ACS Infect Dis 2019, 5 (11), 1952&#x2013;1962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7167248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31532189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musharrafieh R.; Ma C.; Zhang J.; Hu Y.; Diesing J. M.; Marty M. T.; Wang J., Validating Enterovirus D68&#x2013;2A(pro) as an Antiviral Drug Target and the Discovery of Telaprevir as a Potent D68&#x2013;2A(pro) Inhibitor. J Virol 2019, 93 (7), e02221&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6430540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30674624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma C.; Hu Y.; Zhang J.; Wang J., Pharmacological Characterization of the Mechanism of Action of R523062, a Promising Antiviral for Enterovirus D68. ACS Infect Dis 2020, 6 (8), 2260&#x2013;2270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8057299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32692536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Q. A.; Kato-Weinstein J.; Li Y.; Deng Y.; Granet R.; Garner L.; Liu C.; Polshakov D.; Gessner C.; Watkins S., Potential Therapeutic Agents and Associated Bioassay Data for COVID-19 and Related Human Coronavirus Infections. ACS Pharmacol Transl Sci 2020, asap.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7447080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33062950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen N. C.; Kim Y.; Liu H.; Galasiti Kankanamalage A. C.; Eckstrand C.; Groutas W. C.; Bannasch M.; Meadows J. M.; Chang K. O., Efficacy of a 3C-like protease inhibitor in treating various forms of acquired feline infectious peritonitis. J Feline Med Surg 2018, 20 (4), 378&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5871025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28901812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y.; Liu H.; Galasiti Kankanamalage A. C.; Weerasekara S.; Hua D. H.; Groutas W. C.; Chang K. O.; Pedersen N. C., Reversal of the Progression of Fatal Coronavirus Infection in Cats by a Broad-Spectrum Coronavirus Protease Inhibitor. PLoS Pathog 2016, 12 (3), e1005531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4814111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27027316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan C. W.; Tee H. K.; Lee M. H.; Sam I. C.; Chan Y. F., Enterovirus A71 DNA-Launched Infectious Clone as a Robust Reverse Genetic Tool. PLoS One 2016, 11 (9), e0162771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5019408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27617744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marty M. T.; Baldwin A. J.; Marklund E. G.; Hochberg G. K.; Benesch J. L.; Robinson C. V., Bayesian deconvolution of mass and ion mobility spectra: from binary interactions to polydisperse ensembles. Anal Chem 2015, 87 (8), 4370&#x2013;4376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4594776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25799115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>