<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34219290</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1399-3038</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pediatric allergy and immunology : official publication of the European Society of Pediatric Allergy and Immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Allergy Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association of different enteroviruses with atopy and allergic diseases in early childhood.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1629</StartPage><EndPage>1636</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1629-1636</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/pai.13577</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Enterovirus (EV) infections, being among the most prevalent viruses worldwide, have been associated with reduced risk of allergic diseases. We sought to determine the association between EVs and allergic sensitization and disease in early childhood.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The study was carried out in a nested case-control setting within a prospective birth cohort in Finland. We included 138 case children who had specific IgE (s-IgE) sensitization at the age of 5&#xa0;years and 138 control children without s-IgE sensitization. Allergic disease was recorded at study visits and identified with the ISAAC questionnaire. We screened for the presence of serotype-specific antibodies against 41 EVs at 1-5&#xa0;years of age and assessed their association with allergic sensitization and disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The overall number of EV infections did not differ between s-IgE-sensitized children and non-sensitized control children. However, there was a tendency of case children with an allergic disease having less EV infections than their controls. This observation was statistically significant for species A EVs in case children with atopic dermatitis vs. control children: OR 0.6 (95% CI 0.36-0.99), p&#xa0;=&#xa0;.048.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This study supports the evidence that EV exposure and development of allergic disease are inversely associated. Interestingly, the inverse association was not observed for bare atopic IgE sensitization, but for IgE sensitization coupled with clinical atopic disease. This suggests that environmental factors influencing IgE sensitization may differ from those influencing progression to clinical allergic disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. Pediatric Allergy and Immunology published by European Academy of Allergy and Clinical Immunology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palmu</LastName><ForeName>Tiina</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7191-7938</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology, Faculty of Medicine and Health Technology, Tampere University, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Allergology, The Hospital District of South Ostrobothnia, Sein&#xe4;joki, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lehtonen</LastName><ForeName>Jussi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology, Faculty of Medicine and Health Technology, Tampere University, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korhonen</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology, Faculty of Medicine and Health Technology, Tampere University, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Tampere University Hospital, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Virtanen</LastName><ForeName>Suvi M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8928-0878</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Well-Being Promotion Unit, Finnish Institute for Health and Welfare, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Health Sciences, Faculty of Social Sciences, Tampere University, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tampere University Hospital, Research, Development and Innovation Center, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Child Health Research, Tampere University and Tampere University Hospital, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niemel&#xe4;</LastName><ForeName>Onni</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine and Medical Research Unit, Sein&#xe4;joki Central Hospital and Tampere University, Sein&#xe4;joki/Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toppari</LastName><ForeName>Jorma</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedicine, Centre for Integrative Physiology and Pharmacology, and Centre for Population Health Research, University of Turku, Turku, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Turku University Hospital, Turku, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ilonen</LastName><ForeName>Jorma</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Immunogenetics Laboratory, Institute of Biomedicine, University of Turku, Turku, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Veijola</LastName><ForeName>Riitta</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, University of Oulu and Oulu University Hospital, Oulu, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Knip</LastName><ForeName>Mikael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0474-0033</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Research Center, Children's Hospital, University of Helsinki and Helsinki University Hospital, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Program for Clinical and Molecular Metabolism, Faculty of Medicine, University of Helsinki, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Tampere University Hospital, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laitinen</LastName><ForeName>Olli H</ForeName><Initials>OH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology, Faculty of Medicine and Health Technology, Tampere University, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xf6;nnrot</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology, Faculty of Medicine and Health Technology, Tampere University, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Tampere University Hospital, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hy&#xf6;ty</LastName><ForeName>Heikki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology, Faculty of Medicine and Health Technology, Tampere University, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fimlab Laboratories, Pirkanmaa Hospital District, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Allergy Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9106718</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0905-6157</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000485">Allergens</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000485" MajorTopicYN="N">Allergens</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001249" MajorTopicYN="Y">Asthma</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000089822" MajorTopicYN="N">Birth Cohort</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003876" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dermatitis, Atopic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">allergic rhinitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">allergy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">asthma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atopic dermatitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atopic sensitization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">children</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enterovirus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34219290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pai.13577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kulig M, Bergmann R, Klettke U, Wahn V, Tacke U, Wahn U. Natural course of sensitization to food and inhalant allergens during the first 6 years of life. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 1999;103(6):1173-1179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burney P, Malmberg E, Chinn S, Jarvis D, Luczynska C, Lai E. The distribution of total and specific serum IgE in the European community respiratory health survey. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 1997;99(3):314-322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law M, Morris JK, Wald N, Luczynska C, Burney P. Changes in atopy over a quarter of a century, based on cross sectional data at three time periods. BMJ. 2005;330(7501):1187-1188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu AH. Revisiting the hygiene hypothesis for allergy and asthma. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2015;136(4):860-865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haahtela T. A biodiversity hypothesis. Allergy. 2019;74(8):1445-1456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehar SM, Bevan MJ. Immunology: polarizing a T-cell response. Nature. 2004;430(6996):150-151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustonen K, Orivuori L, Keski-Nisula L, et al. Inflammatory response and IgE sensitization at early age. Pediatr Allergy Immunol. 2013;24(4):395-401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linneberg A, Ostergaard C, Tvede M, et al. IgG antibodies against microorganisms and atopic disease in Danish adults: the Copenhagen allergy study. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2003;111(4):847-853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matricardi PM, Rosmini F, Riondino S, et al. Exposure to foodborne and orofecal microbes versus airborne viruses in relation to atopy and allergic asthma: epidemiological study. BMJ. 2000;320(7232):412-417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverberg JI, Norowitz KB, Kleiman E, et al. Association between varicella zoster virus infection and atopic dermatitis in early and late childhood: a case-control study. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2010;126(2):300-305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korhonen L, Kondrashova A, Tauriainen S, et al. Enterovirus infections in early childhood and the risk of atopic disease - a nested case-control study. Clin Exp Allergy. 2013;43(6):625-632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seiskari T, Kondrashova A, Tauriainen S, et al. Role of enterovirus infections in IgE sensitization. J Med Virol. 2012;84(2):268-271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsson C, Linde A, Montgomery SM, et al. Does early EBV infection protect against IgE sensitization? J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2005;116(2):438-444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reimerink J, Stelma F, Rockx B, et al. Early-life rotavirus and norovirus infections in relation to development of atopic manifestation in infants. Clin Exp Allergy. 2009;39(2):254-260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janse JJ, Wong GWK, Potts J, et al. The association between foodborne and orofecal pathogens and allergic sensitisation - EuroPrevall study. Pediatr Allergy Immunol. 2014;25(3):250-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Crom SCM, Rossen JWA, van Furth AM, Obihara CC. Enterovirus and parechovirus infection in children: a brief overview. Eur J Pediatr. 2016;175(8):1023-1029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond CG, Bolock AM, Ma C, Luke CJ, Good M, Coyne CB. Enteroviruses infect human enteroids and induce antiviral signaling in a cell lineage-specific manner. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2017;114(7):1672-1677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vreugdenhil GR, Wijnands PGJTB, Netea MG, van der Meer JWM, Melchers WJG, Galama JMD. Enterovirus-induced production of pro-inflammatory and T-helper cytokines by human leukocytes. Cytokine. 2000;12(12):1793-1796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korhonen L, Seiskari T, Lehtonen J, et al. Enterovirus infection during pregnancy is inversely associated with atopic disease in the offspring. Clin Exp Allergy. 2018;48(12):1698-1704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee Z-M, Huang Y-H, Ho S-C, Kuo H-C. Correlation of symptomatic enterovirus infection and later risk of allergic diseases via a population-based cohort study. Medicine (Baltimore). 2017;96(4):e5827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korhonen L, Oikarinen S, Lehtonen J, et al. Rhinoviruses in infancy and risk of immunoglobulin E sensitization. J Med Virol. 2019;91(8):1470-1478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kupila A, Muona P, Simell T, et al. Feasibility of genetic and immunological prediction of type I diabetes in a population-based birth cohort. Diabetologia. 2001;44(3):290-297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laitinen OH, Honkanen H, Pakkanen O, et al. Coxsackievirus B1 is associated with induction of -cell autoimmunity that portends type 1 diabetes. Diabetes. 2014;63(2):446-455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roivainen M, Knip M, Hy&#xf6;ty H, et al. Several different enterovirus serotypes can be associated with prediabetic autoimmune episodes and onset of overt IDDM. Childhood Diabetes in Finland (DiMe) Study Group. J Med Virol. 1998;56(1):74-78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christiansen ES, Kjaer HF, Eller E, et al. The prevalence of atopic diseases and the patterns of sensitization in adolescence. Pediatr Allergy Immunol. 2016;27(8):847-853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;m&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen S, Nurminen N, Ahlfors H, et al. Coxsackievirus B1 reveals strain specific differences in plasmacytoid dendritic cell mediated immunogenicity. J Med Virol. 2014;86(8):1412-1420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vuorinen T, Vainionp&#xe4;&#xe4; R, Heino J, Hyypi&#xe4; T. Enterovirus receptors and virus replication in human leukocytes. J Gen Virol. 1999;80(4):921-927.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seiskari T, Viskari H, Kondrashova A, et al. Co-occurrence of allergic sensitization and type 1 diabetes. Ann Med. 2010;42(5):352-359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Str&#xf6;mberg LG, Ludvigsson GJ, Bj&#xf6;rkst&#xe9;n B. Atopic allergy and delayed hypersensitivity in children with diabetes. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 1995;96(2):188-192.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>