<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34650940</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-2360</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neurodevelopmental Outcomes of Infants Younger Than 90 Days Old Following Enterovirus and Parechovirus Infections of the Central Nervous System.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>719119</StartPage><MedlinePgn>719119</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">719119</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fped.2021.719119</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enteroviruses (EVs) and human parechoviruses (HPeVs) are a major cause of central nervous system (CNS) infection in young infants. They have been implicated in neurodevelopmental delay, however limited data are available. The aim of this study is to describe the clinical outcome of young infants and to assess and compare the medium-term neurodevelopment following CNS infections caused by EV and HPeV. A multicentre observational ambispective study was conducted between May 2013 and March 2018. Children under 3 months of age with EV or HPeV CNS infection excluding encephalitis were included. Infants were contacted 1 year after the acute infection and their neurological development was evaluated using the Ages and Stages Questionnaire-3 (ASQ-3). If any area assessed was abnormal during the first round of tests, a second round was completed 6 to 12 months later. Forty-eight young infants with EV and HPeV CNS infection were identified: 33 (68.8%) were positive for EV and 15 (31.3%) for HPeV. At first assessment 14 out of 29 EV (48.3%) and 3 out of 15 HPeV (20%) positive cases presented some developmental concern in the ASQ-3 test. EV-positive infants showed mild and moderate alteration in all domains analyzed and HPeV-positive infants showed mild alterations only in gross and fine motor domains. Significant alterations in communication were observed in EV-positive but not in HPeV-positive infants (31 vs. 0%, <i>p</i> = 0.016). At second assessment 4 out of 13 EV-positive patients (30.8%) showed mild to moderate concerns in communication and gross motor function domains and 3 out of 13 (23.1%) showed significant concern in fine motor function. Although CNS infections without associated encephalitis are generally assumed to be benign our study shows that at a median age of 18 months almost half of the EV-infected infants (48.3%) and 20% of HPeV-positive infants presented some developmental concern in the ASQ-3 test. We recommend monitor the neurological development of infants during the first years of life after HPeV CNS infection and especially after EV CNS infection, even in mild cases, for an early intervention and stimulation of psychomotor development if necessary.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 de Ceano-Vivas, Garc&#xed;a, Vel&#xe1;zquez, Mart&#xed;n del Valle, Menasalvas, Cilla, Epalza, Romero, Cabrerizo and Calvo.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Ceano-Vivas</LastName><ForeName>Mar&#xed;a</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Emergency Department, La Paz University Hospital, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a</LastName><ForeName>M Luz</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Severo Ochoa University Hospital, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vel&#xe1;zquez</LastName><ForeName>Ana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, La Paz University Hospital, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;n Del Valle</LastName><ForeName>Fernando</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Severo Ochoa University Hospital, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menasalvas</LastName><ForeName>Ana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Virgen de la Arixaca University Hospital, Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cilla</LastName><ForeName>Amaia</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Burgos University Hospital, Burgos, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Epalza</LastName><ForeName>Cristina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, 12 de Octubre University Hospital, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Romero</LastName><ForeName>M Pilar</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, La Paz University Hospital, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cabrerizo</LastName><ForeName>Mar&#xed;a</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Microbiology, Instituto de Salud Carlos III, CIBER de Epidemiolog&#xed;a y Salud P&#xfa;blica, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calvo</LastName><ForeName>Cristina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Infectious Diseases, La Paz University Hospital and La Paz Research Institute (IdiPaz), Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Research Network in Pediatric Infectious Diseases (Red de Investigaci&#xf3;n Traslacional en Infectolog&#xed;a Pedi&#xe1;trica), Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101615492</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-2360</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ASQ-3 test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">central nervous system infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">developmental outcome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enterovirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">parechovirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">young infant</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34650940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8505960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2021.719119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cabrerizo M, Trallero G, Pena MJ, Cilla A, Megias G, Munoz-Almagro C, et al. . Comparison of epidemiology and clinical characteristics of infections by human parechovirus vs. Those by enterovirus during the first month of life. Eur J Pediatr. (2015) 174:1511&#x2013;6. 10.1007/s00431-015-2566-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-015-2566-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4623089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25982340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvala H, Wolthers KC, Simmonds P. Parechoviruses in children: understanding a new infection. Curr Opin Infect Dis. (2010) 23:224&#x2013;30. 10.1097/QCO.0b013e32833890ca</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/QCO.0b013e32833890ca</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20414971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Crom SC. Enterovirus and parechovirus infections in children: differences in clinical presentation, mechanisms for meningitis without pleocytosis and mechanisms involved in the neurological outcome. Minerva Pediatr. (2019) 71:150&#x2013;8. 10.23736/S0026-4946.18.05449-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0026-4946.18.05449-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30511561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Crom SC, Rossen JW, Van Furth AM, Obihara CC. Enterovirus and parechovirus infection in children: a brief overview. Eur J Pediatr. (2016) 175:1023&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s00431-016-2725-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-016-2725-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4930465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27156106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios G, Oberste MS. Enteroviruses as agents of emerging infectious diseases. J Neurovirol. (2005) 11:424&#x2013;33. 10.1080/13550280591002531</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13550280591002531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16287683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvala H, Simmonds P. Human parechoviruses: biology, epidemiology and clinical significance. J Clin Virol. (2009) 45:1&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.jcv.2009.03.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcv.2009.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19372062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jubelt B, Lipton H. Enterovirus/picornavirus infections. In: Booss ATJ, editors. Handbook of Clinical Neurology. Amsterdam: Elsevier; (2014). p. 379&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25015496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadambari S, Braccio S, Ribeiro S, Allen DJ, Pebody R, Brown D, et al. . Enterovirus and parechovirus meningitis in infants younger than 90 days old in the UK and republic of Ireland: a British paediatric surveillance unit study. arch Dis Child. (2019) 104:552&#x2013;7. 10.1136/archdischild-2018-315643</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/archdischild-2018-315643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30530486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasidharan A, Banerjee D, Harrison CJ, Selvarangan R. Emergence of parechovirus A3 as the leading cause of central nervous system infection, surpassing any single enterovirus type, in children in Kansas city from 2007 to 2016. J Clin Microbiol. (2021) 59. 10.1128/JCM.02935-20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.02935-20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8316090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33692140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L'huillier AG, Mardegan C, Cordey S, Luterbacher F, Papis S, Hugon F, Kaiser L, et al. . Enterovirus, parechovirus, adenovirus and herpes virus type 6 viraemia in fever without source. Arch Dis Child. (2020) 105:180&#x2013;6. 10.1136/archdischild-2019-317382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/archdischild-2019-317382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakrabarti P, Warren C, Vincent L, Kumar Y. Outcome of routine cerebrospinal fluid screening for enterovirus and human parechovirus infection among infants with sepsis-like illness or meningitis in Cornwall, UK. Eur J Pediatr. (2018) 177:1523&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s00431-018-3209-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-018-3209-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30022279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harik N, Debiasi RL. Neonatal nonpolio enterovirus and parechovirus infections. Semin Perinatol. (2018) 42:191&#x2013;7. 10.1053/j.semperi.2018.02.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.semperi.2018.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29526382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black S, Bradley C, Lai FY, Shenoy S, Bandi S, Allen DJ, et al. . Comparing the clinical severity of disease caused by enteroviruses and human parechoviruses in neonates and infants. Pediatr Infect Dis J. (2019) 38:e36&#x2013;8. 10.1097/INF.0000000000002145</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000002145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30001232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Jong EP, Van Den Beuken MGA, Van Elzakker EPM, Wolthers KC, Sprij AJ, Lopriore E, et al. . Epidemiology of sepsis-like illness in young infants: major role of enterovirus and human parechovirus. Pediatr Infect Dis J. (2018) 37:113&#x2013;8. 10.1097/INF.0000000000001718</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000001718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28763426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aizawa Y, Suzuki Y, Watanabe K, Oishi T, Saitoh A. Clinical utility of serum samples for human parechovirus type 3 infection in neonates and young infants: the 2014 epidemic in Japan. J Infect. (2016) 72:223&#x2013;32. 10.1016/j.jinf.2015.10.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2015.10.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26550926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renaud C, Kuypers J, Ficken E, Cent A, Corey L, Englund JA. Introduction of a novel parechovirus RT-PCR clinical test in a regional medical center. J Clin Virol. (2011) 51:50&#x2013;3. 10.1016/j.jcv.2011.02.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcv.2011.02.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21397555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin Del Valle F, Calvo C, Martinez-Rienda I, Cilla A, Romero MP, Menasalvas AI, et al. . [Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of infants admitted to hospital due to human parechovirus infections: a prospective study in Spain]. An Pediatr. (2018) 88:82&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.anpede.2017.02.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anpede.2017.02.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28365283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchand S, Launay E, Schuffenecker I, Gras-Le Guen C, Imbert-Marcille BM, Coste-Burel M. Severity of parechovirus infections in infants under 3 months of age and comparison with enterovirus infections: a French retrospective study. Arch Pediatr. (2021) 28:291&#x2013;5. 10.1016/j.arcped.2021.02.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arcped.2021.02.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33773893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin Del Valle F, Menasalvas Ruiz A, Cilla A, Gonzalez AV, De Ceano Vivas M, Cabrerizo Sanz M, et al. . Neurodevelopment medium-term outcome after parechovirus infection. Early Hum Dev. (2019) 132:1&#x2013;5. 10.1016/j.earlhumdev.2019.03.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earlhumdev.2019.03.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30908988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Britton PN, Dale RC, Nissen MD, Crawford N, Elliott E, Macartney K, et al. . Parechovirus encephalitis and neurodevelopmental outcomes. Pediatrics. (2016) 137:e20152848. 10.1542/peds.2015-2848</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2015-2848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26791970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph L, May M, Thomas M, Smerdon C, Tozer S, Bialasiewicz S, et al. . Human parechovirus 3 in infants: expanding our knowledge of adverse outcomes. Pediatr Infect Dis J. (2019) 38:1&#x2013;5. 10.1097/INF.0000000000002136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000002136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30204658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrerizo M, Echevarria JE, Gonzalez I, De Miguel T, Trallero G. Molecular epidemiological study of HEV-B enteroviruses involved in the increase in meningitis cases occurred in Spain during 2006. J Med Virol. (2008) 80:1018&#x2013;24. 10.1002/jmv.21197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.21197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18428125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvala H, Robertson I, Mcwilliam Leitch EC, Benschop K, Wolthers KC, Templeton K, et al. . Epidemiology and clinical associations of human parechovirus respiratory infections. J Clin Microbiol. (2008) 46:3446&#x2013;53. 10.1128/JCM.01207-08</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.01207-08</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2566073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18753351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Sanz R, Taravillo I, Reina J, Navascues A, Moreno-Docon A, Aranzamendi M, et al. . Enterovirus D68-associated respiratory and neurological illness in Spain, 2014-2018. Emerg Microbes Infect. (2019) 8:1438&#x2013;44. 10.1080/22221751.2019.1668243</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/22221751.2019.1668243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6781473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31571527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valla L, Wentzel-Larsen T, Hofoss D, Slinning K. Prevalence of suspected developmental delays in early infancy: results from a regional population-based longitudinal study. BMC Pediatr. (2015) 15:215. 10.1186/s12887-015-0528-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-015-0528-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4683867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26678149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abo El Elella SS, Tawfik MAM, Abo El Fotoh WMM, Barseem NF. Screening for developmental delay in preschool-aged children using parent-completed ages and stages questionnaires: additional insights into child development. Postgrad Med J. (2017) 93:597&#x2013;602. 10.1136/postgradmedj-2016-134694</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/postgradmedj-2016-134694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28408725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A, Yeh CJ, Boone Blanchard S. Ages and stages questionnaire: a global screening scale. Bol Med Hosp Infant Mex. (2017) 74:5&#x2013;12. 10.1016/j.bmhimx.2016.07.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bmhimx.2016.07.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29364814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piralla A, Mariani B, Stronati M, Marone P, Baldanti F. Human enterovirus and parechovirus infections in newborns with sepsis-like illness and neurological disorders. Early Hum Dev. (2014) 1(Suppl. 90):S75&#x2013;7. 10.1016/S0378-3782(14)70023-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0378-3782(14)70023-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24709467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvala H, Griffiths M, Solomon T, Simmonds P. Distinct systemic and central nervous system disease patterns in enterovirus and parechovirus infected children. J Infect. (2014) 69:69&#x2013;74. 10.1016/j.jinf.2014.02.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2014.02.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24662038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudson JA, Broad J, Martin NG, Sadarangani M, Galal U, Kelly DF, et al. . Outcomes beyond hospital discharge in infants and children with viral meningitis: a systematic review. Rev Med Virol. (2020) 30:e2083. 10.1002/rmv.2083</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rmv.2083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31524309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyle CA, Cordero JF, Trevathan E. The national center on birth defects and developmental disabilities: past, present, and future. Am J Prev Med. (2012) 43:655&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.amepre.2012.08.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2012.08.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4445684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23159262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hinsbergh TMT, Elbers RG, Van Furth MAM, Obihara CCC. Longitudinal association between human parechovirus central nervous system infection and gross-motor neurodevelopment in young children. Pediatr Infect Dis J. (2019) 38:110&#x2013;4. 10.1097/INF.0000000000002052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000002052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29601457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hinsbergh TMT, Elbers RG, Hans Ket JCF, Van Furth AM, Obihara CC. Neurological and neurodevelopmental outcomes after human parechovirus CNS infection in neonates and young children: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. (2020) 4:592&#x2013;605. 10.1016/S2352-4642(20)30181-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-4642(20)30181-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32710840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilfert CM, Thompson Jr RJ, Sunder TR, O'quinn A, Zeller J, et al. . Longitudinal assessment of children with enteroviral meningitis during the first three months of life. Pediatrics. (1981) 67:811&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7232044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sells CJ, Carpenter RL, Ray CG. Sequelae of central-nervous-system enterovirus infections. N Engl J Med. (1975) 293:1&#x2013;4. 10.1056/NEJM197507032930101</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM197507032930101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1168853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ream MA, Lehwald L. Neurologic consequences of preterm birth. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. (2018) 18:48. 10.1007/s11910-018-0862-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11910-018-0862-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29907917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dokkum NH, De Kroon MLA, Bos AF, Reijneveld SA, Kerstjens JM. Attainment of gross motor milestones by preterm children with normal development upon school entry. Early Hum Dev. (2018) 119:62&#x2013;67. 10.1016/j.earlhumdev.2018.03.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earlhumdev.2018.03.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29579559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woythaler MA, Mccormick MC, Smith VC. Late preterm infants have worse 24-month neurodevelopmental outcomes than term infants. Pediatrics. (2011) 127:e622&#x2013;9. 10.1542/peds.2009-3598</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2009-3598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21321024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutierrez-Cruz N, Torres-Mohedas J, Carrasco-Marina ML, Olabarrieta-Arnal I, Martin-Del Valle F, Garcia-Garcia ML. [Psychomotor development in late preterms at two years of age: a comparison with full-term newborn infants using two different instruments]. Rev Neurol. (2019) 68:503&#x2013;9. 10.33588/rn.6812.2018360</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33588/rn.6812.2018360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31173330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>