<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34988812</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1614-7499</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>19</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental science and pollution research international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Sci Pollut Res Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Quantitative RT-PCR detection of human noroviruses and hepatitis A virus in fresh produce and surface water used for irrigation in the Mansoura and Giza regions, Egypt.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>28139</StartPage><EndPage>28148</EndPage><MedlinePgn>28139-28148</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11356-021-18412-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Surface water used as an irrigation source can be a significant source of viral contamination of fresh produce. Enteric viruses such as hepatitis A virus (HAV) and human norovirus genogroup I (HNoV GI) and genogroup II (HNoV GII) can be transmitted to human via fresh produce when irrigated with contaminated water or when prepared by infected food handlers. In the current study, we investigated the presence of HAV, HNoV GI and GII in fresh produce and surface water used in cultivation of this produce using real-time PCR. Samples were collected from six different points in the Mansoura and Giza regions, Egypt. Our analysis showed that at least one virus was found in 41.6% (30/72) of surface water samples and 27% (13/48) of fresh produce samples. HAV (23/72) with a mean viral concentration&#x2009;=&#x2009;4&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>6</sup> genome copies/litre (GC/L) was the most frequently identified virus in surface water samples, followed by human norovirus genogroup II (HNoV GII) (15/72, with a mean concentration&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.2&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>6</sup> GC/L, and human noroviruses genogroup I (HNoV GI) (12/72, with a mean concentration&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.4&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>4</sup> GC/L). Additionally, HAV (10/48) with a mean concentration&#x2009;=&#x2009;5.2&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>5</sup> genome copies/gram (GC/g) was also the most frequently detected virus in the fresh produce samples, followed by HNoV GII (8/48, with a mean concentration&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.7&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>4</sup> GC/g); meanwhile, HNoV GI (6/48) was less detected virus with a mean concentration&#x2009;=&#x2009;3&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>3</sup> GC/g. This work suggests a wide prevalence of human enteric viruses in surface waters and fresh produce, which is of concern when the fresh produce is eaten raw. Thus, additional monitoring for viral pathogens in irrigation water and food is needed to increase the awareness of this issue to rise the control measures to reduce illness from contaminated food.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaheen</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed N F</ForeName><Initials>MNF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Environmental Virology Laboratory, Water Pollution Research Department, Environment and Climate Change Research Institute, National Research Centre, Dokki, 12622, Giza, Egypt. m_nrc2007@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elmahdy</LastName><ForeName>Elmahdy M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Environmental Virology Laboratory, Water Pollution Research Department, Environment and Climate Change Research Institute, National Research Centre, Dokki, 12622, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahmoud</LastName><ForeName>Lamiaa H I</ForeName><Initials>LHI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genetics and Molecular Biology Unit, Botany and Microbiology Department, Faculty of Science, Helwan University, Helwan, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hammad</LastName><ForeName>Ibtisam A</ForeName><Initials>IA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genetics and Molecular Biology Unit, Botany and Microbiology Department, Faculty of Science, Helwan University, Helwan, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soliman</LastName><ForeName>Elham R S</ForeName><Initials>ERS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genetics and Molecular Biology Unit, Botany and Microbiology Department, Faculty of Science, Helwan University, Helwan, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Sci Pollut Res Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9441769</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0944-1344</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004534" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Egypt</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D030041" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hepatitis A virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029322" MajorTopicYN="Y">Norovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020133" MajorTopicYN="N">Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014780" MajorTopicYN="Y">Viruses</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="N">Water</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fresh produce</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatitis A virus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Noroviruses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Real-time PCR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Water</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34988812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-021-18412-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11356-021-18412-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahmed SM, Hall AJ, Robinson AE, Verhoef L, Premkumar P, Parashar UD, Koopmans M, Lopman BA (2014) Global prevalence of norovirus in cases of gastroenteritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Infect Dis 14:725&#x2013;730</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(14)70767-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amon JJ, Devasia R, Xia G, Nainan OV, Hall S, Lawson B, Wolthuis JS, Macdonald PD, Shepard CW, Williams IT, Armstrong GL, Gabel JA, Erwin P, Sheeler L, Kuhnert W, Patel P, Vaughan G, Weltman A, Craig AS, Bell BP, Fiore A (2005) Molecular epidemiology of foodborne hepatitis a outbreaks in the United States, 2003. J Infect Dis 192(8):1323&#x2013;1330</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/462425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baert L, Mattison K, Loisy-Hamon F, Harlow J, Martyres A, Lebeau B, Stals A, Van Coillie E, Herman L, Uyttendaele M (2011) Review: norovirus prevalence in Belgian, Canadian and French fresh: a threat to human health? Int J Food Microbiol 151:261&#x2013;269</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2011.09.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bidawid S, Farber JM, Sattar SA (2000a) Contamination of foods by food handlers: experiments on HAV transfer to food and its interruption. Appl Environ Microbiol 7:2759&#x2013;2763</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.66.7.2759-2763.2000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bidawid S, Farber JM, Sattar SA (2000b) Contamination of foods by food handlers: experiments on hepatitis a virus transfer to food and its interruption. Appl Environ Microbiol 66(7):2759&#x2013;2763</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.66.7.2759-2763.2000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bitton G (2014) Microbiology of drinking water: production and distribution. John Wiley &amp; Sons</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosch A, Gkogka E, Le Guyader FS, Loisy-Hamon F, Lee A, van Lieshout L, Marthi B, Myrmel M, Sansom A, Schultz AC, Winkler A, Zuber S, Phister T (2018) Foodborne viruses: detection, risk assessment, and control options in food processing. Int J Food Microbiol 285:110&#x2013;128</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2018.06.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brassard J, Gagn&#xe9; MJ, G&#xe9;n&#xe9;reux M, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; C (2012) Detection of human food-borne and zoonotic viruses on irrigated, field-grown strawberries. Appl Environ Microbiol 78(10):3763&#x2013;3766</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatziprodromidou IP, Bellou M, Vantarakis G, Vantarakis A (2018) Viral outbreaks linked to fresh produce consumption: a systematic review. J Appl Microbiol 124(4):932&#x2013;942</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jam.13747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chhabra P, de Graaf M, Parra GI, Chan MC, Green K, Martella V, Wang Q, White PA, Katayama K, Vennema H, Koopmans MPG, Vinj&#xe9; J (2019) Updated classification of norovirus genogroups and genotypes. J Gen Virol 100(10):1393&#x2013;1406</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/jgv.0.001318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook N, Williams L, D&#x2019;Agostino M (2019) Prevalence of Norovirus in produce sold at retail in the United Kingdom. Food Microbiol 79:85&#x2013;89</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datta SD, Traeger MS, Nainan OV (2001) Identification of a multi-state outbreak of hepatitis A associated with green onions using a novel molecular epidemiologic technique [abstract 896]. InProgram and abstracts of the 39th Annual Meeting of the Infectious Diseases Society of America (Vol. 192). Alexandra, VA: Infectious Diseases Society of America 2001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dentinger CM, Bower WA, Nainan OV, Cotter SM, Myers G, Dubusky LM, Fowler S, Salehi ED, Bell BP (2001) An outbreak of hepatitis A associated with green onions. J Infect Dis 183:1273&#x2013;1276</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/319688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Directorate-General for Agriculture European Commission (2002) Economic impacts of genetically modified crops on the agri-food sector. A synthesis. p. 18</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmahdy EM, Shaheen MN, Rizk NM, Saad-Hussein A (2020) Quantitative detection of human adenovirus and Human Rotavirus Group A in wastewater and el-Rahawy drainage canal influencing River Nile in the north of Giza, Egypt. Food Environ Virol 12(3):218&#x2013;225</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emilse PV, Mat&#xed;as V, Cecilia ML, Oscar GM, Gisela M, Guadalupe D, Elizabethab RV, Victorioa PJ, Rodneyc C, Vivianaa NS, Ang&#xe9;lica BP (2021) Enteric virus presence in green vegetables and associated irrigation waters in a rural area from Argentina. A quantitative microbial risk assessment. LWT 144:111201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lwt.2021.111201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethelberg S, Lisby M, B&#xf6;ttiger B, Schultz AC, Villif A, Jensen T, Olsen KE, Scheutz F, Kjels&#xf8; C, Muller L (2010) Outbreaks of gastroenteritis linked to lettuce, Denmark, January 2010. Eurosurveillance 15(6):19484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2807/ese.15.06.19484-en</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felix-Valenzuela L, Resendiz-Sandoval M, Burgara-Estrella A, Hern&#xe1;ndez J, Mata-Haro V (2012) Quantitative detection of hepatitis A, rotavirus and genogroup I norovirus by RT-qPCR in fresh produce from packinghouse facilities. J Food Saf 32(4):467&#x2013;473</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jfs.12009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerba CP, Choi CY (2006) Role of irrigation water in crop contamination by viruses. In: Goyal SM (ed) Viruses in Foods, 1st edn. Springer, New York, pp 257&#x2013;263</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/0-387-29251-9_11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerba PC, Choi YP, Goyal SM (2006) Role of irrigation water in crop contamination by viruses. Viruses in foods. Springer, Boston, MA, pp 257&#x2013;263</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/0-387-29251-9_11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta E, Ballani N (2014) State of the globe: hepatitis A virus&#x2014;return of a water devil. J Glob Infect Dis 6:57&#x2013;58</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0974-777X.132036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamza IA, Jurzik L, Stang A, Sure K, Uberla K, Wilhelm M (2009) Detection of human viruses in rivers of a densly&#x2212;populated area in Germany using a virus adsorption elution method optimized for PCR analyses. Water Res 43(10):2657&#x2013;2668</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2009.03.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris JP, Edmunds WJ, Pebody R, Brown DW, Lopman BA (2008) Deaths from norovirus among the elderly, England and Wales. Emerg Infect Dis 14:1546&#x2013;1552</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid1410.080188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennechart-Collette C, Dehan O, Laurentie M, Fraisse A, Martin-Latil S, Perelle S (2021) Detection of norovirus, hepatitis A and hepatitis E viruses in multicomponent foodstuffs. Int J Food Microbiol 337:108931</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2020.108931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hidayah N, Tuan Zainazor C, Pui CF, Noorlis A, Noor Eliza MR, Naziehah MD, Ghazali FM, Cheah YK, Nakaguchi Y, Nishibuchi M, Son R (2011) Occurrence of Norovirus GI in green and red onion. Int Food Res J 18(2):677&#x2013;681</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutson AM, Atmar RL, Estes MK (2004) Norovirus disease: changing epidemiology and host susceptibility factors. Trends Microbiol 12:279&#x2013;287</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tim.2004.04.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ISO 15216&#x2013;1:2017 (2017) Microbiology of food and animal stuffs&#x2014; horizontal method for detection of hepatis A virus and norovirus in food using real-time RT-PCR. International Organization for Standardization</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen KH (2009) The global prevalence of hepatitis A virus infection and susceptibility: a systematic review (No. WHO/IVB/10.01); WHO Press, Geneva, Switzerland</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jothikumar N, Cromeans TL, Sobsey MD, Robertson H (2005) Development and evaluation of a broadly reactive TaqMan assay for rapid detection of hepatitis A virus. Appl Environ Microbiol 71:3359&#x2013;3363</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.6.3359-3363.2005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kageyama T, Kojima S, Shinohara M, Uchida K, Fukushi S, Hoshino FB, Takeda N, Katayama K (2003) Broadly reactive and highly sensitive assay for Norwalk-like viruses based on real-time quantitative reverse transcription-PCR. J Clin Microbiol 41:1548&#x2013;1557</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.41.4.1548-1557.2003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamel AH, AliMA E-N, De Rougemont A, Pothier P, Belliot G (2009) Predominance and circulation of enteric viruses in the region of Greater Cairo, Egypt. J Clin Microbiol 47(4):1037&#x2013;1045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.01381-08</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamel AH, Ali MA, El-Nady HG, Aho S, Pothier P, Belliot G (2010) Evidence of the co-circulation of enteric viruses in sewage and in the population of Greater Cairo. J Appl Microbiol 108(5):1620&#x2013;1629</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2672.2009.04562.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamel AH, Ali MA, El-Nady HG, Deraz A, Aho S, Pothier P, Belliot G (2011) Presence of enteric hepatitis viruses in the sewage and population of Greater Cairo. Clin Microbiol Infect 17(8):1182&#x2013;1185</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-0691.2011.03461.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katayama H, Shimasaki A, Ohgaki S (2002) Development of a virus concentration method and its application to detection of enterovirus and Norwalk virus from coastal seawater. Appl Environ Microbiol 68:1033&#x2013;1039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.68.3.1033-1039.2002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan W, Irshad M, Rehman G, Hussain A (2014) HAV in fresh vegetables: a hidden health risk in district Mardan. Pakistan. Springerplus 3(1):1&#x2013;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo HL, Ajami N, Atmar RL, DuPont HL (2010) Noroviruses: the leading cause of gastroenteritis worldwide. Discov Med 10:61&#x2013;70</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotwal G, Cannon JL (2014) Environmental persistence and transfer of enteric viruses. Curr Opin Virol 4C:37&#x2013;43</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coviro.2013.12.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M, Seo DJ, Seo J, Oh H, Jeon SB, Ha SD, Myoung J, Choi IS, Choi C (2015) Detection of viable murine norovirus using the plaque assay and propidium-monoazide-combined real-time reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction. J Virol Methods 221:57&#x2013;61</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jviromet.2015.04.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon-Felix J, Martinez-Bustillos RA, Baez-Sa&#xf1;udo M, Peraza-Garay F, Chaidez C (2010) Norovirus contamination of bell pepper from handling during harvesting and packing. Food Environ Virol 2:211&#x2013;217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12560-010-9048-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodder WJ, de RodaHusman AM (2005) Presence of noroviruses and other enteric viruses in sewage and surface waters in the Netherlands. Appl Environ Microbiol 71:1453&#x2013;1461</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.3.1453-1461.2005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loutreul J, Cazeaux C, Levert D, Nicolas A, Vautier S, Le Sauvage AL, Perelle S, Morin T (2014) Prevalence of human noroviruses in frozen marketed shellfish, red fruits and fresh vegetables. Food Environ Virol 6(3):157&#x2013;168</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathijs E, Stals A, Baert L, Botteldoorn N, Denayer S, Mauroy A, Scipioni A, Daube G, Dierick K, Herman L, Van Coillie E, Uyttendaele M, Thiry E (2012) A review of known and hypothetical transmission routes for noroviruses. Food Environ Virol 4(4):131&#x2013;152</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12560-012-9091-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews JE, Dickey BW, Miller RD, Felzer JR, Dawson BP, Lee AS, Rocks JJ, Kiel J, Montes JS, Moe CL, Eisenberg JN, Leon JS (2012) The epidemiology of published norovirus outbreaks: a review of risk factors associated with attack rate and genogroup. Epidemiol Infect 140:1161&#x2013;1172</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0950268812000234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira NA, Bondelind M (2017) Safe drinking water and waterborne outbreaks. J Water Health 15(1):83&#x2013;96</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2016.103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nainan OV, Xia G, Vaughan G, Margolis HS (2006) Diagnosis of hepatitis a virus infection: a molecular approach. Clin Microbiol Rev 19:63&#x2013;79</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/CMR.19.1.63-79.2006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osuolale O, Okoh A (2015) Incidence of human adenoviruses and hepatitis A virus in the final e_uent of selected wastewater treatment plants in Eastern Cape Province, South Africa. Virol J 12:1&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12985-015-0327-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne DC, Vinj&#xe9; J, Szilagyi PG, Edwards KM, Staat MA, Weinberg GA, Hall CB, Chappell J, Bernstein DI, Curns AT, Wikswo M, Shirley SH, Hall AJ, Lopman B, Parashar UD (2013) Norovirus and medically attended gastroenteritis in U.S. children. N Engl J Med 368:1121&#x2013;1130</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMsa1206589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pires SM, Fischer-Walker CL, Lanata CF, Devleesschauwer B, Hall AJ, Kirk MD, Duarte ASR, Black RE, Angulo FJ (2015) Aetiology-specific estimates of the global and regional incidence and mortality of diarrhoeal diseases commonly transmitted through food. PLoS ONE 10:e0142927</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0142927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prez VE, Martinez LC, Victoria M, Giordano MO, Masachessi G, Re VE, Pavan JV, Colina R, Barril PA, Nates SV (2018) Tracking enteric viruses in green vegetables from central Argentina: potential association with viral contamination of irrigation waters. Sci Total Environ 637&#x2013;638:665&#x2013;671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.05.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purpari G, Macaluso G, Di Bella S, Gucciardi F, Mira F, Di Marco P, Lastra A, Petersen E, La Rosa G, Guercio A (2019) Molecular characterization of human enteric viruses in food, water samples, and surface swabs in Sicily. Int J Infect Dis 1(80):66&#x2013;72</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2018.12.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santamaria J, Toranzos GA (2003) Enteric pathogens and soil: a short review. Int Microbiol 6:5&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10123-003-0096-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seymour IJ, Appleton H (2001) Foodborne viruses and fresh produce. J Appl Microbiol 91:759&#x2013;773</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2672.2001.01427.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen MN, Elmahdy EM (2019a) Environmental monitoring of astrovirus and norovirus in the Rosetta branch of the River Nile and the El-Rahawy drain, Egypt. Water Supply 19(5):1381&#x2013;1387</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/ws.2019.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen MN, Elmahdy EM (2019b) Molecular detection of group C rotavirus in environmental samples in Giza, Egypt. Asian J Water Environ Pollut 16(4):17&#x2013;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/AJW190044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen MN, Abd El-Daim SE, Ahmed NI, Elmahdy EM (2018) Molecular detection of three gastroenteritis viruses in urban sewage treatment plant and river water in Egypt. J Aquat Biol Fish 22(5):615&#x2013;627</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/ejabf.2018.60278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen MN, Elmahdy EM, Chawla-Sarkar M (2019) Quantitative PCR-based identification of enteric viruses contaminating fresh produce and surface water used for irrigation in Egypt. Environ Sci Pollut Res 26(21):21619&#x2013;21628</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-019-05435-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen MN, Abd El-Daim SE, Ahmed NI, Elmahdy EM (2020) Environmental monitoring of Aichi virus and human bocavirus in samples from wastewater treatment plant, drain, and River Nile in Egypt. J Water Health 18(1):30&#x2013;37</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2019.075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebenga JJ, Vennema H, Zheng DP, Vinj&#xe9; J, Lee BE, Pang XL, Ho EC, Lim W, Choudekar A, Broor S, Halperin T, Rasool NB, Hewitt J, Greening GE, Jin M, Duan ZJ, Lucero Y, O&#x2019;Ryan M, Hoehne M, Schreier E, Ratcliff RM, White PA, Iritani N, Reuter G, Koopmans M (2009) Norovirus illness is a global problem: emergence and spread of norovirus GII.4 Variants, 2001&#x2013;2007. J Infect Dis 200:802&#x2013;812</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian G, Jin M, Li H, Li Q, Wang J, Duan ZJ (2014) Clinical characteristics and genetic diversity of noroviruses in adults with acute gastroenteritis in Beijing, China in 2008&#x2013;2009. J Med Virol 86:1235&#x2013;1242</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.23802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughan G, Goncalves Rossi LM, Forbi JC, de Paula VS, Purdy MA, Xia G, Khudyakov YE (2014) Hepatitis A virus: host interactions, molecular epidemiology and evolution. Infect Genet Evol 21C:227&#x2013;243</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.meegid.2013.10.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheeler C, Vogt TM, Armstrong GL, Vaughan G, Weltman A, Nainan OV, Dato V, Xia G, Waller K, Amon J, Lee TM (2005) An outbreak of hepatitis A associated with green onions. N Engl J Med 353(9):890&#x2013;897</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa050855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2005) Acute water diarrhea outbreaks. Wkly Morb Mortal Rep 1(6)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, WHO/UNICEF Joint Water Supply, Sanitation Monitoring Programme (2015) Progress on sanitation and drinking water: 2015 update and MDG assessment. World Health Organization</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yezlis, Otter JA (2011) Minimum infective dose of the major human respiratory and enteric viruses transmitted through food and the environment. Food Environ Virol 3:1&#x2013;30</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12560-011-9056-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong HT, Son R (2009) Review article hepatitis A virus&#x2014;a general overview. Int Food Res J 467:455&#x2013;467</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaher KS, Ahmed WM, Syame SM, El-Hewairy HM (2008) Detection of health hazard-food born viruses in animal products anticipated for human consumption. Global Veterinaria 2(4):192&#x2013;197</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaki ME, Abdel-Rahaman EA, AshryAY El, Al-Kasaby NM (2019) Molecular study of norovirus in pediatric patients with gastroenteritis. Open Microbiol J 13(1):324&#x2013;329</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1874285801913010324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaki ME, El Kheir NA (2017) Molecular study of astrovirus, adenovirus and norovirus in community acquired diarrhea in children: One Egyptian center study. Asian Pac J Trop Biomed 7(11):987&#x2013;990</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>