<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35118781</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1554-7531</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>94</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Water environment research : a research publication of the Water Environment Federation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Water Environ Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Examining the antimicrobial efficacy of granulated tetraacetylethylenediamine derived peracetic acid and commercial peracetic acid in urban wastewaters.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e10688</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e10688</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/wer.10688</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The ever-increasing need for access to safe water has meant that alternative water sources and innovative water reclamation approaches are often required to meet the global water demand. As a result, many wastewater treatment facilities have faced regulatory pressure to seek alternative disinfection methods that ensure public health safety, while adhering to regulations that set limits on carcinogenic disinfection by-products (DBPs). Peracetic acid (PAA) is an emerging wastewater disinfectant in the United States that has been widely used in other industries such as food sanitization and does not produce carcinogenic DBPs. However, several factors such as transport, storage, and physical and chemical effects have stymied its widespread use in wastewater markets. Therefore, the purpose of this study was to examine the antimicrobial efficacy of an on-site generated PAA compared against a commercially available PAA. Antimicrobial efficacy was assessed using standard fecal contamination indicators (i.e., total coliforms and Escherichia coli) in six urban wastewater treatment facilities ranging in size and treatment processes. Overall, few statistical differences were found between the antimicrobial efficacies of on-site generated PAA and commercially available PAA; however, before becoming more widely utilized, the on-site PAA should be tested against emerging fecal contamination indicators (e.g., human norovirus and enterovirus) and be assessed in terms of economic and sustainability impacts. PRACTITIONER POINTS: Alternative Ct approaches should be considered when using disinfectants like PAA. On-site generated PAA can achieve the same level of disinfection as commercial PAA. On-site generation of PAA may help further its use as a wastewater disinfectant.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Water Environment Federation.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spencer-Williams</LastName><ForeName>Isaiah</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6311-0229</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Theobald</LastName><ForeName>Allister</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lubrizol Advanced Materials, Inc., Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cypcar</LastName><ForeName>Christopher C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lubrizol Advanced Materials, Inc., Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Casson</LastName><ForeName>Leonard W</ForeName><Initials>LW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4010-7684</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haig</LastName><ForeName>Sarah-Jane</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0004-8894</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental and Occupational Health, Graduate School of Public Health, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Lubrizol</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>University of Pittsburgh</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Water Environ Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9886167</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1061-4303</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TAED</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">emerging disinfection technology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fecal coliforms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">on&#x2010;site disinfection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peracetic acid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wastewater disinfection</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35118781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wer.10688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Amerian, T., Farnood, R., Sarathy, S., &amp; Santoro, D. (2019). Effects of total suspended solids, particle size, and effluent temperature on the kinetics of peracetic acid decomposition in municipal wastewater. Water Science and Technology, 80(12), 2299&#x2013;2309. https://doi.org/10.2166/wst.2020.047</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldry, M. G. C. (1983). The bactericidal, fungicidal and sporicidal properties of hydrogen peroxide and peracetic acid. Journal of Applied Bacteriology, 54, 417&#x2013;423. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2672.1983.tb02637.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldry, M. G. C., Cavdore, A., French, M. S., Rodrigues, L. M., Schirch, P. F. T., &amp; Threadgold, T. L. (1995). Effluent disinfection in warm climates with peracetic acid. Water Science and Technology, 31(5&#x2013;6), 161&#x2013;164. https://doi.org/10.2166/wst.1995.0589</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldry, M. G. C., French, M. S., &amp; Slater, D. (1991). The activity of peracetic acid on sewage indicator bacteria and viruses. Water Science and Technology, 24(2), 353&#x2013;357. https://doi.org/10.2166/wst.1991.0089</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauermeister, L. J., Bowers, J. W. J., Townsend, J. C., &amp; McKee, S. R. (2008). The microbial and quality properties of poultry carcasses treated with peracetic acid as an antimicrobial treatment. Poultry Science, 87(11), 2390&#x2013;2398. https://doi.org/10.3382/ps.2008-00087</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettenhausen, C. A. (2020, April 20). How peracetic acid is changing wastewater treatment. Chemical &amp; Engineering News, 98(15). https://cen.acs.org/environment/water/peracetic-acid-changing-wastewater-treatment/98/i15</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block, P. (2016). The decomposition kinetics of peracetic acid and hydrogen peroxide in municipal wastewaters. Proceedings of the Water Environment Federation, 2016(10), 555&#x2013;563. https://doi.org/10.2175/193864716819707265</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrasco, G., &amp; Urrestarazu, M. (2010). Green chemistry in protected horticulture: The use of peroxyacetic acid as a sustainable strategy. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 11(5), 1999&#x2013;2009. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms11051999</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casanova, J., Devau, N., &amp; Pettenati, M. (2016). Managed aquifer recharge: An overview of issues and options. In A. J. Jakeman, O. Barreteau, R. J. Hunt, J.&#x2010;D. Rinaudo, &amp; A. Ross (Eds.), Integrated groundwater management: Concepts, approaches and challenges (pp. 413&#x2013;434). Springer International Publishing. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-23576-9_16</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavallini, G. S., de Campos, S. X., de Souza, J. B., &amp; de Sousa Vidal, C. M. (2013). Evaluation of the physical&#x2010;chemical characteristics of wastewater after disinfection with peracetic acid. Water, Air, &amp; Soil Pollution, 224(10) Academic OneFile, 1&#x2013;11. http://link.galegroup.com/apps/doc/A348216632/AONE?u=upitt_main&amp;sid=AONE&amp;xid=e2ddf3e4, https://doi.org/10.1007/s11270-013-1752-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crebelli, R., Conti, L., Monarca, S., Feretti, D., Zerbini, I., Zani, C., Veschetti, E., Cutilli, D., &amp; Ottaviani, M. (2005). Genotoxicity of the disinfection by&#x2010;products resulting from peracetic acid&#x2010; or hypochlorite&#x2010;disinfected sewage wastewater. Water Research, 39(6), 1105&#x2013;1113. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2004.12.029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson, J., Summerfelt, S., Straus, D. L., Schrader, K. K., &amp; Good, C. (2019). Evaluating the effects of prolonged peracetic acid dosing on water quality and rainbow trout Oncorhynchus mykiss performance in recirculation aquaculture systems. Aquacultural Engineering, 84, 117&#x2013;127. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aquaeng.2018.12.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dell'Erba, A., Falsanisi, D., Liberti, L., Notarnicola, M., &amp; Santoro, D. (2007). Disinfection by&#x2010;products formation during wastewater disinfection with peracetic acid. Desalination, 215(1&#x2013;3), 177&#x2013;186. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.desal.2006.08.021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xed;nguez Henao, L., Cascio, M., Turolla, A., &amp; Antonelli, M. (2018). Effect of suspended solids on peracetic acid decay and bacterial inactivation kinetics: Experimental assessment and definition of predictive models. Science of the Total Environment, 643, 936&#x2013;945. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.06.219</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xed;nguez Henao, L., Delli Compagni, R., Turolla, A., &amp; Antonelli, M. (2018). Influence of inorganic and organic compounds on the decay of peracetic acid in wastewater disinfection. Chemical Engineering Journal, 337, 133&#x2013;142. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2017.12.074</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eramo, A., Medina, W. R. M., &amp; Fahrenfeld, N. L. (2017). Peracetic acid disinfection kinetics for combined sewer overflows: Indicator organisms, antibiotic resistance genes, and microbial community. Environmental Science: Water Research &amp; Technology, 3(6), 1061&#x2013;1072. https://doi.org/10.1039/C7EW00184C</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falsanisi, D., Gehr, R., Liberti, L., &amp; Notarnicola, M. (2008). Effect of suspended particles on disinfection of a physicochemical municipal wastewater with peracetic acid. Water Quality Research Journal, 43(1), 47&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.2166/wqrj.2008.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Human &amp; Environmental Risk Assessment. (2002). 2&#x2010;F&#x2010;04&#x2010;HERA TAED full web wd.pdf. Human &amp; Environmental Risk Assessment. https://www.heraproject.com/files/2&#x2010;F&#x2010;04&#x2010;HERA%20TAED%20full%20web%20wd.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kataria, J., Vaddu, S., Rama, E. N., Sidhu, G., Thippareddi, H., &amp; Singh, M. (2020). Evaluating the efficacy of peracetic acid on Salmonella and Campylobacter on chicken wings at various pH levels. Poultry Science, 99(10), 5137&#x2013;5142. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psj.2020.06.070</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, J., Du, P., Liu, W., Luo, C., Zhao, H., &amp; Huang, C.&#x2010;H. (2020). Cobalt/peracetic acid: Advanced oxidation of aromatic organic compounds by acetylperoxyl radicals. Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 54(8), 5268&#x2013;5278. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.0c00356</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, J., Zhang, T., Liu, W., Du, P., Dobson, J. T., &amp; Huang, C.&#x2010;H. (2019). Advanced oxidation process with peracetic acid and Fe(II) for contaminant degradation. Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 53(22), 13312&#x2013;13322. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.9b02991</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitis, M. (2004). Disinfection of wastewater with peracetic acid: A review. Environment International, 30(1), 47&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0160-4120(03)00147-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koivunen, J., &amp; Heinonen&#x2010;Tanski, H. (2005). Peracetic acid (PAA) disinfection of primary, secondary and tertiary treated municipal wastewaters. Water Research, 39(18), 4445&#x2013;4453. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2005.08.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, S., Singh, M., Cosby, D. E., Cox, N. A., &amp; Thippareddi, H. (2020). Efficacy of peroxy acetic acid in reducing Salmonella and Campylobacter spp. populations on chicken breast fillets. Poultry Science, 99(5), 2655&#x2013;2661. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psj.2019.12.045</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, W.&#x2010;N., &amp; Huang, C.&#x2010;H. (2019). Formation of disinfection byproducts in wash water and lettuce by washing with sodium hypochlorite and peracetic acid sanitizers. Food Chemistry: X, 1, 100003. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fochx.2018.100003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefevre, F., Audic, J. M., &amp; Ferrand, F. (1992). Peracetic acid disinfection of secondary effluents discharged off coastal seawater. Water Science and Technology, 25(12), 155&#x2013;164. https://doi.org/10.2166/wst.1992.0347</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levels, N. R. C. (US) C. on A. E. G. (2010). Peracetic acid acute exposure guideline levels. In Acute exposure guideline levels for selected airborne chemicals: Volume 8. National Academies Press (US). https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK220001/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, R., Manoli, K., Kim, J., Feng, M., Huang, C.&#x2010;H., &amp; Sharma, V. K. (2021). Peracetic acid&#x2013;ruthenium(III) oxidation process for the degradation of micropollutants in water. Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 55(13), 9150&#x2013;9160. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.0c06676</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, D., Behrens, S., Pedersen, L.&#x2010;F., Straus, D. L., &amp; Meinelt, T. (2016). Peracetic acid is a suitable disinfectant for recirculating fish&#x2010;microalgae integrated multi&#x2010;trophic aquaculture systems. Aquaculture Reports, 4, 136&#x2013;142. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aqrep.2016.09.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lofrano, G., &amp; Brown, J. (2010). Wastewater management through the ages: A history of mankind. Science of the Total Environment, 408(22), 5254&#x2013;5264. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2010.07.062</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luca, G. D., Sacchetti, R., Zanetti, F., &amp; Leoni, E. (2008). Comparative study on the efficiency of peracetic acid and chlorine dioxide at low doses in the disinfection of urban wastewaters. Annals of Agricultural and Environmental Medicine, 15(2), 217&#x2013;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luukkonen, T., &amp; Pehkonen, S. O. (2017). Peracids in water treatment: A critical review. Critical Reviews in Environmental Science and Technology, 47(1), 1&#x2013;39. https://doi.org/10.1080/10643389.2016.1272343</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luukkonen, T., Prokkola, H., &amp; Pehkonen, S. O. (2020). Peracetic acid for conditioning of municipal wastewater sludge: Hygienization, odor control, and fertilizing properties. Waste Management, 102, 371&#x2013;379. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.wasman.2019.11.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luukkonen, T., Teeriniemi, J., Prokkola, H., Ramo, J., &amp; Lassi, U. (2014). Chemical aspects of peracetic acid based wastewater disinfection. Water SA, 40(1), 73&#x2013;80. Academic OneFile. https://doi.org/10.4314/wsa.v40i1.9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manoli, K., Sarathy, S., Maffettone, R., &amp; Santoro, D. (2019). Detailed modeling and advanced control for chemical disinfection of secondary effluent wastewater by peracetic acid. Water Research, 153, 251&#x2013;262. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2019.01.022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattle, M. J., Crouzy, B., Brennecke, M., Wigginton, K. R., Perona, P., &amp; Kohn, T. (2011). Impact of virus aggregation on inactivation by peracetic acid and implications for other disinfectants. Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 45(18), 7710&#x2013;7717. https://doi.org/10.1021/es201633s</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFadden, M., Loconsole, J., Schockling, A. J., Nerenberg, R., &amp; Pavissich, J. P. (2017). Comparing peracetic acid and hypochlorite for disinfection of combined sewer overflows: Effects of suspended&#x2010;solids and pH. Science of the Total Environment, 599&#x2013;600, 533&#x2013;539. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2017.04.179</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monarca, S. (2002). Mutagenicity and disinfection by&#x2010;products in surface drinking water disinfected with peracetic acid. Environmental Toxicology and Chemistry, 21(2), 309&#x2013;318. https://doi.org/10.1002/etc.5620210212</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otterspoor, S., &amp; Farrell, J. (2019). An evaluation of buffered peracetic acid as an alternative to chlorine and hydrogen peroxide based disinfectants. Infection, Disease &amp; Health, 24(4), 240&#x2013;243. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.idh.2019.06.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen, L.&#x2010;F., Pedersen, P. B., Nielsen, J. L., &amp; Nielsen, P. H. (2009). Peracetic acid degradation and effects on nitrification in recirculating aquaculture systems. Aquaculture, 296(3), 246&#x2013;254. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aquaculture.2009.08.021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen, P. O., Brodersen, E., &amp; Cecil, D. (2013). Disinfection of tertiary wastewater effluent prior to river discharge using peracetic acid; treatment efficiency and results on by&#x2010;products formed in full scale tests. Water Science and Technology, 68(8), 1852&#x2013;1856. https://doi.org/10.2166/wst.2013.436</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson, S. D., Plewa, M. J., Wagner, E. D., Schoeny, R., &amp; DeMarini, D. M. (2007). Occurrence, genotoxicity, and carcinogenicity of regulated and emerging disinfection by&#x2010;products in drinking water: A review and roadmap for research. Mutation Research, Reviews in Mutation Research, 636(1), 178&#x2013;242. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mrrev.2007.09.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson, S. D., &amp; Ternes, T. A. (2014). Water analysis: Emerging contaminants and current issues. Analytical Chemistry, 86(6), 2813&#x2013;2848. https://doi.org/10.1021/ac500508t</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothbart, S., Ember, E. E., &amp; van Eldik, R. (2012). Mechanistic studies on the oxidative degradation of Orange II by peracetic acid catalyzed by simple manganese(II) salts. Tuning the lifetime of the catalyst. New Journal of Chemistry, 36(3), 732&#x2013;748. https://doi.org/10.1039/C2NJ20852K</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaefer, K., Exall, K., &amp; Marsalek, J. (2004). Water reuse and recycling in Canada: A status and needs assessment. Canadian Water Resources Journal, 15, 195&#x2013;208. https://doi.org/10.4296/cwrj195</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, X., Sheng, L., Gao, H., Hanrahan, I., Suslow, T. V., &amp; Zhu, M.&#x2010;J. (2019). Enhanced efficacy of peroxyacetic acid against Listeria monocytogenes on fresh apples at elevated temperature. Frontiers in Microbiology, 10, 1196&#x2013;1205. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2019.01196</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer&#x2010;Williams, I. (2021, September 14). Dataset for examining the antimicrobial efficacy of granulated tetraacetylethylenediamine (TAED) derived peracetic acid and commercial peracetic acid in urban wastewaters [data repository]. Zenodo. https://zenodo.org/deposit/5198756, https://doi.org/10.1002/wer.10688</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stampi, S., Luca, G. D., &amp; Zanetti, F. (2001). Evaluation of the efficiency of peracetic acid in the disinfection of sewage effluents. Journal of Applied Microbiology, 91(5), 833&#x2013;838. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365-2672.2001.01451.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, P., Zhang, T., Mejia&#x2010;Tickner, B., Zhang, R., Cai, M., &amp; Huang, C.&#x2010;H. (2018). Rapid disinfection by peracetic acid combined with UV irradiation. Environmental Science &amp; Technology Letters, 5(6), 400&#x2013;404. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.estlett.8b00249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suurn&#xe4;kki, S., Pulkkinen, J. T., Lindholm&#x2010;Lehto, P. C., Tiirola, M., &amp; Aalto, S. L. (2020). The effect of peracetic acid on microbial community, water quality, nitrification and rainbow trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss) performance in recirculating aquaculture systems. Aquaculture, 516, 734534. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aquaculture.2019.734534</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USDA. (2016). Peracetic acid: Handling/processing [Technical Evaluation Report]. https://www.ams.usda.gov/sites/default/files/media/Peracetic%20Acid%20TR%203_3_2016%20Handling%20final.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA. (1976). Disinfection of wastewater: Task force report (p. 65). https://nepis.epa.gov/Exe/ZyNET.exe/9101F9QT.TXT?ZyActionD=ZyDocument&amp;Client=EPA&amp;Index=1976%2BThru%2B1980&amp;Docs=&amp;Query=&amp;Time=&amp;EndTime=&amp;SearchMethod=1&amp;TocRestrict=n&amp;Toc=&amp;TocEntry=&amp;QField=&amp;QFieldYear=&amp;QFieldMonth=&amp;QFieldDay=&amp;IntQFieldOp=0&amp;ExtQFieldOp=0&amp;XmlQuery=&amp;File=D%3A%5Czyfiles%5CIndex%20Data%5C76thru80%5CTxt%5C00000029%5C9101F9QT.txt&amp;User=ANONYMOUS&amp;Password=anonymous&amp;SortMethod=h%7C&#x2010;&amp;MaximumDocuments=1&amp;FuzzyDegree=0&amp;ImageQuality=r75g8/r75g8/x150y150g16/i425&amp;Display=hpfr&amp;DefSeekPage=x&amp;SearchBack=ZyActionL&amp;Back=ZyActionS&amp;BackDesc=Results%20page&amp;MaximumPages=1&amp;ZyEntry=1&amp;SeekPage=x&amp;ZyPURL#</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA. (1983, March). EPA 600/4&#x2010;79&#x2010;020 methods for chemical analysis of water and wastes. https://www.wbdg.org/FFC/EPA/EPACRIT/epa600_4_79_020.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA. (1986). Quality criteria for water.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA. (1999). Wastewater technology fact sheet: Chlorine disinfection [fact sheet]. Office of Water. https://www3.epa.gov/npdes/pubs/chlo.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA. (2002). Method 1604: Total coliforms and Escherichia coli in water by membrane filtration using a simultaneous detection technique (MI medium). USEPA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA. (2012a). 2012 Guidelines for Water Reuse. 643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA. (2012b). Recreational water quality criteria. Office of Water.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA. (2015). National pollution discharge elimination system&#x2014;Water quality based permits for recreational water criteria.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA. (2018). Total chlorine DPD method.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veschetti, E., Cutilli, D., Bonadonna, L., Briancesco, R., Martini, C., Cecchini, G., Anastasi, P., &amp; Ottaviani, M. (2003). Pilot&#x2010;plant comparative study of peracetic acid and sodium hypochlorite wastewater disinfection. Water Research, 37(1), 78&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0043-1354(02)00248-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner, M., Brumelis, D., &amp; Gehr, R. (2002). Disinfection of wastewater by hydrogen peroxide or peracetic acid: Development of procedures for measurement of residual disinfectant and application to a physicochemically treated municipal effluent. Water Environment Research, 74(1), 33&#x2013;50. JSTOR. https://doi.org/10.2175/106143002X139730</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Fu, Y., Peng, Y., Wang, S., &amp; Liu, Y. (2021). HCO3&#x2212;/CO32&#x2212; enhanced degradation of diclofenac by Cu(II)&#x2010;activated peracetic acid: Efficiency and mechanism. Separation and Purification Technology, 277, 119434. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2021.119434</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Water Environment Federation. (2020). Peracetic acid disinfection: Implementation considerations for water resource recovery facilities (1st ed.). Water Environment Federation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoganarasimha, S., Trahan, W. R., Best, A. M., Bowlin, G. L., Kitten, T. O., Moon, P. C., &amp; Madurantakam, P. A. (2014). Peracetic acid: A practical agent for sterilizing heat&#x2010;labile polymeric tissue&#x2010;engineering scaffolds. Tissue Engineering Part C: Methods, 20(9), 714&#x2013;723. https://doi.org/10.1089/ten.tec.2013.0624</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, Z., Ni, Y., &amp; Heiningen, A. R. P. V. (1997). Kinetics of the peracetic acid decomposition: Part II: pH effect and alkaline hydrolysis. The Canadian Journal of Chemical Engineering, 75(1), 42&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.1002/cjce.5450750109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanetti, F., De Luca, G., Sacchetti, R., &amp; Stampi, S. (2007). Disinfection efficiency of peracetic acid (PAA): Inactivation of coliphages and bacterial indicators in a municipal wastewater plant. Environmental Technology, 28, 1265&#x2013;1271. https://doi.org/10.1080/09593332808618886</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, X., Cheng, K., Hao, J., &amp; Liu, D. (2008). Preparation of peracetic acid from hydrogen peroxide, part II: Kinetics for spontaneous decomposition of peracetic acid in the liquid phase. Journal of Molecular Catalysis A: Chemical, 284(1), 58&#x2013;68. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molcata.2008.01.003</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>