<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35130884</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1423-0127</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of biomedical science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Biomed Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An auto-antibody identified from phenotypic directed screening platform shows host immunity against EV-A71 infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>10</StartPage><MedlinePgn>10</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12929-022-00794-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Enterovirus A71 (EV-A71) is a neurotropic virus which may cause severe neural complications, especially in infants and children. The clinical manifestations include hand-foot-and-mouth disease, herpangina, brainstem encephalitis, pulmonary edema, and other severe neurological diseases. Although there are some vaccines approved, the post-marketing surveillance is still unavailable. In addition, there is no antiviral drugs against EV-A71 available.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this study, we identified a novel antibody that could inhibit viral growth through a human single chain variable fragment (scFv) library expressed in mammalian cells and panned by infection with lethal dose of EV-A71.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We identified that the host protein &#x3b1;-enolase (ENO1) is the target of this scFv, and anti-ENO1 antibody was found to be more in mild cases than severe EV-A71 cases. Furthermore, we examined the antiviral activity in a mouse model. We found that the treatment of the identified 07-human IgG<sub>1</sub> antibody increased the survival rate after virus challenge, and significantly decreased the viral RNA and the level of neural pathology in brain tissue.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Collectively, through a promising intracellular scFv library expression and screening system, we found a potential scFv/antibody which targets host protein ENO1 and can interfere with the infection of EV-A71. The results indicate that the usage and application of this antibody may offer a potential treatment against EV-A71 infection.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Wei</ForeName><Initials>YW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Institute of Basic Medical Sciences, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Leadgene Biomedical, Inc., Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chuang</LastName><ForeName>Yung-Chun</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Leadgene Biomedical, Inc., Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Science and Biotechnology, College of Medicine, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Sheng-Wen</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Mosquito-Borne Diseases Control Research Center, National Health Research Institutes, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Ching-Chuan</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, National Cheng Kung University Hospital, College of Medicine, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Infectious Disease and Signaling Research, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jen-Ren</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4127-4046</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Institute of Basic Medical Sciences, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan, Taiwan. jrwang@mail.ncku.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Science and Biotechnology, College of Medicine, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan, Taiwan. jrwang@mail.ncku.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Infectious Disease and Signaling Research, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan, Taiwan. jrwang@mail.ncku.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Infectious Diseases and Vaccinology, National Health Research Institutes, Tainan, Taiwan. jrwang@mail.ncku.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MOST 109-2320-B-006-053</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Science and Technology, Taiwan</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MOST 110-2320-B-006-053</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Science and Technology, Taiwan</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Biomed Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9421567</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1021-7770</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000998">Antiviral Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000998" MajorTopicYN="N">Antiviral Agents</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibody</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ENO1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EV-A71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scFv</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35130884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8822709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12929-022-00794-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12929-022-00794-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Liu CC. Update of enterovirus 71 infection: epidemiology, pathogenesis and vaccine. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2014;12(4):447&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24579906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. Enterovirus vaccines for an emerging cause of brain-stem encephalitis. N Engl J Med. 2014;370(9):792&#x2013;794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, Twu SJ, Chen KT, Tsai SF, et al. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N Engl J Med. 1999;341(13):929&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogozin IB, Solovyov VV, Kolchanov NA. Somatic hypermutagenesis in immunoglobulin genes. I. Correlation between somatic mutations and repeats. Somatic mutation properties and clonal selection. Biochem Biophys Acta. 1991;1089(2):175&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2054380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Chang J, Chen Y, Wan B, Wang Y, Zhang G. Construction of a human scFv antibody library with VH regions randomized and its application. Biotech Lett. 2012;34(7):1203&#x2013;1208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22421974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulkeaw K, Sakolvaree Y, Srimanote P, Tongtawe P, Maneewatch S, Sookrung N, et al. Human monoclonal ScFv neutralize lethal Thai cobra, Naja kaouthia, neurotoxin. J Proteomics. 2009;72(2):270&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19162253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukhtar MM, Li S, Li W, Wan T, Mu Y, Wei W, et al. Single-chain intracellular antibodies inhibit influenza virus replication by disrupting interaction of proteins involved in viral replication and transcription. Int J Biochem Cell Biol. 2009;41(3):554&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18687409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan L, Laughlin MA, Oakes JW, Pomerantz RJ. Potent inhibition of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 replication by an intracellular anti-Rev single-chain antibody. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1998;95(17):10344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC56214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12465612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marasco WA, LaVecchio J, Winkler A. Human anti-HIV-1 tat sFv intrabodies for gene therapy of advanced HIV-1-infection and AIDS. J Immunol Methods. 1999;231(1&#x2013;2):223&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10648940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho NC, Williamson RA, Parren PW, Lundkvist A, Burton DR, Bjorling E. Neutralizing human Fab fragments against measles virus recovered by phage display. J Virol. 2002;76(1):251&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC135717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11739690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vascotto F, Campagna M, Visintin M, Cattaneo A, Burrone OR. Effects of intrabodies specific for rotavirus NSP5 during the virus replicative cycle. J Gen Virol. 2004;85(Pt 11):3285&#x2013;3290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15483242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazuc E, Guglielmi L, Bec N, Parez V, Hahn CS, Mollevi C, et al. In-cell intrabody selection from a diverse human library identifies C12orf4 protein as a new player in rodent mast cell degranulation. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(8):e104998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4133367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25122211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winter G, Griffiths AD, Hawkins RE, Hoogenboom HR. Making antibodies by phage display technology. Annu Rev Immunol. 1994;12:433&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8011287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willats WG. Phage display: practicalities and prospects. Plant Mol Biol. 2002;50(6):837&#x2013;854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12516857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang JX, Bishop-Hurley SL, Cooper MA. Development of anti-infectives using phage display: biological agents against bacteria, viruses, and parasites. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2012;56(9):4569&#x2013;4582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3421897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22664969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parray HA, Chiranjivi AK, Asthana S, Yadav N, Shrivastava T, Mani S, et al. Identification of an anti-SARS-CoV-2 receptor-binding domain-directed human monoclonal antibody from a naive semisynthetic library. J Biol Chem. 2020;295(36):12814&#x2013;12821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7476711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32727845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prins M, Lohuis D, Schots A, Goldbach R. Phage display-selected single-chain antibodies confer high levels of resistance against Tomato spotted wilt virus. J Gen Virol. 2005;86(Pt 7):2107&#x2013;2113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15958689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deutscher SL. Phage display in molecular imaging and diagnosis of cancer. Chem Rev. 2010;110(5):3196&#x2013;3211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2868952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20170129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Gao S, Lv J, Lin Y, Zhou L, Han L. Phage display technology and its applications in cancer immunotherapy. Anticancer Agents Med Chem. 2019;19(2):229&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30370861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Kang J, Wang X, Wei W, Jiang W. Phage display screening identifies a novel peptide to suppress ovarian cancer cells in vitro and in vivo in mouse models. BMC Cancer. 2015;15:889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4641363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26555399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira D, Silva AP, Nobrega FL, Martins IM, Barbosa-Matos C, Granja S, et al. Rational identification of a colorectal cancer targeting peptide through phage display. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):3958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6408488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30850705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie J, Yea K, Zhang H, Moldt B, He L, Zhu J, et al. Prevention of cell death by antibodies selected from intracellular combinatorial libraries. Chem Biol. 2014;21(2):274&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24440080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCafferty J. Phenotypic directed antibody selection. Chem Biol. 2014;21(2):170&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24560164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu DT, Seita Y, Zhang X, Lu CW, Roth MJ. Antibody-directed lentiviral gene transduction for live-cell monitoring and selection of human iPS and hES cells. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(4):e34778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3334894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22536330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SW, Tai CH, Fonville JM, Lin CH, Wang SM, Liu CC, et al. Mapping enterovirus A71 antigenic determinants from viral evolution. J Virol. 2015;89(22):11500&#x2013;11506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4645677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26339057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SW, Wang YF, Yu CK, Su IJ, Wang JR. Mutations in VP2 and VP1 capsid proteins increase infectivity and mouse lethality of enterovirus 71 by virus binding and RNA accumulation enhancement. Virology. 2012;422(1):132&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22078110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andris-Widhopf J, Steinberger P, Fuller R, Rader C, Barbas CF, 3rd. Generation of human scFv antibody libraries: PCR amplification and assembly of light- and heavy-chain coding sequences. Cold Spring Harbor protocols. 2011;2011(9).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21880816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. WHO manual on animal influenza diagnosis and surveillance. World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland.; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitrov JD, Planchais C, Roumenina LT, Vassilev TL, Kaveri SV, Lacroix-Desmazes S. Antibody polyreactivity in health and disease: statu variabilis. J Immunol. 2013;191(3):993&#x2013;999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23873158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin JY, Li ML, Huang PN, Chien KY, Horng JT, Shih SR. Heterogeneous nuclear ribonuclear protein K interacts with the enterovirus 71 5&#x2019; untranslated region and participates in virus replication. J Gen Virol. 2008;89(Pt 10):2540&#x2013;2549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18796723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih SR, Stollar V, Li ML. Host factors in enterovirus 71 replication. J Virol. 2011;85(19):9658&#x2013;9666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21715481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo RL, Lin YH, Wang RY, Hsu CW, Chiu YT, Huang HI, et al. Proteomics analysis of EV71-infected cells reveals the involvement of host protein NEDD4L in EV71 replication. J Proteome Res. 2015;14(4):1818&#x2013;1830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25785312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Ramos A, Roig-Borrellas A, Garcia-Melero A, Lopez-Alemany R. alpha-Enolase, a multifunctional protein: its role on pathophysiological situations. J Biomed Biotechnol. 2012;2012:156795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3479624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23118496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kishimoto N, Yamamoto K, Iga N, Kirihara C, Abe T, Takamune N, et al. Alpha-enolase in viral target cells suppresses the human immunodeficiency virus type 1 integration. Retrovirology. 2020;17(1):31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7488571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32917235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kishimoto N, Yamamoto K, Abe T, Yasuoka N, Takamune N, Misumi S. Glucose-dependent aerobic glycolysis contributes to recruiting viral components into HIV-1 particles to maintain infectivity. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2021;549:187&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33676187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong WF, Chow VT. Transcriptomic and proteomic analyses of rhabdomyosarcoma cells reveal differential cellular gene expression in response to enterovirus 71 infection. Cell Microbiol. 2006;8(4):565&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7162300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16548883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan SY, Sam IC, Lai JK, Chan YF. Cellular proteome alterations in response to enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 infections in neuronal and intestinal cell lines. J Proteomics. 2015;125:121&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26003530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Too IHK, Bonne I, Tan EL, Chu JJH, Alonso S. Prohibitin plays a critical role in Enterovirus 71 neuropathogenesis. PLoS Pathog. 2018;14(1):e1006778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5764453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29324904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang-Chun D, Xiao-Qing Y, Ting-Ting Y, Zhen-Hui L, Xiao-Yan L, Xia L, et al. Alpha-enolase regulates hepatitis B virus replication through suppression of the interferon signalling pathway. J Viral Hepat. 2018;25(3):289&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29080231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles LA, Dahlberg CM, Plescia J, Felez J, Kato K, Plow EF. Role of cell-surface lysines in plasminogen binding to cells: identification of alpha-enolase as a candidate plasminogen receptor. Biochemistry. 1991;30(6):1682&#x2013;1691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1847072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudani AK, Cummings C, Hashemi S, Ganz PR. Isolation of a novel 45 kDa plasminogen receptor from human endothelial cells. Thromb Res. 1993;69(2):185&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8383363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aaronson RM, Graven KK, Tucci M, McDonald RJ, Farber HW. Non-neuronal enolase is an endothelial hypoxic stress protein. J Biol Chem. 1995;270(46):27752&#x2013;27757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7499243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Miller DM. Structural analysis of alpha-enolase. Mapping the functional domains involved in down-regulation of the c-myc protooncogene. J Biol Chem. 2000;275(8):5958&#x2013;5965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10681589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niklinski J, Furman M. Clinical tumour markers in lung cancer. Eur J Cancer Prev. 1995;4(2):129&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7539317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledermann JA. Serum neurone-specific enolase and other neuroendocrine markers in lung cancer. Eur J Cancer. 1994;30A(5):574&#x2013;576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8080666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksson B, Oberg K, Stridsberg M. Tumor markers in neuroendocrine tumors. Digestion. 2000;62(Suppl 1):33&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10940685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takashima M, Kuramitsu Y, Yokoyama Y, Iizuka N, Fujimoto M, Nishisaka T, et al. Overexpression of alpha enolase in hepatitis C virus-related hepatocellular carcinoma: association with tumor progression as determined by proteomic analysis. Proteomics. 2005;5(6):1686&#x2013;1692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15800975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Y, Kuhn C, Kosters M, Arnold GJ, Ishikawa-Ankerhold H, Schulz C, et al. Anti alpha-enolase antibody is a novel autoimmune biomarker for unexplained recurrent miscarriages. EBioMedicine. 2019;41:610&#x2013;622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6444073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30827932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akisawa N, Maeda T, Iwasaki S, Onishi S. Identification of an autoantibody against alpha-enolase in primary biliary cirrhosis. J Hepatol. 1997;26(4):845&#x2013;851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9126798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saulot V, Vittecoq O, Charlionet R, Fardellone P, Lange C, Marvin L, et al. Presence of autoantibodies to the glycolytic enzyme alpha-enolase in sera from patients with early rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis Rheum. 2002;46(5):1196&#x2013;1201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12115223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae S, Kim H, Lee N, Won C, Kim HR, Hwang YI, et al. alpha-Enolase expressed on the surfaces of monocytes and macrophages induces robust synovial inflammation in rheumatoid arthritis. J Immunol. 2012;189(1):365&#x2013;372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22623332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih NY, Lai HL, Chang GC, Lin HC, Wu YC, Liu JM, et al. Anti-alpha-enolase autoantibodies are down-regulated in advanced cancer patients. Jpn J Clin Oncol. 2010;40(7):663&#x2013;669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20395242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Wang H, Dong X. Diagnostic value of alpha-enolase expression and serum alpha-enolase autoantibody levels in lung cancer. J Bras Pneumol. 2018;44(1):18&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6130332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29538538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai L, Qu Y, Li J, Wang X, Wang K, Wang P, et al. Serological proteome analysis approach-based identification of ENO1 as a tumor-associated antigen and its autoantibody could enhance the sensitivity of CEA and CYFRA 21&#x2013;1 in the detection of non-small cell lung cancer. Oncotarget. 2017;8(22):36664&#x2013;36673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5482686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28456790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han L, Li K, Jin C, Wang J, Li Q, Zhang Q, et al. Human enterovirus 71 protein interaction network prompts antiviral drug repositioning. Sci Rep. 2017;7:43143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5318855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28220872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou P, Yang Y, Xu X, Liu B, Mei F, You J, et al. Silencing of vacuolar ATPase c subunit ATP6V0C inhibits the invasion of prostate cancer cells through a LASS2/TMSG1-independent manner. Oncol Rep. 2018;39(1):298&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29138865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sennoune SR, Luo D, Martinez-Zaguilan R. Plasmalemmal vacuolar-type H+-ATPase in cancer biology. Cell Biochem Biophys. 2004;40(2):185&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15054222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng B, Huang X, Nakayasu ES, Petersen JR, Qiu S, Almeida IC, et al. Using immunoproteomics to identify alpha-enolase as an autoantigen in liver fibrosis. J Proteome Res. 2013;12(4):1789&#x2013;1796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3743961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23458688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu BR, Brindley SM, Tucker RM, Lambert CL, Mack CL. alpha-enolase autoantibodies cross-reactive to viral proteins in a mouse model of biliary atresia. Gastroenterology. 2010;139(5):1753&#x2013;1761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3792016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20659472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthony RM, Wermeling F, Karlsson MC, Ravetch JV. Identification of a receptor required for the anti-inflammatory activity of IVIG. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2008;105(50):19571&#x2013;19578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2604916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19036920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han JF, Cao RY, Deng YQ, Tian X, Jiang T, Qin ED, et al. Antibody dependent enhancement infection of enterovirus 71 in vitro and in vivo. Virol J. 2011;8:106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3060144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21385398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiramel AI, Brady NR, Bartenschlager R. Divergent roles of autophagy in virus infection. Cells. 2013;2(1):83&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3972664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24709646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SC, Chang CL, Wang PS, Tsai Y, Liu HS. Enterovirus 71-induced autophagy detected in vitro and in vivo promotes viral replication. J Med Virol. 2009;81(7):1241&#x2013;1252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7166624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19475621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xi X, Zhang X, Wang B, Wang T, Wang J, Huang H, et al. The interplays between autophagy and apoptosis induced by enterovirus 71. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(2):e56966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3577684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23437282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu X, Cao KY, Liu HQ, Yu L, Sun LX, Yang ZH, et al. Alpha-enolase (ENO1), identified as an antigen to monoclonal antibody 12C7, promotes the self-renewal and malignant phenotype of lung cancer stem cells by AMPK/mTOR pathway. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2021;12(1):119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7881626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33579362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao F, Zhang M, Chen L. 5&#x2019;-Monophosphate-activated protein kinase (AMPK) improves autophagic activity in diabetes and diabetic complications. Acta Pharm Sin B. 2016;6(1):20&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4724658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26904395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Didiasova M, Schaefer L, Wygrecka M. When place matters: shuttling of enolase-1 across cellular compartments. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2019;7:61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6498095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31106201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baixauli F, Lopez-Otin C, Mittelbrunn M. Exosomes and autophagy: coordinated mechanisms for the maintenance of cellular fitness. Front Immunol. 2014;5:403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4138502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25191326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojha CR, Lapierre J, Rodriguez M, Dever SM, Zadeh MA, DeMarino C, et al. Interplay between autophagy, exosomes and HIV-1 associated neurological disorders: new insights for diagnosis and therapeutic applications. Viruses. 2017;9(7):176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5537668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28684681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salimi L, Akbari A, Jabbari N, Mojarad B, Vahhabi A, Szafert S, et al. Synergies in exosomes and autophagy pathways for cellular homeostasis and metastasis of tumor cells. Cell Biosci. 2020;10:64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7218515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32426106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappello P, Principe M, Bulfamante S, Novelli F. Alpha-Enolase (ENO1), a potential target in novel immunotherapies. Front Biosci (Landmark Ed) 2017;22:944&#x2013;959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27814656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>