<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35474513</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>94</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cell pyroptosis in picornavirus and its potential for treating viral infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3570</StartPage><EndPage>3580</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3570-3580</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.27813</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cell pyroptosis has received increased attention due to the associations between innate immunity and disease, and it has become a major focal point recently due to in-depth studies of cancer. With increased research on pyroptosis, scientists have discovered that it has an essential role in viral infections, especially in the occurrence and development of some picornavirus infections. Many picornaviruses, including Coxsackievirus, a71 enterovirus, human rhinovirus, encephalomyocarditis virus, and foot-and-mouth disease virus induce pyroptosis to varying degrees. This review summarized the mechanisms by which these viruses induce cell pyroptosis, which can be an effective defense against pathogen infection. However, excessive inflammasome activation or pyroptosis also can damage the host's health or aggravate disease progression. Careful approaches that acknowledge this dual effect will aid in the exploration of picornavirus infections and the mechanisms that produce the inflammatory response. This information will promote the development of drugs that can inhibit cell pyroptosis and provide new avenues for future clinical treatment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Medicine, Nanchang University, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Queen Mary of Nanchang University, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Haolin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Medicine, Nanchang University, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Ophthalmology and Optometry of Nanchang University, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhuang</LastName><ForeName>Wenyue</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Medicine, Nanchang University, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, The Second Clinical Medical College of Nanchang University, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jingxuan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Medicine, Nanchang University, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Ophthalmology and Optometry of Nanchang University, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Medicine, Nanchang University, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Ophthalmology and Optometry of Nanchang University, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Zhicheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Medicine, Nanchang University, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaotian</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Medicine, Nanchang University, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Qiong</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8950-6133</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, School of Medicine, Nanchang University, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058847">Inflammasomes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000071199">NLR Family, Pyrin Domain-Containing 3 Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058847" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammasomes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071199" MajorTopicYN="N">NLR Family, Pyrin Domain-Containing 3 Protein</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010849" MajorTopicYN="Y">Picornaviridae</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010850" MajorTopicYN="Y">Picornaviridae Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069292" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyroptosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014777" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014779" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Replication</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NLRP3 inflammasome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caspase-1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">picornavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pyroptosis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35474513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.27813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Fischer FA, Chen KW, Bezbradica JS. Posttranslational and therapeutic control of gasdermin-mediated pyroptosis and inflammation. Front Immunol. 2021;12:661162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tapparel C, Siegrist F, Petty TJ, Kaiser L. Picornavirus and enterovirus diversity with associated human diseases. Infect Genet Evol. 2013;14:282-293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sborgi L, R&#xfc;hl S, Mulvihill E, et al. GSDMD membrane pore formation constitutes the mechanism of pyroptotic cell death. EMBO J. 2016;35(16):1766-1778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Zhang Z, Ruan J, et al. Inflammasome-activated gasdermin D causes pyroptosis by forming membrane pores. Nature. 2016;535(7610):153-158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding J, Wang K, Liu W, et al. Pore-forming activity and structural autoinhibition of the gasdermin family. Nature. 2016;535(7610):111-116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strowig T, Henao-Mejia J, Elinav E, Flavell R. Inflammasomes in health and disease. Nature. 2012;481(7381):278-286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedlander AM. Macrophages are sensitive to anthrax lethal toxin through an acid-dependent process. J Biol Chem. 1986;261(16):7123-7126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cookson BT, Brennan MA. Pro-inflammatory programmed cell death. Trends Microbiol. 2001;9(3):113-114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu P, Zhang X, Liu N, Tang L, Peng C, Chen X. Pyroptosis: mechanisms and diseases. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2021;6(1):128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarhan J, Liu BC, Muendlein HI, et al. Caspase-8 induces cleavage of gasdermin D to elicit pyroptosis during Yersinia infection. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2018;115(46):E10888-E10897.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liston A, Masters SL. Homeostasis-altering molecular processes as mechanisms of inflammasome activation. Nat Rev Immunol. 2017;17(3):208-214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamkanfi M, Dixit VM. Mechanisms and functions of inflammasomes. Cell. 2014;157(5):1013-1022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupfer CR, Anand PK, Qi X, Zaki H. Editorial: role of NOD-like receptors in infectious and immunological diseases. Front Immunol. 2020;11:923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Man SM, Kanneganti TD. Regulation of inflammasome activation. Immunol Rev. 2015;265(1):6-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yogarajah T, Ong KC, Perera D, Wong KT. AIM2 inflammasome-mediated pyroptosis in enterovirus A71-infected neuronal cells restricts viral replication. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):5845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma D, Kanneganti TD. The cell biology of inflammasomes: mechanisms of inflammasome activation and regulation. J Cell Biol. 2016;213(6):617-629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aglietti RA, Estevez A, Gupta A, et al. GsdmD p30 elicited by caspase-11 during pyroptosis forms pores in membranes. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2016;113(28):7858-7863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He WT, Wan H, Hu L, et al. Gasdermin D is an executor of pyroptosis and required for interleukin-1beta secretion. Cell Res. 2015;25(12):1285-1298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J, Zhao Y, Wang Y, et al. Inflammatory caspases are innate immune receptors for intracellular LPS. Nature. 2014;514(7521):187-192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Zhang Y, Lieberman J. Lighting a fire: can we harness pyroptosis to ignite antitumor immunity? Cancer Immunol Res. 2021;9(1):2-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Zhang Y, Xia S, et al. Gasdermin E suppresses tumour growth by activating anti-tumour immunity. Nature. 2020;579(7799):415-420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang M, Qi L, Li L, Li Y. The caspase-3/GSDME signal pathway as a switch between apoptosis and pyroptosis in cancer. Cell Death Discov. 2020;6:112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z, He H, Wang K, et al. Granzyme A from cytotoxic lymphocytes cleaves GSDMB to trigger pyroptosis in target cells. Science. 2020;368(6494):eaaz7548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertheloot D, Latz E, Franklin BS. Necroptosis, pyroptosis and apoptosis: an intricate game of cell death. Cell Mol Immunol. 2021;18(5):1106-1121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickman G, Julian L, Olson MF. How apoptotic cells aid in the removal of their own cold dead bodies. Cell Death Differ. 2012;19(5):735-742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaczanowski S. Apoptosis: its origin, history, maintenance and the medical implications for cancer and aging. Phys Biol. 2016;13(3):031001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirschhorn T, Stockwell BR. The development of the concept of ferroptosis. Free Radic Biol Med. 2019;133:130-143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchiya K. Switching from apoptosis to pyroptosis: gasdermin-elicited inflammation and antitumor immunity. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(1)&#x200b;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, He W, Hu L, et al. Pyroptosis is driven by non-selective gasdermin-D pore and its morphology is different from MLKL channel-mediated necroptosis. Cell Res. 2016;26(9):1007-1020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang R, Xu J, Zhang B, et al. Ferroptosis, necroptosis, and pyroptosis in anticancer immunity. J Hematol Oncol. 2020;13(1):110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nord&#xe9;n R, Nystr&#xf6;m K, Aurelius J, Brisslert M, Olofsson S. Virus-induced appearance of the selectin ligand sLeX in herpes simplex virus type 1-infected T-cells: involvement of host and viral factors. Glycobiology. 2013;23(3):310-321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ampomah PB, Lim LHK. Influenza A virus-induced apoptosis and virus propagation. Apoptosis. 2020;25(1-2):1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herold S, Ludwig S, Pleschka S, Wolff T. Apoptosis signaling in influenza virus propagation, innate host defense, and lung injury. J Leukoc Biol. 2012;92(1):75-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mocarski ES, Kaiser WJ, Livingston-Rosanoff D, Upton JW, Daley-Bauer LP. True grit: programmed necrosis in antiviral host defense, inflammation, and immunogenicity. J Immunol. 2014;192(5):2019-2026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upton JW, Shubina M, Balachandran S. RIPK3-driven cell death during virus infections. Immunol Rev. 2017;277(1):90-101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balachandran S, Rall GF. Benefits and perils of necroptosis in influenza virus infection. J Virol. 2020;94(9)&#x200b;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habib HM, Ibrahim S, Zaim A, Ibrahim WH. The role of iron in the pathogenesis of COVID-19 and possible treatment with lactoferrin and other iron chelators. Biomed Pharmacother. 2021;136:111228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haque S, Lan X, Wen H, et al. HIV promotes NLRP3 inflammasome complex activation in murine HIV-associated nephropathy. Am J Pathol. 2016;186(2):347-358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo X, Herzig E, Doitsh G, Grimmett ZW, Mu&#xf1;oz-Arias I, Greene WC. HIV-2 depletes CD4 T cells through pyroptosis despite vpx-dependent degradation of SAMHD1. J Virol. 2019;93(24)&#x200b;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan S, Yuan J, Deng S, et al. Activation of interleukin-1beta release by the classical swine fever virus is dependent on the NLRP3 inflammasome, which affects virus growth in monocytes. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2018;8:225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Church JA. Cell death by pyroptosis drives CD4 T-cell depletion in HIV-1 infection. Pediatrics. 2014;134(Suppl 3):S183-S184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao J, Sun T, Yue Y, Xiong S. Macrophage NLRP3 inflammasome activated by CVB3 capsid proteins contributes to the development of viral myocarditis. Mol Immunol. 2019;114:41-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi L, Kamada N, Nakamura Y, et al. NLRC4-driven production of IL-1beta discriminates between pathogenic and commensal bacteria and promotes host intestinal defense. Nat Immunol. 2012;13(5):449-456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurston TLM, Matthews SA, Jennings E, et al. Growth inhibition of cytosolic Salmonella by caspase-1 and caspase-11 precedes host cell death. Nat Commun. 2016;7:13292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kofahi HM, Taylor NG, Hirasawa K, Grant MD, Russell RS. Hepatitis C virus infection of cultured human hepatoma cells causes apoptosis and pyroptosis in both infected and bystander cells. Sci Rep. 2016;6:37433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peischard S, et al. A kidnapping story how coxsackievirus B3 and its host cell interact. Cell Physiol Biochem. 2019;53(1):121-140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, et al. Inhibition of calpain alleviates coxsackievirus B3-induced myocarditis through suppressing the canonical NLRP3 inflammasome casp. Am J Transl Res. 2020;12(5):1954-1964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Qin Y, Wang T, et al. Pyroptosis induced by enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus B3 infection affects viral replication and host response. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):2887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Gao B, Xiong S. Involvement of NLRP3 inflammasome in CVB3-induced viral myocarditis. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2014;307(10):H1438-H1447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Jia L, Shen J, et al. Cathepsin B aggravates coxsackievirus B3-induced myocarditis through activating the inflammasome and promoting pyroptosis. PLoS Pathog. 2018;14(1):e1006872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathinayake PS, Hsu AC, Wark PA. Innate immunity and immune evasion by enterovirus 71. Viruses. 2015;7(12):6613-6630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lind K, Svedin E, Domsgen E, et al. Coxsackievirus counters the host innate immune response by blocking type III interferon expression. J Gen Virol. 2016;97(6):1368-1380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury SM, Ma X, Abdullah SW, Zheng H. Activation and Inhibition of the NLRP3 Inflammasome by RNA Viruses. J Inflamm Res. 2021;14(1):1145-1163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Liu CC. Update of enterovirus 71 infection epidemiology, pathogenesis and vaccine. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2014;12(4):447-456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Lei X, Xiao X, et al. Reciprocal regulation between enterovirus 71 and the NLRP3 inflammasome. Cell Rep. 2015;12(1):42-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X, Wu T, Chi Y, et al. Pyroptosis induced by enterovirus A71 infection in cultured human neuroblastoma cells. Virology. 2018;521:69-76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen W, Qi Z, Wang J. The function and mechanism of enterovirus 71 (EV71) 3C protease. Curr Microbiol. 2020;77(9):1968-1975.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei X, Zhang Z, Xiao X, Qi J, He B, Wang J. Enterovirus 71 inhibits pyroptosis through cleavage of gasdermin D. J Virol. 2017;91(18)&#x200b;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Xu B, Ma Y, Shang L, Ye S, Wang Y. Reversible covalent inhibitors suppress enterovirus 71 infection by targeting the 3C protease. Antiviral Res. 2021;192:105102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Z, Lemon SM. Innate immunity to enteric hepatitis viruses. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2019;9(3):a033464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng H, Lenarcic EM, Yamane D, et al. NLRX1 promotes immediate IRF1-directed antiviral responses by limiting dsRNA-activated translational inhibition mediated by PKR. Nat Immunol. 2017;18(12):1299-1309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K, Wang C, Yang F, Cao W, Zhu Z, Zheng H. Virus-host interactions in foot-and-mouth disease virus infection. Front Immunol. 2021;12:571509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triantafilou K, Kar S, van Kuppeveld FJM, Triantafilou M. Rhinovirus-induced calcium flux triggers NLRP3 and NLRC5 activation in bronchial cells. Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol. 2013;49(6):923-934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ao D, Guo HC, Sun SQ, et al. Viroporin activity of the foot-and-mouth disease virus non-structural 2B protein. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(5):e0125828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Zhai X, Chen Y, et al. Protein 2B of coxsackievirus B3 induces autophagy relying on its transmembrane hydrophobic sequences. Viruses. 2016;8(5)&#x200b;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhi X, Zhang Y, Sun S, et al. NLRP3 inflammasome activation by foot-and-mouth disease virus infection mainly induced by viral RNA and non-structural protein 2B. RNA Biol. 2020;17(3):335-349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu QY, et al. A role for mitochondria in NLRP3 inflammasome activation. Nature. 2018;469(7329):221-225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladue DP, Largo E, de la Arada I, et al. Molecular characterization of the viroporin function of foot-and-mouth disease virus nonstructural protein 2B. J Virol. 2018;92(23):e01360-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Church JA. Cell death by pyroptosis drives CD4 T cell depletion in HIV 1 infection. Pediatrics. 2014;134(Suppl 3):S184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Z, An S, Chen J, et al. Neural progenitor cell pyroptosis contributes to Zika virus-induced brain atrophy and represents a therapeutic target. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2020;117(38):23869-23878.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yap JKY, Moriyama M, Iwasaki A. Inflammasomes and pyroptosis as therapeutic targets for COVID-19. J Immunol. 2020;205(2):307-312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu JJ, Liu X, Xia S, et al. FDA-approved disulfiram inhibits pyroptosis by blocking gasdermin D pore formation. Nat Immunol. 2020;21(7):736-745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis MA, Fairgrieve MR, Den Hartigh A, et al. Calpain drives pyroptotic vimentin cleavage, intermediate filament loss, and cell rupture that mediates immunostimulation. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2019;116(11):5061-5070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Costa LS, Outlioua A, Anginot A, Akarid K, Arnoult D. RNA viruses promote activation of the NLRP3 inflammasome through cytopathogenic effect-induced potassium efflux. Cell Death Dis. 2019;10(5):346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathinam VA, Fitzgerald KA. Inflammasome complexes: emerging mechanisms and effector functions. Cell. 2016;165(4):792-800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathkey JK, Zhao J, Liu Z, et al. Chemical disruption of the pyroptotic pore-forming protein gasdermin D inhibits inflammatory cell death and sepsis. Sci Immunol. 2018;3(26)&#x200b;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J, Zhao Y, Wang K, et al. Cleavage of GSDMD by inflammatory caspases determines pyroptotic cell death. Nature. 2015;526(7575):660-665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayagaki N, Stowe IB, Lee BL, et al. Caspase-11 cleaves gasdermin D for non-canonical inflammasome signalling. Nature. 2015;526(7575):666-671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Zheng J, Hu Q, et al. Magnesium protects against sepsis by blocking gasdermin D N-terminal-induced pyroptosis. Cell Death Differ. 2020;27(2):466-481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo HM, Rathkey J, Boyd-Tressler A, Katsnelson MA, Abbott DW, Dubyak GR. Active caspase-1 induces plasma membrane pores that precede pyroptotic lysis and are blocked by lanthanides. J Immunol. 2016;197(4):1353-1367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng J, Wang D, Chen Q, et al. Hypertonic saccharide solution delays pyroptosis in murine macrophages regardless of the membrane binding of gasdermin D N-terminal. Eur J Immunol. 2020;50(3):464-467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loomis WP, den Hartigh AB, Cookson BT, Fink SL. Diverse small molecules prevent macrophage lysis during pyroptosis. Cell Death Dis. 2019;10(4):326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y, Tian S, Pan Y, et al. Pyroptosis: a new frontier in cancer. Biomed Pharmacother. 2020;121:109595.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>