<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35593042</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>94</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Respiratory viruses among pediatric inpatients with acute lower respiratory tract infections in Jinan, China, 2016-2019.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4319</StartPage><EndPage>4328</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4319-4328</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.27875</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The viral etiologies responsible for acute lower respiratory tract infections (ALRI) are a major cause of pediatric hospitalization, and some develop severe diseases requiring pediatric intensive care unit (PICU) admission. The aim of this study is to determine the prevalence of viruses and risk factors associated with PICU admission among patients hospitalized for ALRI. Nasopharyngeal swabs were collected to detect human rhinovirus (HRV), influenza A and B viruses (IAV and&#xa0;IBV), parainfluenza viruses (PIV), and respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) by reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction (PCR) and adenovirus (ADV) by PCR. Of the 5590 pediatric inpatients enrolled, respiratory viral infection occurred in 2102 (37.60%) patients, including 1846 (33.02%) single and 256 (4.58%) mixed viral infections. Among the nasopharyngeal swabs from pediatric inpatients, HRV accounted for the highest detection rate (16.48%), followed by PIV (8.35%), RSV (7.41%), ADV (4.63%), IAV (3.51%), and IBV (2.08%). The positive rate of viral tests decreased with increasing age and was higher in males (39.29%) than females (34.67%). The prevalence of viral infection was the highest in winter (41.57%) and lowest in autumn (31.78%). Each virus had a seasonal pattern, with peaks occurring in months of their epidemic seasons. RSV infection and the presence of comorbidities including congenital tracheal stenosis, congenital heart disease, metabolic disorder, immunodeficiency, renal disease, gastrointestinal disease, and neurological disorder might be associated with the need for PICU admission. Therefore, this study provides useful information for the prevention and control of virus-related respiratory diseases and the early identification of and intervention in severe cases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chu</LastName><ForeName>Fu-Lu</ForeName><Initials>FL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Laboratory, Shandong Provincial Hospital Affiliated to Shandong First Medical University, Jinan, Shandong, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jinan Hospital, Jinan, Shandong, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Shandong Provincial Hospital Affiliated to Shandong First Medical University, Jinan, Shandong, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Shandong Provincial Hospital Affiliated to Shandong First Medical University, Jinan, Shandong, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qiu</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Laboratory, Shandong Provincial Hospital Affiliated to Shandong First Medical University, Jinan, Shandong, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yiqing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2844-2770</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Laboratory, Shandong Provincial Hospital Affiliated to Shandong First Medical University, Jinan, Shandong, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000256" MajorTopicYN="N">Adenoviridae</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009980" MajorTopicYN="Y">Influenza A virus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009981" MajorTopicYN="N">Influenza B virus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007297" MajorTopicYN="N">Inpatients</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010222" MajorTopicYN="N">Parainfluenza Virus 1, Human</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018113" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Syncytial Virus, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012141" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Tract Infections</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012621" MajorTopicYN="N">Seasons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014777" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acute lower respiratory tract infections</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric inpatient</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric intensive care unit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polymerase chain reaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory virus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35593042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.27875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Franz A, Adams O, Willems R, et al. Correlation of viral load of respiratory pathogens and co-infections with disease severity in children hospitalized for lower respiratory tract infection. J Clin Virol. 2010;48:239-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CY, Chang YF, Lee CL, et al. Molecular viral epidemiology and clinical characterization of acute febrile respiratory infections in hospitalized children in Taiwan. J Med Virol. 2015;87:1860-1866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsagarakis N, Sideri A, Makridis P, Triantafyllou A, Stamoulakatou A, Papadogeorgaki E. Age-related prevalence of common upper respiratory pathogens, based on the application of the FilmArray respiratory panel in a tertiary hospital in Greece. Medicine. 2018;97:e10903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goka EA, Vallely PJ, Mutton KJ, Klapper PE. Klapper P. Single, dual and multiple respiratory virus infections and risk of hospitalization and mortality. Epidemiol Infect. 2015;143:37-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H, Seo Y, Han S, Jeong D, Kang J. Clinical impact of mixed respiratory viral infection in children with adenoviral infection. Infect Chemother. 2016;48:309-316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair H, Nokes DJ, Gessner BD, et al. Global burden of acute lower respiratory infections due to respiratory syncytial virus in young children: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet. 2010;375:1545-1555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fendrick A, Monto A, Nightengale B, Sarnes M. The economic burden of non-influenza-related viral respiratory tract infection in the United States. Arch Intern Med. 2003;163:487-494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayden F. Advances in antivirals for non-influenza respiratory virus infections. Influenza Other Respir Viruses. 2013;7(suppl 3):36-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beumer MC, Koch RM, van Beuningen D, et al. Influenza virus and factors that are associated with ICU admission, pulmonary co-infections and ICU mortality. J Crit Care. 2019;50:59-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salcedo-Mej&#xed;a F, Alvis-Zakzuk NJ, Carrasquilla-Sotomayor M, et al. Economic cost of severe acute respiratory infection associated to influenza in Colombian Children: a single setting analysis. Value Health Reg Issues. 2019;20:159-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedraza-Bernal A, Rodriguez-Martinez C, Acuna-Cordero R. Predictors of severe disease in a hospitalized population of children with acute viral lower respiratory tract infections. J Med Virol. 2016;88:754-759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moynihan K, Barlow A, Heney C, Clark J, Schlebusch S, Schlapbach L. Viral respiratory infections diagnosed after PICU admission. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2019;20:e46-e50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuno AK, Gagliardi TB, Paula FE, et al. Human coronavirus alone or in co-infection with rhinovirus C is a risk factor for severe respiratory disease and admission to the pediatric intensive care unit: a one-year study in Southeast Brazil. PLoS One. 2019;14:e0217744.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham H, Bakare AA, Ayede AI, et al. Hypoxaemia in hospitalised children and neonates: a prospective cohort study in Nigerian secondary-level hospitals. EClinicalMedicine. 2019;16:51-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tregoning J, Schwarze J. Respiratory viral infections in infants: causes, clinical symptoms, virology, and immunology. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2010;23:74-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiuyan X. Impact of human rhinovirus types and viral load on the severity of illness in hospitalized children with lower respiratory tract infections. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2015;34:1187-1192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyene GT, Alemu F, Kebede ES, et al. Saliva is superior over nasopharyngeal swab for detecting SARS-CoV2 in COVID-19 patients. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):22640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Cao L, Xu Z, et al. Evaluation of a multiplex PCR assay for detection of respiratory viruses and Mycoplasma pneumoniae in oropharyngeal swab samples from outpatients. J Clin Lab Anal. 2020;34(1):e23032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otasek D, Morris J, Bou&#xe7;as J, Pico A, Demchak B. Cytoscape automation: empowering workflow-based network analysis. Genome Biol. 2019;20:185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Robertson G, Ashworth J, et al. Epidemiology and phylogenetic analysis of viral respiratory infections in Vietnam. Front Microbiol. 2020;11:833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan A, Kumar R, Broor S, et al. Epidemiology of viral acute lower respiratory infections in a community-based cohort of rural north Indian children. J Glob Health. 2019;9:010433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T, Li Z, Zhang S, et al. Viral etiology of acute respiratory tract infections in hospitalized children and adults in Shandong Province, China. Virol J. 2015;12:168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Wang S, Zhang L, et al. Epidemiology of human respiratory viruses in children with acute respiratory tract infections in Jinan, China. Clin Dev Immunol. 2013;2013:210490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasuwa T, Kinoshita F, Harada S, et al. Viral etiology of acute lower respiratory tract infections in hospitalized children in Nagasaki, a regional city of Japan in 2013-2015. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2020;39:687-693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Xiao Y, Zhang J, et al. Adenovirus infection in children with acute lower respiratory tract infections in Beijing, China, 2007 to 2012. BMC Infect Dis. 2015;15:408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korsun N, Angelova S, Trifonova I, et al. Viral pathogens associated with acute lower respiratory tract infections in children younger than 5 years of age in Bulgaria. Braz J Microbiol. 2019;50:117-125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin ET, Kuypers J, Chu HY, et al. Heterotypic infection and spread of rhinovirus A, B, and C among childcare attendees. J Infect Dis. 2018;218:848-855.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Care A, Bellenghi M, Matarrese P, Gabriele L, Salvioli S, Malorni W. Sex disparity in cancer: roles of microRNAs and related functional players. Cell Death Differ. 2018;25:477-485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papenburg J, Hamelin M&#xc8;, Ouhoummane N, et al. Comparison of risk factors for human metapneumovirus and respiratory syncytial virus disease severity in young children. J Infect Dis. 2012;206:178-189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heping W. Prevalence of respiratory viruses among children hospitalized from respiratory infections in Shenzhen, China. Virol J. 2016;13:39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen S, Yu M, Zheng G, et al. Changes in the etiology of viral lower respiratory tract infections in hospitalized children in Wenzhou, China: 2008-2017. J Med Virol. 92, 2020:982-987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etemadi MR, Jalilian FA, Othman N, et al. Diversity of respiratory viruses detected among hospitalized children with acute lower respiratory tract infections at Hospital Serdang, Malaysia. J Virol Methods. 2019;269:1-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Mauri&#xf1;o C, Moore-Clingenpeel M, Thomas J, et al. Viral load dynamics and clinical disease severity in infants with respiratory syncytial virus infection. J Infect Dis. 2019;219:1207-1215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L, Xiao Q, Zhao Y, Huang A, Ren L, Liu E. The impact of viral dynamics on the clinical severity of infants with respiratory syncytial virus bronchiolitis. J Med Virol. 2015;87:1276-1284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arruda E, Jones MH, Escremim de Paula F, et al. The burden of single virus and viral coinfections on severe lower respiratory tract infections among preterm infants: a prospective birth cohort study in Brazil. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2014;33:997-1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu SS, Chan KH, Chen H, et al. Virologically confirmed population-based burden of hospitalization caused by respiratory syncytial virus, adenovirus, and parainfluenza viruses in children in Hong Kong. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2010;29:1088-1092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore HC, de Klerk N, Keil AD, et al. Use of data linkage to investigate the aetiology of acute lower respiratory infection hospitalisations in children. J Paediatr Child Health. 2012;48:520-528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Zhu B, Xu X. Follow-up investigation of 41 children after metallic airway stent implantation: an 8-year experience. Front Pediatr. 2020;8:579209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray J, Bottle A, Sharland M, et al. Risk factors for hospital admission with RSV bronchiolitis in England: a population-based birth cohort study. PLoS One. 2014;9(2):e89186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J, Han S. Seizures related to influenza in pediatric patients: a comparison with seizures associated with other respiratory viral infections. J Clin Med. 2021;10(14):3088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinney GL, Black-Shinn JL, Wan ES, et al. Pulmonary function reduction in diabetes with and without chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Diabetes Care. 2014;37(2):389-395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okereke I, Hamilton C, Wenholz A, et al. Associations of the microbiome and esophageal disease. J Thorac Dis. 2019;11:S1588-S1593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, Zhang J, Chen Y, et al. Hydrogen protects lung from hypoxia/re-oxygenation injury by reducing hydroxyl radical production and inhibiting inflammatory responses. Sci Rep. 2018;8:8004.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>