<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35694176</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-3546</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Brain, behavior, &amp; immunity - health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Brain Behav Immun Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long-term psychiatric outcomes in youth with enterovirus A71 central nervous system involvement.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100479</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100479</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100479</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bbih.2022.100479</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long-term neurological and neurodevelopmental sequelae are a concerning issue for people with Enterovirus A71 (EV-A71) central nervous system (CNS) infection. Unfortunately, no longitudinal prospective clinical study has systematically investigated the consequences of EV-A71 CNS infection during early life on the later development of other psychiatric disorders. In this naturalistic longitudinal follow-up design, we followed forty-three youth, who got EV-A71 CNS involvement 6-18 years ago and were enrolled in other EV-A71 clinical studies then. Their psychiatric presentation, emotional/behavioral problems, and cognitive issues were examined using a psychiatrist-conducted diagnostic interview, parent- and self-rated questionnaires, and neuropsychological tests, respectively. We compared the prevalence of psychiatric disorders in youth with EV-A71 CNS involvement to a nationally representative cohort. Emotion/behavior and cognition in EV-A71-CNS-infected youth were compared to those in a matched community-based sample of healthy controls and youth with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD). Compared to a national sample (absolute ADHD prevalence 10.1%), youth with EV-A71 CNS involvement had three times the odds of receiving an ADHD diagnosis (standardized prevalence ratio, 95% CI&#xa0;=&#xa0;1.8, 4.2; absolute ADHD prevalence 34.9%). No other psychiatric diagnoses were more common in EV-A71-CNS-infected youth. Compared to community-based ADHD youth, EV-A71-CNS-infected youth with psychiatric disorders showed comparable core ADHD symptoms, opposition/defiance, autistic features, and suboptimal sustained attention performance (based on the Conners' Continuous Performance Test), all of which were more severe than healthy controls. EV-A71-CNS-infected youth without psychiatric disorders showed comparable autistic features to EV-A71-CNS-infected youth with psychiatric disorders and ADHD youth. EV-A71 CNS involvement may cause long-term, adverse psychiatric outcomes that develop into an ADHD diagnosis alongside social/communication/emotion problems and autistic features. We recommend earlier identification and intervention of these problems among these children.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Hsiang-Yuan</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Azrieli Adult Neurodevelopmental Centre, Campbell Family Mental Health Research Institute, Centre for Addiction and Mental Health, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Temerty Faculty of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, National Taiwan University Hospital and College of Medicine, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Lung</ForeName><Initials>YL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology and Department of Healthcare Administration, Asia University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chou</LastName><ForeName>Pei-Hsuan</ForeName><Initials>PH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, National Taiwan University Hospital and College of Medicine, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gau</LastName><ForeName>Susan Shur-Fen</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, National Taiwan University Hospital and College of Medicine, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Luan-Yin</ForeName><Initials>LY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, National Taiwan University Hospital and College of Medicine, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Brain Behav Immun Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101759062</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-3546</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ADHD, attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AQ, Autism Spectrum Quotient</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ASD, autism spectrum disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autistic traits</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CCPT, Conners' Continuous Performance Test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CNS infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CNS, central nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EV-A71, enterovirus A71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FSIQ, full-scale intelligence quotient</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">K-SADS-E, Kiddie Schedule for Affective Disorders and Schizophrenia-Epidemiological Version</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Naturalistic study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PIQ, performance intelligence quotient</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychiatric diagnostic interview</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SDQ, Strengths and Difficulties Questionnaire</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SNAP-IV, Swanson Nolan and Pelham, Version IV Scale</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SRS, Social Responsiveness Scale</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TDC, typically developing control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TNESCMD, Taiwan's National Epidemiological Study of Child Mental Disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VIQ, verbal intelligence quotient</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35694176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9184869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbih.2022.100479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-3546(22)00069-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ali Awan H., Najmuddin Diwan M., Aamir A., Ali M., Di Giannantonio M., Ullah I., Shoib S., De Berardis D. SARS-CoV-2 and the brain: what do we know about the causality of 'cognitive COVID? J. Clin. Med. 2021;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8347421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34362224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astle D.E., Holmes J., Kievit R., Gathercole S.E. Annual Research Review: the transdiagnostic revolution in neurodevelopmental disorders. J. Child Psychol. Psychiatry Allied Discip. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34296774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron-Cohen S., Wheelwright S., Skinner R., Martin J., Clubley E. The autism-spectrum quotient (AQ): evidence from Asperger syndrome/high-functioning autism, males and females, scientists and mathematicians. J. Autism Dev. Disord. 2001;31:5&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11439754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D.V., Maybery M., Maley A., Wong D., Hill W., Hallmayer J. Using self-report to identify the broad phenotype in parents of children with autistic spectrum disorders: a study using the Autism-Spectrum Quotient. J. Child Psychol. Psychiatry Allied Discip. 2004;45:1431&#x2013;1436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15482503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bussing R., Fernandez M., Harwood M., Wei H., Garvan C.W., Eyberg S.M., Swanson J.M. Parent and teacher SNAP-IV ratings of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder symptoms: psychometric properties and normative ratings from a school district sample. Assessment. 2008;15:317&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3623293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18310593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera Filho F.D., Ribeiro B.N.F., Marchiori E. Bilateral striatal necrosis associated with enterovirus infection. Rev. Soc. Bras. Med. Trop. 2021;54</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8047696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33886814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang J.C., Lin H.Y., Lv J., Tseng W.I., Gau S.S. Regional brain volume predicts response to methylphenidate treatment in individuals with ADHD. BMC Psychiatr. 2021;21:26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7798216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33430830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang L.Y., Huang L.M., Gau S.S., Wu Y.Y., Hsia S.H., Fan T.Y., Lin K.L., Huang Y.C., Lu C.Y., Lin T.Y. Neurodevelopment and cognition in children after enterovirus 71 infection. N. Engl. J. Med. 2007;356:1226&#x2013;1234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17377160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang L.Y., Lin H.Y., Gau S.S., Lu C.Y., Hsia S.H., Huang Y.C., Huang L.M., Lin T.Y. Enterovirus A71 neurologic complications and long-term sequelae. J. Biomed. Sci. 2019;26:57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6688366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31395054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang L.Y., Lin T.Y., Hsu K.H., Huang Y.C., Lin K.L., Hsueh C., Shih S.R., Ning H.C., Hwang M.S., Wang H.S., Lee C.Y. Clinical features and risk factors of pulmonary oedema after enterovirus-71-related hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet (London, England) 1999;354:1682&#x2013;1686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y.L., Chen W.J., Lin K.C., Shen L.J., Gau S.S. Prevalence of DSM-5 mental disorders in a nationally representative sample of children in Taiwan: methodology and main findings. Epidemiol. Psychiatr. Sci. 2019;29:e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8061245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30696515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y.L., Shen L.J., Gau S.S. The Mandarin version of the Kiddie-Schedule for Affective Disorders and Schizophrenia-Epidemiological version for DSM-5 - a psychometric study. J. Formos. Med. Assoc. 2017;116:671&#x2013;678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28709821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia M.Y., Chiang P.S., Chung W.Y., Luo S.T., Lee M.S. Epidemiology of enterovirus 71 infections in Taiwan. Pediatrics and neonatology. 2014;55:243&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24120535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou I.C., Lin C.C., Kao C.H. Enterovirus encephalitis increases the risk of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: a Taiwanese population-based case-control study. Medicine. 2015;94:e707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4602682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25906098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conners C.K., Staff M. North Tonwanda; NY: 2000. Conners' Continuous Performance Test II: Computer Program for Windows Technical Guide and Software Manual. Mutli-Health Systems.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constantino J.N., Davis S.A., Todd R.D., Schindler M.K., Gross M.M., Brophy S.L., Metzger L.M., Shoushtari C.S., Splinter R., Reich W. Validation of a brief quantitative measure of autistic traits: comparison of the social responsiveness scale with the autism diagnostic interview-revised. J. Autism Dev. Disord. 2003;33:427&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12959421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Berardis D. How concerned should we be about neurotropism of SARS-Cov-2? A brief clinical consideration of the possible psychiatric implications. CNS Spectr. 2020:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33300484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De la Marche W., Noens I., Luts J., Scholte E., Van Huffel S., Steyaert J. Quantitative autism traits in first degree relatives: evidence for the broader autism phenotype in fathers, but not in mothers and siblings. Autism : Int. J. Res. Practice. 2012;16:247&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21949002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraone S.V., Asherson P., Banaschewski T., Biederman J., Buitelaar J.K., Ramos-Quiroga J.A., Rohde L.A., Sonuga-Barke E.J., Tannock R., Franke B. Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Nat. Rev. Dis. Prim. 2015;1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27189265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gau S.S., Chang L.Y., Huang L.M., Fan T.Y., Wu Y.Y., Lin T.Y. Attention-deficit/hyperactivity-related symptoms among children with enterovirus 71 infection of the central nervous system. Pediatrics. 2008;122:e452&#x2013;458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18606624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gau S.S., Chong M.Y., Chen T.H., Cheng A.T. A 3-year panel study of mental disorders among adolescents in Taiwan. Am. J. Psychiatr. 2005;162:1344&#x2013;1350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15994718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gau S.S., Shang C.Y., Liu S.K., Lin C.H., Swanson J.M., Liu Y.C., Tu C.L. Psychometric properties of the Chinese version of the Swanson, Nolan, and Pelham, version IV scale - parent form. Int. J. Methods Psychiatr. Res. 2008;17:35&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6878250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18286459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gau S.S.-F., Liu L.-T., Wu Y.-Y., Chiu Y.-N., Tsai W.-C. Psychometric properties of the Chinese version of the social responsiveness scale. Res. Autism Spectrum Disorders. 2013;7:349&#x2013;360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman R. The extended version of the Strengths and Difficulties Questionnaire as a guide to child psychiatric caseness and consequent burden. J. Child Psychol. Psychiatry Allied Discip. 1999;40:791&#x2013;799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10433412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hearne L.J., Lin H.Y., Sanz-Leon P., Tseng W.I., Gau S.S., Roberts J.A., Cocchi L. ADHD symptoms map onto noise-driven structure-function decoupling between hub and peripheral brain regions. Mol. Psychiatr. 2021;26:4036&#x2013;4045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31666679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H.I., Shih S.R. Neurotropic enterovirus infections in the central nervous system. Viruses. 2015;7:6051&#x2013;6066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4664993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26610549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang M.C., Wang S.M., Hsu Y.W., Lin H.C., Chi C.Y., Liu C.C. Long-term cognitive and motor deficits after enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in children. Pediatrics. 2006;118:e1785&#x2013;1788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17116698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappeler P.M., Cremer S., Nunn C.L. Vol. 370. Philosophical transactions of the Royal Society of London. Series B, Biological sciences; 2015. (Sociality and Health: Impacts of Sociality on Disease Susceptibility and Transmission in Animal and Human Societies).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4410382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25870402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;hler-Forsberg O., Petersen L., Gasse C., Mortensen P.B., Dalsgaard S., Yolken R.H., Mors O., Benros M.E. A nationwide study in Denmark of the association between treated infections and the subsequent risk of treated mental disorders in children and adolescents. JAMA Psychiatr. 2019;76:271&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6439826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30516814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau W.Y., Gau S.S., Chiu Y.N., Wu Y.Y., Chou W.J., Liu S.K., Chou M.C. Psychometric properties of the Chinese version of the autism spectrum quotient (AQ) Res. Dev. Disabil. 2013;34:294&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22985783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang L., Cheng Y., Li Y., Shang Q., Huang J., Ma C., Fang S., Long L., Zhou C., Chen Z., Cui P., Lv N., Lou P., Cui Y., Sabanathan S., van Doorn H.R., Luan R., Turtle L., Yu H. Long-term neurodevelopment outcomes of hand, foot and mouth disease inpatients infected with EV-A71 or CV-A16, a retrospective cohort study. Emerg. Microb. Infect. 2021;10:545&#x2013;554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8009121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33691598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y.J., Tseng W.L., Gau S.S. Psychiatric comorbidity and social adjustment difficulties in children with disruptive mood dysregulation disorder: a national epidemiological study. J. Affect. Disord. 2021;281:485&#x2013;492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8142276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33383391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S.K., Chien Y.L., Shang C.Y., Lin C.H., Liu Y.C., Gau S.S. Psychometric properties of the Chinese version of strength and difficulties questionnaire. Compr. Psychiatr. 2013;54:720&#x2013;730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23433222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Aranda M.F., Chattopadhyay I., Boxx G.M., Fraley E.R., Silva T.K., Zhou M., Phan M., Herrera I., Taloma S., Mandanas R., Bach K., Gandal M., Geschwind D.H., Cheng G., Rzhetsky A., White S.A., Silva A.J. Postnatal immune activation causes social deficits in a mouse model of tuberous sclerosis: role of microglia and clinical implications. Sci. Adv. 2021;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8448451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34533985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lord C., Bishop S.L. Let's Be clear that "autism spectrum disorder symptoms" are not always related to autism spectrum disorder. Am. J. Psychiatr. 2021;178:680&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34383567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyall K., Constantino J.N., Weisskopf M.G., Roberts A.L., Ascherio A., Santangelo S.L. Parental social responsiveness and risk of autism spectrum disorder in offspring. JAMA Psychiatr. 2014;71:936&#x2013;942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4126195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25100167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munkvold L.H., Manger T., Lundervold A.J. Conners' continuous performance test (CCPT-II) in children with ADHD, ODD, or a combined ADHD/ODD diagnosis. Child Neuropsychol. : J. Normal Abnormal Deve. Childhood Adolescence. 2014;20:106&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23244393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura R., Chong P.F., Haraguchi K., Katano H., Tanaka-Taya K., Kira R. Disseminated cortical and subcortical lesions in neonatal enterovirus 71 encephalitis. J. Neurovirol. 2020;26:790&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32671810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen N.M., Rostgaard K., Hjalgrim H., Askgaard D., Skinh&#xf8;j P., Aaby P. Psychiatric hospitalizations in a cohort of Danish polio patients. Am. J. Epidemiol. 2007;165:319&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17098819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okyar E., G&#xf6;rker I. Examining the autistic traits in children and adolescents diagnosed with attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder and their parents. BMC Psychiatr. 2020;20:285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7275391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32503560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panagiotidi M., Overton P.G., Stafford T. Co-occurrence of ASD and ADHD traits in an Adult population. J. Atten. Disord. 2019;23:1407&#x2013;1415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28800716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen E.M.J., K&#xf6;hler-Forsberg O., Nordentoft M., Christensen R.H.B., Mortensen P.B., Petersen L., Benros M.E. Infections of the central nervous system as a risk factor for mental disorders and cognitive impairment: a nationwide register-based study. Brain Behav. Immun. 2020;88:668&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32353515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiersen A.M., Constantino J.N., Volk H.E., Todd R.D. Autistic traits in a population-based ADHD twin sample. J. Child Psychol. Psychiatry Allied Discip. 2007;48:464&#x2013;472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17501727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabanathan S., Tan le V., Thwaites L., Wills B., Qui P.T., Rogier van Doorn H. Enterovirus 71 related severe hand, foot and mouth disease outbreaks in South-East Asia: current situation and ongoing challenges. J. Epidemiol. Community. 2014;68:500&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4033151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24652348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuid A.N., Jayusman P.A., Shuid N., Ismail J., Kamal Nor N., Mohamed I.N. Association between viral infections and risk of autistic disorder: an overview. Int. J. Environ. Res. Publ. Health. 2021;18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7999368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33802042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T., Lewthwaite P., Perera D., Cardosa M.J., McMinn P., Ooi M.H. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. The Lancet. Infectious diseases. 2010;10:778&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20961813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng J.J., Lin C.H., Lin M.C. Long-term outcomes of pediatric enterovirus infection in taiwan: a population-based cohort study. Front Pediatr. 2020;8:285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7303813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32596191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsou Y.A., Cheng Y.K., Chung H.K., Yeh Y.C., Lin C.D., Tsai M.H., Chang J.S. Upper aerodigestive tract sequelae in severe enterovirus 71 infection: predictors and outcome. Int. J. Pediatr. Otorhinolaryngol. 2008;72:41&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18029029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung Y.H., Lin H.Y., Chen C.L., Shang C.Y., Yang L.Y., Hsu Y.C., Tseng W.I., Gau S.S. The American journal of psychiatry; 2021. Whole Brain White Matter Tract Deviation and Idiosyncrasy from Normative Development in Autism and ADHD and Unaffected Siblings Link with Dimensions of Psychopathology and Cognition. appiajp.202020070999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33726525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turano A., McAuley E.M., Muench M.C., Schwarz J.M. Examining the impact OF neuroimmune dysregulation ON social behavior OF male and female juvenile rats. Behav. Brain Res. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8648073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34252501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virkud Y.V., Todd R.D., Abbacchi A.M., Zhang Y., Constantino J.N. Familial aggregation of quantitative autistic traits in multiplex versus simplex autism. Am. J. Med. Genet. Part B, Neuropsychiatric genetics: the official publication of the International Society of Psychiatric Genetics. 2009;150b:328&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2819431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18618672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wechsler D. third ed. WISC-III). Psychological Corporation; San Antonio, TX: 1991. Wechsler Intelligence Scale for Children.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wechsler D. Psychological Corporation; San Antonio, TX: 1997. Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale - Third Edition (WAIS-III)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou R., Xia Q., Shen H., Yang X., Zhang Y., Xu J. Diagnosis of children's attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) and its association with cytomegalovirus infection with ADHD: a historical review. Int. J. Clin. Exp. Med. 2015;8:13969&#x2013;13975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4613039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26550354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>