<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">36094067</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2472-1727</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>115</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Birth defects research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Birth Defects Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multiple subtypes of coxsackievirus group B can cause congenital heart disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>171</StartPage><EndPage>178</EndPage><MedlinePgn>171-178</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/bdr2.2086</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Different serotypes of coxsackievirus B (CVB), which is the most common cause of viral myocarditis, target cardiomyocytes through Coxsackie and Adenovirus Receptor and Decay-Accelerating Factor. Both receptors are expressed in the fetal heart. We hypothesized that infection with different serotypes of CVB during early pregnancy plays a role in pathogenesis of congenital heart defect (CHD).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this study, we use a murine model to infect with CVB1, CVB4, and combination of CVB3&#x2009;+&#x2009;CVB4 during a critical period in gestation. We examined offspring of pregnant mice for fetal death and heart defects following viral infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Fetuses from uninfected control dams showed normal heart development, while maternal CVB infection precipitates CHD: majorly ventricular septal defects (VSD) and non-compaction of ventricular myocardium (NC), with some infrequent cases of double outlet right ventricle, left ventricle wall rupture, right ventricle hypertrophy, and thickened/dysplastic semilunar valves. Infection of pregnant dams with CVB1 leads to 44% VSD and 41.2% NC cases, while with CVB4 leads to 31.7% VSD and 13.3% NC cases. Co-infection with CVB3&#x2009;+&#x2009;CVB4 increases fetal pathology to 51.3% VSD and 41% NC cases. Infection can also result in fetal death, with higher incidences with CVB3&#x2009;+&#x2009;CVB4 with 46.2% cases, compared to 33.3% by CVB1 and 21.7% by CVB4. Male fetuses were more susceptible to all phenotypes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our report shows that prenatal CVB infections can lead to pathogenesis of certain heart defects in mouse model, particularly exacerbated with co-infections. This data confirms a link between prenatal CVB infection and CHD development and highlights it is not unique to just one serotype of CVB.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Vipul</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5952-4963</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Cardiothoracic Surgery, Department of Surgery, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goessling</LastName><ForeName>Lisa S</ForeName><Initials>LS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Cardiothoracic Surgery, Department of Surgery, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brar</LastName><ForeName>Anoop K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Cardiothoracic Surgery, Department of Surgery, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eghtesady</LastName><ForeName>Pirooz</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Cardiothoracic Surgery, Department of Surgery, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Birth Defects Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101701004</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029822" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus B, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006330" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart Defects, Congenital</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009205" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myocarditis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009206" MajorTopicYN="N">Myocardium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D032383" MajorTopicYN="N">Myocytes, Cardiac</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003384" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coxsackievirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011251" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pregnancy Complications, Infectious</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">congenital heart disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coxsackievirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatrics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pregnancy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">virus infection</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36094067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bdr2.2086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ahn, J., Joo, C. H., Seo, I., Kim, D. H., Kim, Y. K., &amp; Lee, H. (2005). All CVB serotypes and clinical isolates induce irreversible cytopathic effects in primary cardiomyocytes. Journal of Medical Virology, 75, 290-294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andr&#xe9;oletti, L., Hober, D., Hober-Vandenberghe, C., Belaich, S., Vantyghem, M. C., Lefebvre, J., &amp; Wattr&#xe9;, P. (1997). Detection of coxsackie B virus RNA sequences in whole blood samples from adult patients at the onset of type I diabetes mellitus. Journal of Medical Virology, 52, 121-127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Axelsson, C., Bondestam, K., Frisk, G., Bergstr&#xf6;m, S., &amp; Diderholm, H. (1993). Coxsackie B virus infections in women with miscarriage. Journal of Medical Virology, 39, 282-285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bopegamage, S., Precechtelova, J., Marosova, L., Stipalova, D., Sojka, M., Borsanyiova, M., &#x2026; Galama, J. M. D. (2012). Outcome of challenge with coxsackievirus B4 in young mice after maternal infection with the same virus during gestation. FEMS Immunology and Medical Microbiology, 64, 184-190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, G. C., &amp; Evans, T. N. (1967). Serologic evidence of coxsackievirus etiology of congenital heart disease. JAMA, 199, 183-187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, G. C., &amp; Karunas, R. S. (1972). Relationship of congenital anomalies and maternal infection with selected enteroviruses. American Journal of Epidemiology, 95, 207-217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvajal, H. G., Sharma, V., Goessling, L. S., Merritt, T. C., Brar, A. K., &amp; Eghtesady, P. (2022). Possible Association of Pulmonary Atresia with in-utero coxsackievirus B exposure. Pediatric Cardiology, 43, 960-968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chehadeh, W., Lobert, P. E., Sauter, P., Goffard, A., Lucas, B., Weill, J., &#x2026; Hober, D. (2005). Viral protein VP4 is a target of human antibodies enhancing coxsackievirus B4- and B3-induced synthesis of alpha interferon. Journal of Virology, 79, 13882-13891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chehadeh, W., Weill, J., Vantyghem, M. C., Alm, G., Lef&#xe8;bvre, J., Wattr&#xe9;, P., &amp; Hober, D. (2000). Increased level of interferon-alpha in blood of patients with insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus: Relationship with coxsackievirus B infection. The Journal of Infectious Diseases, 181, 1929-1939.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clements, G. B., Galbraith, D. N., &amp; Taylor, K. W. (1995). Coxsackie B virus infection and onset of childhood diabetes. Lancet, 346, 221-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Euscher, E., Davis, J., Holzman, I., &amp; Nuovo, G. J. (2001). Coxsackie virus infection of the placenta associated with neurodevelopmental delays in the newborn. Obstetrics and Gynecology, 98, 1019-1026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feuer, R., Mena, I., Pagarigan, R. R., Harkins, S., Hassett, D. E., &amp; Whitton, J. L. (2003). Coxsackievirus B3 and the neonatal CNS: The roles of stem cells, developing neurons, and apoptosis in infection, viral dissemination, and disease. The American Journal of Pathology, 163, 1379-1393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frisk, G., &amp; Diderholm, H. (1992). Increased frequency of Coxsackie B virus IgM in women with spontaneous abortion. The Journal of Infection, 24, 141-145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebhard, J. R., Perry, C. M., Harkins, S., Lane, T., Mena, I., Asensio, V. C., &#x2026; Whitton, J. L. (1998). Coxsackievirus B3-induced myocarditis: Perforin exacerbates disease, but plays no detectable role in virus clearance. The American Journal of Pathology, 153, 417-428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafenstein, S., Bowman, V. D., Chipman, P. R., Kelly, C. M. B., Lin, F., Medof, M. E., &amp; Rossmann, M. G. (2007). Interaction of decay-accelerating factor with coxsackievirus B3. Journal of Virology, 81, 12927-12935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, B.-C., Yang, P.-C., &amp; Yu, S.-L. (2016). MicroRNA and pathogenesis of enterovirus infection. Viruses, 8, 11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunt, J. C., Schneider, C., Menticoglou, S., Herath, J., &amp; Del Bigio, M. R. (2012). Antenatal and postnatal diagnosis of coxsackie b4 infection: Case series. AJP Reports, 2, 1-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang, J. Y., Lee, K. M., Kim, Y. H., Shim, H. M., Bae, Y. K., Hwang, J. H., &amp; Park, H. (2014). Pregnancy loss following coxsackievirus b3 infection in mice during early gestation due to high expression of coxsackievirus-adenovirus receptor (CAR) in uterus and embryo. Experimental Animals, 63, 63-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenson, H. B., Gauntt, C. J., Easley, K. A., Pitt, J., Lipshultz, S. E., McIntosh, K., &#x2026; Pediatric Pulmonary and Cardiovascular Complications of HIV-1 Infection Study Group. (2002). Evaluation of coxsackievirus infection in children with human immunodeficiency virus type 1-associated cardiomyopathy. The Journal of Infectious Diseases, 185, 1798-1802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konstantinidou, A., Anninos, H., Spanakis, N., Kotsiakis, X., Syridou, G., Tsakris, A., &amp; Patsouris, E. (2007). Transplacental infection of coxsackievirus B3 pathological findings in the fetus. Journal of Medical Virology, 79, 754-757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lansdown, A. B. (1977). Coxsackievirus B3 infection in pregnancy and its influence on foetal heart development. British Journal of Experimental Pathology, 58, 378-385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Van Quyen, P., Desprez, P., Livolsi, A., Lindner, V., Fafi-Kremer, S., Helms, P., &amp; Anta, M. C. (2017). Peculiar clinical presentation of coxsackievirus B4 infection: Neonatal restrictive cardiomyopathy. AJP Reports, 7, e124-e126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, F., Fukuoka, Y., Spicer, A., Ohta, R., Okada, N., Harris, C. L., &#x2026; Medof, M. E. (2001). Tissue distribution of products of the mouse decay-accelerating factor (DAF) genes. Exploitation of a Daf1 knock-out mouse and site-specific monoclonal antibodies. Immunology, 104, 215-225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;nnrot, M., Salminen, K., Knip, M., Savola, K., Kulmala, P., Leinikki, P., &#x2026; Hy&#xf6;ty, H. (2000). Enterovirus RNA in serum is a risk factor for beta-cell autoimmunity and clinical type 1 diabetes: A prospective study. Childhood Diabetes in Finland (DiMe) Study Group. Journal of Medical Virology, 61, 214-220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFarlane, L., Truong, V., Palmer, J. S., &amp; Wilhelm, D. (2013). Novel PCR assay for determining the genetic sex of mice. Sexual Development, 7, 207-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nairn, C., Galbraith, D. N., Taylor, K. W., &amp; Clements, G. B. (1999). Enterovirus variants in the serum of children at the onset of type 1 diabetes mellitus. Diabetic Medicine, 16, 509-513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ornoy, A., Chen, L., Silver, R. M., &amp; Miller, R. K. (2004). Maternal autoimmune diseases and immunologically induced embryonic and fetoplacental damage. Birth Defects Research, 70, 371-381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafren, D. R., Bates, R. C., Agrez, M. V., Herd, R. L., Burns, G. F., &amp; Barry, R. D. (1995). Coxsackieviruses B1, B3, and B5 use decay accelerating factor as a receptor for cell attachment. Journal of Virology, 69, 3873-3877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma V., Goessling L. S., Brar A. K., &amp; Eghtesady P. In utero infection with coxsackievirus-B is associated with congenital pulmonary atresia. medRxiv. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, V., Goessling, L. S., Brar, A. K., Joshi, C. S., Mysorekar, I. U., &amp; Eghtesady, P. (2021). Coxsackievirus B3 infection early in pregnancy induces congenital heart defects through suppression of fetal cardiomyocyte proliferation. Journal of the American Heart Association, 10, e017995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, V., Perry, D. J., &amp; Eghtesady, P. (2021). Role of coxsackie-adenovirus receptor in cardiac development and pathogenesis of congenital heart disease. Birth Defects Research, 113, 535-545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tennant, P. W. G., Samarasekera, S. D., Pless-Mulloli, T., &amp; Rankin, J. (2011). Sex differences in the prevalence of congenital anomalies: A population-based study. Birth Defects Research, 91, 894-901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verheugt, C. L., Uiterwaal, C. S. P. M., van der Velde, E. T., Meijboom, F. J., Pieper, P. G., Vliegen, H. W., &#x2026; Mulder, B. J. M. (2008). Gender and outcome in adult congenital heart disease. Circulation, 118, 26-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, N. A., Zheng, X. T., Harris, M. U., Cadichon, S. B., Melin-Aldana, H., Khetsuriani, N., &#x2026; Shulman, S. T. (2009). Outbreak of life-threatening coxsackievirus B1 myocarditis in neonates. Clinical Infectious Diseases, 49, 759-763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wikswo, M. E., Khetsuriani, N., Fowlkes, A. L., Zheng, X., Pe&#xf1;aranda, S., Verma, N., &#x2026; Oberste, M. S. (2009). Increased activity of coxsackievirus B1 strains associated with severe disease among young infants in the United States, 2007-2008. Clinical Infectious Diseases, 49, e44-e51.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>