<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36219869</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1529-4242</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>151</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Plastic and reconstructive surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Plast Reconstr Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute Flaccid Myelitis: Review of Clinical Features, Diagnosis, and Management with Nerve Transfers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>85e</StartPage><EndPage>98e</EndPage><MedlinePgn>85e-98e</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PRS.0000000000009788</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Acute flaccid myelitis (AFM) is a devastating neurologic condition in children, manifesting as acute limb weakness and/or paralysis. Despite increased awareness of AFM following initiation of U.S. surveillance in 2014, no treatment consensus exists. The purpose of this systematic review was to summarize the most current knowledge regarding AFM epidemiology, cause, clinical features, diagnosis, and supportive and operative management, including nerve transfer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The authors systematically reviewed the literature based on Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines using multiple databases to search the keywords ("acute flaccid myelitis"), ('acute flaccid myelitis'/exp OR 'acute flaccid myelitis'), and (Acute AND flaccid AND myelitis). Included articles reported on (1) AFM diagnosis and (2) patient-specific data regarding epidemiology, cause, clinical features, diagnostic features, or management of AFM.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Ninety-nine articles were included in this review. The precise cause and pathophysiologic mechanism of AFM remain undetermined, but AFM is strongly associated with nonpolio enterovirus infections. Clinical presentation typically comprises preceding viral prodrome, pleocytosis, spinal cord lesions on T2-weighted magnetic resonance imaging, and acute onset of flaccid weakness/paralysis with hyporeflexia in at least one extremity. Supportive care includes medical therapy and rehabilitation. Early studies of nerve transfer for AFM have shown favorable outcomes for patients with persistent weakness.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Supportive care and physical therapy are the foundation of a multidisciplinary approach to managing AFM. For patients with persistent limb weakness, nerve transfer has shown promise for improving function in distal muscle groups. Surgeons must consider potential spontaneous recovery, patient selection, donor nerve availability, recipient nerve appropriateness, and procedure timing.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 by the American Society of Plastic Surgeons.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kozlowski</LastName><ForeName>Julia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the School of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Linzey</LastName><ForeName>Joseph R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muhlestein</LastName><ForeName>Whitney E</ForeName><Initials>WE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Brandon W</ForeName><Initials>BW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurologic Surgery, Duke University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Kate Wan-Chu</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Lynda J-S</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Plast Reconstr Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1306050</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0032-1052</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C000629404">acute flaccid myelitis</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016067" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nerve Transfer</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009468" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuromuscular Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009187" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myelitis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010243" MajorTopicYN="N">Paralysis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009123" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Hypotonia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36219869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PRS.0000000000009788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006534-202301000-00024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chong PF, Kira R, Mori H, et al. Clinical features of acute flaccid myelitis temporally associated with an enterovirus D68 outbreak: results of a nationwide survey of acute flaccid paralysis in Japan, August-December 2015. Clin Infect Dis. 2018;66:653&#x2013;664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayers T, Lopez A, Lee A, et al. Acute flaccid myelitis in the United States: 2015&#x2013;2017. Pediatrics. 2019;144:e20191619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidd S, Lopez A, Nix WA, et al. Vital signs: Clinical characteristics of patients with confirmed acute flaccid myelitis, United States, 2018. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69:1031&#x2013;1038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charoensanti S. Acute flaccid paralysis in single upper limb with HFMD from enterovirus71 infection: case report and review of the literature. J Med Assoc Thai. 2018;101:411&#x2013;421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moline HL, Karachunski PI, Strain A, Griffith J, Kenyon C, Schleiss MR. Acute transverse myelitis caused by echovirus 11 in a pediatric patient: case report and review of the current literature. Child Neurol Open. 2018;5:2329048X17751526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saltzman EB, Rancy SK, Sneag DB, Feinberg JH, Lange DJ, Wolfe SW. Nerve transfers for enterovirus D68-associated acute flaccid myelitis: a case series. Pediatr Neurol. 2018;88:25&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoder JA, Lloyd M, Zabrocki L, Auten J. Pediatric acute flaccid paralysis: enterovirus D68-associated anterior myelitis. J Emerg Med. 2017;53:e19&#x2013;e23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG PRISMA group. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. BMJ. 2009;339:b2535.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonwitt J, Poel A, DeBolt C, et al. Acute flaccid myelitis among children: Washington, September&#x2013;November 2016. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2017;66:826&#x2013;829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrerizo M, Garcia-Iniguez JP, Munell F, et al. First cases of severe flaccid paralysis associated with enterovirus D68 infection in Spain, 2015-2016. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2017;36:1214&#x2013;1216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai R, Bhise V. Case 1: Sudden bilateral lower extremity weakness and urinary incontinence in a 13-year-old girl. Pediatr Rev. 2019;40:528&#x2013;531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carballo CM, Erro MG, Sordelli N, et al. Acute flaccid myelitis associated with enterovirus D68 in children, Argentina, 2016. Emerg Infect Dis. 2019;25:573&#x2013;576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen IJ, Hu SC, Hung KL, Lo CW. Acute flaccid myelitis associated with enterovirus D68 infection: a case report. Medicine (Baltimore). 2018;97:e11831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho SM, MacDonald S, Frontera JA. Coxsackie B3/B4-related acute flaccid myelitis. Neurocrit Care. 2017;27:259&#x2013;260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong PF, Yoshida T, Yuasa S, Mori H, Tanaka-Taya K, Kira R. Acute flaccid myelitis with neuroradiological finding of brachial plexus swelling. Pediatr Neurol. 2020;109:85&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coriolani G, Ferranti S, Biasci F, Lotti F, Grosso S. Acute flaccid myelitis temporally associated with rhinovirus infection: just a coincidence? Neurol Sci. 2020;41:457&#x2013;458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramer N, Munjal N, Ware D, et al. New cluster of acute flaccid myelitis in Western Pennsylvania. Ann Emerg Med. 2019;74:503&#x2013;508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crone M, Tellier R, Wei XC, et al. Polio-like illness associated with outbreak of upper respiratory tract infection in children. J Child Neurol. 2016;31:409&#x2013;414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doi K, Sem SH, Hattori Y, Sakamoto S, Hayashi K, Maruyama A. Contralateral obturator nerve to femoral nerve transfer for restoration of knee extension after acute flaccid myelitis: a case report. JBJS Case Connect. 2019;9:e0073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donahue ML, Clausen SS, Malloy A, Dennison DH, Falcon J. Acute flaccid myelitis: case report. MSMR. 2019;26:17&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyrdak R, Grabbe M, Hammas B, et al. Outbreak of enterovirus D68 of the new B3 lineage in Stockholm, Sweden, August to September 2016. Euro Surveill. 2016;21:30403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edmiston TL, Elrick MJ, Kovler ML, Jelin EB, Onders RP, Sadowsky CL. Early use of an implantable diaphragm pacing stimulator for a child with severe acute flaccid myelitis: a case report. Spinal Cord Ser Cases. 2019;5:67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elrick MJ, Gordon-Lipkin E, Crawford TO, et al. Clinical subpopulations in a sample of North American children diagnosed with acute flaccid myelitis, 2012-2016. JAMA Pediatr. 2019;173:134&#x2013;139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ertl-Wagner B, Branson H, Shroff M, Bitnun A, Yeh EA. Acute flaccid myelitis in a 10-year-old girl. Radiology. 2019;290:31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito S, Chidini G, Cinnante C, et al. Acute flaccid myelitis associated with enterovirus-D68 infection in an otherwise healthy child. Virol J. 2017;14:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuhara T, Fujii K, Ogawa T, Shiohama T, Shimojo N. Acute myelitis associated with human herpesvirus 7 infection. Pediatr Int. 2018;60:198&#x2013;199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giombini E, Rueca M, Barberi W, et al. Enterovirus D68-associated acute flaccid myelitis in immunocompromised woman, Italy. Emerg Infect Dis. 2017;23:1690&#x2013;1693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon-Lipkin E, Munoz LS, Klein JL, Dean J, Izbudak I, Pardo CA. Comparative quantitative clinical, neuroimaging, and functional profiles in children with acute flaccid myelitis at acute and convalescent stages of disease. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2019;61:366&#x2013;375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatayama K, Goto S, Yashiro M, et al. Acute flaccid myelitis associated with enterovirus D68 in a nonepidemic setting. IDCases. 2019;17:e00549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heise CO, de Oliveira AJ, Bhering T, et al. Nerve transfers for acute flaccid myelitis: a case series. Childs Nerv Syst. 2021;37:211&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hidaka I, Matsushige T, Inoue H, Hoshide M, Shirabe K, Hasegawa S. Cytokine profile in a patient with enterovirus D68-associated acute flaccid myelitis. Pediatr Neurol. 2019;99:88&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hovden IA, Pfeiffer HC. Electrodiagnostic findings in acute flaccid myelitis related to enterovirus D68. Muscle Nerve. 2015;52:909&#x2013;910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubner J, Kruse B, Christen HJ, et al. Acute flaccid myelitis in German children in 2016: The return of polio? Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2017;114:551&#x2013;557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iverson SA, Ostdiek S, Prasai S, et al. Notes from the field: cluster of acute flaccid myelitis in five pediatric patients. Maricopa County, Arizona, 2016. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2017;66:758&#x2013;760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesson AM, Choo CM, Troedson C, Thorley BR, Roberts JA. Echovirus 19 associated with a case of acute flaccid paralysis. J Paediatr Child Health. 2013;49:E239&#x2013;E242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DH. Acute flaccid myelitis in a Korean adult. J Korean Med Sci. 2019;34:e39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirolos A, Mark K, Shetty J, et al. Outcome of paediatric acute flaccid myelitis associated with enterovirus D68: a case series. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2019;61:376&#x2013;380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knoester M, Helfferich J, Poelman R, et al. Twenty-nine cases of enterovirus-D68-associated acute flaccid myelitis in Europe 2016: a case series and epidemiologic overview. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2019;38:16&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kornafel T, Tsao EY, Sabelhaus E, Surges L, Apkon SD. Physical and occupational therapy for a teenager with acute flaccid myelitis: a case report. Phys Occup Ther Pediatr. 2017;37:485&#x2013;595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levin J, Siddiqi AR, Kim H. Capsular distention for adhesive capsulitis in a pediatric patient with acute flaccid myelitis: a case report. J Pediatr Rehabil Med. 2021;14:37&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubelski D, Pennington Z, Tuffaha S, Moore A, Belzberg AJ. Sciatic-to-femoral nerve end-to-end coaptation for proximal lower extremity function in patients with acute flaccid myelitis: technical note and review of the literature. Oper Neurosurg (Hagerstown). 2021;21:20&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makhani N, Mahajan A. Abnormal fluid-attenuated inversion recovery signal in the internal capsule: a novel brain magnetic resonance imaging finding in a child with acute flaccid myelitis. Pediatr Neurol. 2017;73:108&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marciniak C, Sorosky S, Hynes C. Acute flaccid paralysis associated with West Nile virus: motor and functional improvement in 4 patients. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2004;85:1933&#x2013;1938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore AM, Bettlach CR, Tung TT, West JM, Russo SA. Lower extremity nerve transfers in acute flaccid myelitis patients: a case series. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2021;9:e3699.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath RK, Somasundaram C. Functional improvement of upper and lower extremity after decompression and neurolysis and nerve transfer in a pediatric patient with acute flaccid myelitis. Am J Case Rep. 2019;20:668&#x2013;673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson GR, Bonkowsky JL, Doll E, et al. Recognition and management of acute flaccid myelitis in children. Pediatr Neurol. 2016;55:17&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passiak BS, Vogt MR, Wolf M, Sarma A, Vu N. A severe case of enterovirus A71 acute flaccid myelitis with encephalitis. J Pediatric Infect Dis Soc. 2020;9:777&#x2013;780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez G, Rosanova MT, Freire MC, et al. Unusual increase of cases of myelitis in a pediatric hospital in Argentina. Arch Argent Pediatr. 2017;115:364&#x2013;369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeiffer HC, Bragstad K, Skram MK, et al. Two cases of acute severe flaccid myelitis associated with enterovirus D68 infection in children, Norway, autumn 2014. Euro Surveill. 2015;20:21062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabinovich RV, Pino PA, Aversano M, Kozin SH, Zlotolow DA. Nerve transfers for restoration of elbow flexion in patients with acute flaccid myelitis. J Hand Surg Am. 2022;47:91.e1&#x2013;91.e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggieri V, Paz MI, Peretti MG, et al. Enterovirus D68 infection in a cluster of children with acute flaccid myelitis, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 2016. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2017;21:884&#x2013;890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarmast SN, Gowda VK, Ahmed M, Gv B, Saini J, Benakappa A. Acute flaccid myelitis: clustering of polio-like illness in the tertiary care centre in Southern India. J Trop Pediatr. 2019;65:309&#x2013;314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sierakowski J, Arthur J, Wylie T. Acute hypotonia in an infant. J Emerg Med. 2017;52:e245&#x2013;e247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Zhang P, Li J, et al. Enterovirus D68 in a 6-year-old acute flaccid myelitis case in China, 2018: a case report. BMC Infect Dis. 2020;20:125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber EL, Werner JM, Johnson MB, et al. Characteristics of upper extremity recovery in acute flaccid myelitis: a case series. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2021;147:645&#x2013;655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werner JM, Berggren J, Kim G, et al. Recommendations for therapy following nerve transfer for children with acute flaccid myelitis. Phys Occup Ther Pediatr. 2021;41:209&#x2013;226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yogo N, Imamura T, Muto Y, Hirai K. Cardiopulmonary failure as a result of brainstem encephalitis caused by enterovirus D68. BMJ Case Rep. 2019;12:e231990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubart M, Gitiaux C, Roux CJ, et al. Severe acute flaccid myelitis associated with enterovirus in children: two phenotypes for two evolution profiles? Front Neurol. 2020;11:343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doi K, Sem SH, Hattori Y, Sakamoto S, Hayashi K, De la Red-Gallego MA. Surgical reconstruction for upper-extremity paralysis following acute flaccid myelitis. JB JS Open Access. 2019;4:e0030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downey R, McElvain D, Murphey DK, et al. Acute flaccid myelitis among hospitalized children in Texas, 2016. Pediatr Neurol. 2020;106:50&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong L, Wang Y, Zhang W, et al. Acute flaccid myelitis in children in Zhejiang Province, China. Front Neurol. 2020;11:360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrar DB, Darras BT, Ghosh PS. Acute neuromuscular disorders in the pediatric intensive care unit. J Child Neurol. 2020;35:17&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matesanz S, McGuire JL, Hopkins S. Acute flaccid myelitis: characteristics and outcomes of 2014 and 2016 cases at a single center. J Pediatr. 2019;215:272&#x2013;276.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melicosta ME, Dean J, Hagen K, et al. Acute flaccid myelitis: rehabilitation challenges and outcomes in a pediatric cohort. J Pediatr Rehabil Med. 2019;12:245&#x2013;253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messacar K, Sillau S, Hopkins SE, et al. Safety, tolerability, and efficacy of fluoxetine as an antiviral for acute flaccid myelitis. Neurology. 2019;92:e2118&#x2013;e2126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel R, Gombolay GY, Peljovich AE, et al. Acute flaccid myelitis: a single pediatric center experience from 2014 to 2019. J Child Neurol. 2020;35:912&#x2013;917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paziuk TM, Tadley M, Aversano M, Kozin SH, Zlotolow DA. The utilization of nerve transfer for reestablishing shoulder function in the setting of acute flaccid myelitis: a single-institution review. Pediatr Neurol. 2020;111:17&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pino PA, Intravia J, Kozin SH, Zlotolow DA. Early results of nerve transfers for restoring function in severe cases of acute flaccid myelitis. Ann Neurol. 2019;86:607&#x2013;615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed M, Zaidi SZ, Naeem A, et al. Epidemiology and clinical findings associated with enteroviral acute flaccid paralysis in Pakistan. BMC Infect Dis. 2007;7:6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen EW, Kornberg AJ, Freeman JL, Leventer RJ, Ryan MM. Acute flaccid myelitis in childhood: a retrospective cohort study. Eur J Neurol. 2017;24:1077&#x2013;1083.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CY, Chang YC, Huang CC, Lui CC, Lee KW, Huang SC. Acute flaccid paralysis in infants and young children with enterovirus 71 infection: MR imaging findings and clinical correlates. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2001;22:200&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortese MM, Kambhampati AK, Schuster JE, et al. A ten-year retrospective evaluation of acute flaccid myelitis at 5 pediatric centers in the United States, 2005-2014. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0228671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Kang B, Hwang S, et al. Clinical and enterovirus findings associated with acute flaccid paralysis in the Republic of Korea during the recent decade. J Med Virol. 2014;86:1584&#x2013;1589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maloney JA, Mirsky DM, Messacar K, Dominguez SR, Schreiner T, Stence NV. MRI findings in children with acute flaccid paralysis and cranial nerve dysfunction occurring during the 2014 enterovirus D68 outbreak. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2015;36:245&#x2013;250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin JA, Messacar K, Yang ML, et al. Outcomes of Colorado children with acute flaccid myelitis at 1 year. Neurology. 2017;89:129&#x2013;137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCoy DB, Talbott JF, Wilson M, et al. MRI atlas-based measurement of spinal cord injury predicts outcome in acute flaccid myelitis. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2017;38:410&#x2013;417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okumura A, Mori H, Fee Chong P, et al. Serial MRI findings of acute flaccid myelitis during an outbreak of enterovirus D68 infection in Japan. Brain Dev. 2019;41:443&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sejvar JJ, Lopez AS, Cortese MM, et al. Acute flaccid myelitis in the United States, August&#x2013;December 2014: results of nationwide surveillance. Clin Infect Dis. 2016;63:737&#x2013;745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao J, Thorley B, Elliott EJ, McIntyre P, Britton PN. Acute flaccid myelitis: has it gone unrecognised in Australian children? Commun Dis Intell (2018). 2020;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowers JR, Valentine M, Harrison V, et al. Genomic analyses of acute flaccid myelitis cases among a cluster in Arizona provide further evidence of enterovirus D68 role. mBio. 2019;10:e02262-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breitwieser FP, Pardo CA, Salzberg SL. Re-analysis of metagenomic sequences from acute flaccid myelitis patients reveals alternatives to enterovirus D68 infection. F1000Res. 2015;4:180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greninger AL, Naccache SN, Messacar K, et al. A novel outbreak enterovirus D68 strain associated with acute flaccid myelitis cases in the USA (2012-14): a retrospective cohort study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2015;15:671&#x2013;682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kane MS, Sonne C, Zhu S, et al. Incidence, risk factors and outcomes among children with acute flaccid myelitis: a population-based cohort study in a California health network between 2011 and 2016. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2019;38:667&#x2013;672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaren N, Lopez A, Kidd S, et al. Characteristics of patients with acute flaccid myelitis, United States, 2015-2018. Emerg Infect Dis. 2020;26:212&#x2013;219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messacar K, Spence-Davizon E, Osborne C, et al. Clinical characteristics of enterovirus A71 neurological disease during an outbreak in children in Colorado, USA, in 2018: An observational cohort study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20:230&#x2013;239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uprety P, Curtis D, Elkan M, et al. Association of enterovirus D68 with acute flaccid myelitis, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA, 2009-2018. Emerg Infect Dis. 2019;25:1676&#x2013;1682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Haren K, Ayscue P, Waubant E, et al. Acute flaccid myelitis of unknown etiology in California, 2012-2015. JAMA. 2015;314:2663&#x2013;2671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yea C, Bitnun A, Branson HM, et al. Association of outcomes in acute flaccid myelitis with identification of enterovirus at presentation: a Canadian, nationwide, longitudinal study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2020;4:828&#x2013;836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bove R, Rowles W, Carleton M, et al. Unmet needs in the evaluation, treatment, and recovery for 167 children affected by acute flaccid myelitis reported by parents through social media. Pediatr Neurol. 2020;102:20&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fall A, Ndiaye N, Messacar K, et al. Enterovirus D68 subclade B3 in children with acute flaccid paralysis in West Africa, 2016. Emerg Infect Dis. 2020;26:2227&#x2013;2230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilrane VL, Zhuge J, Huang W, et al. Biennial upsurge and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus D68 infection in New York, USA, 2014 to 2018. J Clin Microbiol. 2020;58:e00284-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Midgley SE, Benschop K, Dyrdak R, et al. Co-circulation of multiple enterovirus D68 subclades, including a novel B3 cluster, across Europe in a season of expected low prevalence, 2019/20. Euro Surveill. 2020;25:1900749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okumura A, Numoto S, Iwayama H, et al. Respiratory illness and acute flaccid myelitis in the Tokai district in 2018. Pediatr Int. 2020;62:337&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster JE, Newland JG. Management of the 2014 enterovirus 68 outbreak at a pediatric tertiary care center. Clin Ther. 2015;37:2411&#x2013;2418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The United Kingdom Acute Flaccid Paralysis AFP Task Force. An increase in reports of acute flaccid paralysis (AFP) in the United Kingdom, 1 January 2018&#x2013;21 January 2019: Early findings. Euro Surveill. 2019;24:1900093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliabadi N, Messacar K, Pastula DM, et al. Enterovirus D68 infection in children with acute flaccid myelitis, Colorado, USA, 2014. Emerg Infect Dis. 2016;22:1387&#x2013;1394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra N, Ng TFF, Marine RL, et al. Antibodies to enteroviruses in cerebrospinal fluid of patients with acute flaccid myelitis. mBio. 2019;10:e01903-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schubert RD, Hawes IA, Ramachandran PS, et al. Pan-viral serology implicates enteroviruses in acute flaccid myelitis. Nat Med. 2019;25:1748&#x2013;1752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weldon WC, Zhao K, Jost HA, et al. Cytokine biomarkers associated with clinical cases of acute flaccid myelitis. J Clin Virol. 2020;131:104591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown DM, Hixon AM, Oldfield LM, et al. Contemporary circulating enterovirus D68 strains have acquired the capacity for viral entry and replication in human neuronal cells. mBio. 2018;9:e01954-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hixon AM, Yu G, Leser JS, et al. A mouse model of paralytic myelitis caused by enterovirus D68. PLoS Pathog. 2017;13:e1006199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messacar K, Schreiner TL, Van Haren K, et al. Acute flaccid myelitis: a clinical review of US cases 2012-2015. Ann Neurol. 2016;80:326&#x2013;338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith BW, Daunter AK, Yang LJ, Wilson TJ. An update on the management of neonatal brachial plexus palsy: replacing old paradigms. A review. JAMA Pediatr. 2018;172:585&#x2013;591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith BW, Sakamuri S, Spain DA, Joseph JR, Yang LJ, Wilson TJ. An update on the management of adult traumatic nerve injuries: replacing old paradigms: a review. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2019;86:299&#x2013;306.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>