<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36254857</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1615-9861</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Proteomics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Proteomics</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proteomic and metabonomic analysis uncovering Enterovirus A71 reprogramming host cell metabolic pathway.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2200362</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2200362</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/pmic.202200362</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus A71 (EV71) infection can cause hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) and severe neurological complications in children. However, the biological processes regulated by EV71 remain poorly understood. Herein, proteomics and metabonomics studies were conducted to uncover the mechanism of EV71 infection in rhabdomyosarcoma (RD) cells and identify potential drug targets. Differential expressed proteins from enriched membrane were analyzed by isobaric tags for relative and absolute quantitation (iTRAQ)-based proteomics technology. Twenty-six differential proteins with 1.5-fold (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05) change were detected, including 14 upregulated proteins and 12 downregulated proteins. The upregulated proteins are mainly involved in metabolic process, especially in the glycolysis pathway. Alpha-enolase (ENO1) protein was found to increase with temporal dependence following EV71 infection. The targeted metabolomics analysis revealed that glucose absorption and glycolysis metabolites were increased after EV71 infection. The glycolysis pathway was inhibited by knocking down ENO1 or the use of a glycolysis inhibitor (dichloroacetic acid [DCA]); and we found that EV71 infection was inhibited by depleting ENO1 or using DCA. Our study indicates that EV71 may reprogram glucose metabolism by activating glycolysis, and EV71 infection can be inhibited by interrupting the glycolysis pathway. ENO1 may be a potential target against EV71, and DCA could act as an inhibitor of EV71.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Huichun</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Siyuan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The College of Information, Mechanical and Electrical Engineering, Shanghai Normal University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Zhimi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Liyan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Tiefu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Shuye</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Lijun</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Proteomics</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101092707</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1615-9853</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011506">Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040901" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteomics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011506" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055432" MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolomics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053858" MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolic Networks and Pathways</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LC-MS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">alpha-enolase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">iTRAQ</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolomics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plasma membrane</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">proteomics</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36254857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pmic.202200362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Mcminn, P. C. (2002). An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiology Reviews, 26, 91-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Tan, X.-J., Wang, H.-Y., Yan, D.-M., Zhu, S.-L., Wang, D.-Y., Ji, F., Wang, X.-J., Gao, Y.-J., Chen, L., An, H.-Q., Li, D.-X., Wang, S.-W., Xu, A.-Q., Wang, Z.-J., &amp; Xu, W.-B. (2009). An outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with subgenotype C4 of human enterovirus 71 in Shandong, China. Journal of Clinical Virology, 44, 262-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, K.-T., Yan, T.-R., Cheng, Y.-T., Chen, S.-C., &amp; Chang, H.-L. (2007). An eight-year study of epidemiologic features of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. The American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 77, 188-191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J., &amp; Qi, J. (2020). Prevalence and management of severe hand, foot, and mouth disease in Xiangyang, China, from 2008 to 2013, from 2008 to 2013. Frontiers in Pediatrics, 8, 323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, F., Xu, W., Xia, J., Liang, Z., Liu, Y., Zhang, X., Tan, X., Wang, L., Mao, Q., Wu, J., Hu, Y., Ji, T., Song, L., Liang, Q., Zhang, B., Gao, Q., Li, J., Wang, S., Hu, Y., &#x2026; Wang, N. (2014). Efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in China. New England Journal of Medicine, 370, 818-828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, R., Liu, L., Mo, Z., Wang, X., Xia, J., Liang, Z., Zhang, Y., Li, Y., Mao, Q., Wang, J., Jiang, L., Dong, C., Che, Y., Huang, T., Jiang, Z., Xie, Z., Wang, L., Liao, Y., Liang, Y., &#x2026; Li, Q. (2014). An inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy children. New England Journal of Medicine, 370, 829-837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saguil, A., Kane, S. F., Lauters, R., &amp; Mercado, M. G. (2019). Hand-foot-and-mouth disease: Rapid evidence review. American Family Physician, 100, 408-414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aswathyraj, S., Arunkumar, G., Alidjinou, E. K., &amp; Hober, D. (2016). Hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD): Emerging epidemiology and the need for a vaccine strategy. Medical Microbiology and Immunology, 205, 397-407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergelson, J. M., &amp; Coyne, C. B. (2013). Picornavirus entry. Advances in Experimental Medicine and Biology, 790, 24-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura, Y., Shimojima, M., Tano, Y., Miyamura, T., Wakita, T., &amp; Shimizu, H. (2009). Human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is a functional receptor for enterovirus 71. Nature Medicine, 15, 794-797.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi, S., Yamashita, Y., Li, J., Hanagata, N., Minowa, T., Takemura, T., &amp; Koike, S. (2009). Scavenger receptor B2 is a cellular receptor for enterovirus 71. Nature Medicine, 15, 798-801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilipenko, E. V. (2001). Cell-specific proteins regulate viral RNA translation and virus-induced disease. The EMBO Journal, 20, 6899-6908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, P.-N., &amp; Shih, S.-R. (2014). Update on enterovirus 71 infection. Current Opinion in Virology, 5, 98-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Too, I. H. K., Bonne, I., Tan, E. L., Chu, J. J. H., &amp; Alonso, S. (2018). Prohibitin plays a critical role in Enterovirus 71 neuropathogenesis. PLoS Pathogens, 14, e1006778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Wang, Y., Wang, S., Meng, X., Song, F., Huo, W., Zhang, S., Chang, J., Li, J., Zheng, B., Liu, Y., Zhang, Y., Zhang, W., &amp; Yu, J. (2018). Coxsackievirus A6 induces cell cycle arrest in G0/G1 phase for viral production. Frontiers in Cellular and Infection Microbiology, 8, 279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, F., Yu, X., Zhong, T., Wang, Z., Meng, X., Li, Z., Zhang, S., Huo, W., Liu, X., Zhang, Y., Zhang, W., &amp; Yu, J. (2018). Caspase-3 inhibition attenuates the cytopathic effects of EV71 infection. Frontiers in Microbiology, 9, 817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B., Zhang, C., Yu, C., Zhu, Y., Tang, Q., Huang, H., &amp; Zhao, Z. (2021). Enterovirus 71 induces INF2 cleavage via activated caspase-2 in infected RD cells. Frontiers in Microbiology, 12, 684953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H., Li, F., Pan, Z., Wu, Z., Wang, Y., &amp; Cui, Y. (2014). Activation of PI3K/Akt pathway limits JNK-mediated apoptosis during EV71 infection. Virus Research, 192, 74-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Y.-Z., Wu, D.-G., Ren, H., Xu, Q.-Q., Zheng, K.-C., Chen, W., Chen, S.-L., Qian, X.-J., Tao, Q.-Y., Wang, Y., Zhao, P., &amp; Qi, Z.-T. (2015). The role of lipid rafts in the early stage of Enterovirus 71 infection. Cellular Physiology and Biochemistry, 35, 1347-1359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, H.-Y., Yang, Y.-T., Yu, S.-L., Hsiao, K.-N., Liu, C.-C., Sia, C., &amp; Chow, Y.-H., Caveolar endocytosis is required for human PSGL-1-mediated enterovirus 71 infection. Journal of Virology, 87, 9064-9076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong, W. F., &amp; Chow, V. T. K. (2006). Transcriptomic and proteomic analyses of rhabdomyosarcoma cells reveal differential cellular gene expression in response to enterovirus 71 infection. Cellular Microbiology, 8, 565-580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, R. Y. L., Kuo, R.-L., Ma, W.-C., Huang, H.-I., Yu, J.-S., Yen, S.-M., Huang, C.-R., &amp; Shih, S.-R. (2013). Heat shock protein-90-beta facilitates enterovirus 71 viral particles assembly. Virology, 443, 236-247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L., Jia, X., Zhang, X., Cao, J., Yang, P., Qiu, C., Shen, Y., Ma, F., Liu, L., Sun, J., Shen, F., Yin, L., Liu, L., Yao, Y., &amp; Lu, H. (2010). Alpha-1 antitrypsin variants in plasma from HIV-infected patients revealed by proteomic and glycoproteomic analysis. Electrophoresis, 31, 3437-3445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L., Jia, X., Feng, Y., Peng, X., Zhang, Z., Zhou, W., Zhang, Z., Ma, F., Liu, X., Zheng, Y., Yang, P., &amp; Yuan, Z. (2010). Plasma membrane proteome analysis of the early effect of alcohol on liver: Implications for alcoholic liver disease. Acta Biochimica et Biophysica Sinica (Shanghai), 43, 19-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z., Zhang, L., Hua, Y., Jia, X., Li, J., Hu, S., Peng, X., Yang, P., Sun, M., Ma, F., &amp; Cai, Z. (2010). Comparative proteomic analysis of plasma membrane proteins between human osteosarcoma and normal osteoblastic cell lines. BMC Cancer, 10, 206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shilov, I. V., Seymour, S. L., Patel, A. A., Loboda, A., Tang, W. H., Keating, S. P., Hunter, C. L., Nuwaysir, L. M., &amp; Schaeffer, D. A. (2007). The Paragon Algorithm, a next generation search engine that uses sequence temperature values and feature probabilities to identify peptides from tandem mass spectra. Molecular &amp; Cellular Proteomics, 6, 1638-1655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, H., Yang, Y., Allister, E. M., Wijesekara, N., &amp; Wheeler, M. B. (2008). The identification of potential factors associated with the development of type 2 diabetes: A quantitative proteomics approach. Molecular &amp; Cellular Proteomics, 7, 1434-1451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon, P., Markiel, A., Ozier, O., Baliga, N. S., Wang, J. T., Ramage, D., Amin, N., Schwikowski, B., &amp; Ideker, T. (2003). Cytoscape: A software environment for integrated models of biomolecular interaction networks. Genome Research, 13, 2498-2504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaker, S. K., Chapa, T., Garcia, G., Gong, D., Schmid, E. W., Arumugaswami, V., Sun, R., &amp; Christofk, H. R. (2019). Differential metabolic reprogramming by zika virus promotes cell death in human versus mosquito cells. Cell Metabolism, 29, 1206-1216.e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodgers, M. A., Saghatelian, A., &amp; Yang, P. L. (2009). Identification of an overabundant cholesterol precursor in hepatitis B virus replicating cells by untargeted lipid metabolite profiling. Journal of the American Chemical Society, 131, 5030-5031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H., Zhu, W., Zhang, L., Lei, H., Wu, X., Guo, L., Chen, X., Wang, Y., &amp; Tang, H. (2015). The metabolic responses to hepatitis B virus infection shed new light on pathogenesis and targets for treatment. Scientific Reports, 5, 8421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, Y.-X., Huang, C.-J., &amp; Yang, Z.-G. (2016). Impact of hepatitis B virus infection on hepatic metabolic signaling pathway. World Journal of Gastroenterology, 22, 8161-8167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, K. (2000). Hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak reported in Singapore. Lancet, 356, 1338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, J.-Y., &amp; Shih, S.-R. (2014). Cell and tissue tropism of enterovirus 71 and other enteroviruses infections. Journal of Biomedical Science, 21, 18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, H.-I., Weng, K.-F., &amp; Shih, S.-R. (2012). Viral and host factors that contribute to pathogenicity of enterovirus 71. Future Microbiology, 7, 467-479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, K. X., Phuektes, P., Kumar, P., Goh, G. Y. L., Moreau, D., Chow, V. T. K., Bard, F., &amp; Chu, J. J. H. (2016). Human genome-wide RNAi screen reveals host factors required for enterovirus 71 replication. Nature Communications, 7, 13150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain, K. M., Leong, K. L. J., Ng, M. M.-L., &amp; Chu, J. J. H. (2011). The essential role of clathrin-mediated endocytosis in the infectious entry of human enterovirus 71. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 286, 309-321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber, S. A., Bruett, L., Douglass, B. R., Herbst, D. S., Zink, M. C, &amp; Clements, J. E. (2002). Visna virus-induced activation of MAPK is required for virus replication and correlates with virus-induced neuropathology. Journal of Virology, 76, 817-828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung, W.-H., Hsieh, H.-L., &amp; Yang, C.-M. (2010). Enterovirus 71 induces COX-2 expression via MAPKs, NF-kappaB, and AP-1 in SK-N-SH cells: Role of PGE(2) in viral replication. Cellular Signalling, 22, 234-246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, W.-R., Chen, Y.-Y., Yang, S.-M., Chen, Y.-L., &amp; Horng, J.-T. (2005). Phosphorylation of PI3K/Akt and MAPK/ERK in an early entry step of enterovirus 71. Life Sciences, 78, 82-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L., Jia, X., Jin, J.-O., Lu, H., &amp; Tan, Z. (2017). Recent 5-year findings and technological advances in the proteomic study of HIV-associated disorders. Genomics Proteomics Bioinformatics, 15, 110-120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coombs, K. M. (2020). Update on proteomic approaches to uncovering virus-induced protein alterations and virus -host protein interactions during the progression of viral infection. Expert Review of Proteomics, 17, 513-532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, J. J., Seah, J. B. K., Chow, V. T. K., Poh, C. L., &amp; Tan, E. L. (2011). Comparative proteome analyses of host protein expression in response to Enterovirus 71 and Coxsackievirus A16 infections. Journal of Proteomics, 74, 2018-2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo, R.-L., Lin, Y.-H., Wang, R. Y.-L., Hsu, C.-W., Chiu, Y.-T., Huang, H.-I., Kao, L.-T., Yu, J.-S., Shih, S.-R., &amp; Wu, C.-C. (2015). Proteomics analysis of EV71-infected cells reveals the involvement of host protein NEDD4L in EV71 replication. Journal of Proteome Research, 14, 1818-1830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, N. X., Zou, Y., Liang, Q. H., Wang, Y. E., Liu, Y. L., Xu, G. Q., Fan, H., Xu, Q., Yang, S., &amp; Yu, D. (2021). Anemoside B4 inhibits enterovirus 71 propagation in mice through upregulating 14-3-3 expression and type I interferon responses. Acta Pharmacologica Sinica, 43(4), 977-991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, F., Chen, X., Chen, G., Yan, J., &amp; Xiao, Y. (2019). Identification of SAA and ACTB as potential biomarker of patients with severe HFMD using iTRAQ quantitative proteomics. Clinical Biochemistry, 67, 1-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, Y., Li, D., Sun, T., Du, Y., Gao, Y., Ding, R., Ji, W., Zhang, W., Yang, H., Chen, S., &amp; Duan, G. (2021). Pathological features of Enterovirus 71-associated brain and lung damage in mice based on quantitative proteomic analysis. Frontiers in Microbiology, 12, 663019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L.-K., Lin, T., Zhu, S.-L., Xianyu, L.-Z., &amp; Lu, S.-Y. (2015). Global quantitative proteomic analysis of human glioma cells profiled host protein expression in response to enterovirus type 71 infection. Proteomics, 15, 3784-3796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, L., Ma, Y., Zhou, H., &amp; Wu, M. (2016). Quantitative proteomic analysis of Escherichia coli heat-labile toxin B subunit (LTB) with Enterovirus 71 (EV71) subunit VP1. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 17, 1419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, H.-I., Chang, Y.-Y., Lin, J.-Y., Kuo, R.-L., Liu, H.-P., Shih, S.-R., &amp; Wu, C.-C. (2016). Interactome analysis of the EV71 5&#x2032; untranslated region in differentiated neuronal cells SH-SY5Y and regulatory role of FBP3 in viral replication. Proteomics, 16, 2351-2362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polcicova, K., Badurova, L., &amp; Tomaskova, J. (2020). Metabolic reprogramming as a feast for virus replication. Acta Virologica, 64, 201-215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontaine, K. A., Sanchez, E. L., Camarda, R., &amp; Lagunoff, M. (2015). Dengue virus induces and requires glycolysis for optimal replication. Journal of Virology, 89, 2358-2366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manchester, M., &amp; Anand, A. (2017). Metabolomics: Strategies to define the role of metabolism in virus infection and pathogenesis. Advances in Virus Research, 98, 57-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, A. A., Sitole, L. J., &amp; Meyer, D. (2017). HIV/HAART-associated oxidative stress is detectable by metabonomics. Molecular BioSystems, 13, 2202-2217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diamond, D. L., Syder, A. J., Jacobs, J. M., Sorensen, C. M., Walters, K.-A., Proll, S. C., Mcdermott, J. E., Gritsenko, M. A., Zhang, Q., Zhao, R., Metz, T. O., Camp, D. G., Waters, K. M., Smith, R. D., Rice, C. M., &amp; Katze, M. G. (2010). Temporal proteome and lipidome profiles reveal hepatitis C virus-associated reprogramming of hepatocellular metabolism and bioenergetics. PLoS Pathogens, 6, e1000719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualdoni, G. A., Mayer, K. A., Kapsch, A. M., Kreuzberg, K., Puck, A., Kienzl, P., Oberndorfer, F., Fr&#xfc;hwirth, K., Winkler, S., Blaas, D., Zlabinger, G. J., &amp; Stockl, J. (2018). Rhinovirus induces an anabolic reprogramming in host cell metabolism essential for viral replication. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 115, E7158-E7165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman, E. R., Kulkarni, M., Gabriel, J., Cichon, M. J., Riedl, K., Belury, M. A., Lake, J. E., Richardson, B., Cameron, C., Cameron, M., Koletar, S. L., Lederman, M. M., Sieg, S. F., &amp; Funderburg, N. T. (2019). Altered lipidome composition is related to markers of monocyte and immune activation in antiretroviral therapy treated human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection and in uninfected persons. Frontiers in Immunology, 10, 785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prusinkiewicz, M. A., Tu, J., Dodge, M. J., MacNeil, K. M., Radko-Juettner, S., Fonseca, G. J., Pelka, P., &amp; Mymryk, J. S. (2020). Differential effects of human adenovirus E1A protein isoforms on aerobic glycolysis in A549 human lung epithelial cells. Viruses, 12, 610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thai, M., Graham, N. A., Braas, D., Nehil, M., Komisopoulou, E., Kurdistani, S. K., Mccormick, F., Graeber, T. G., &amp; Christofk, H. R. (2014). Adenovirus E4ORF1-induced MYC activation promotes host cell anabolic glucose metabolism and virus replication. Cell Metabolism, 19, 694-701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, M. L., Chien, K. Y., Lai, C. H., Li, G. J., Lin, J. F., &amp; Ho, H. Y. (2020). Metabolic reprogramming of host cells in response to enteroviral infection. Cells, 9, 473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, Q. F., Liu, Y., Fan, Y., Hua, S. N., Qu, H. Y., Dong, S. W., Li, R.-L., Zhao, M.-Y., Zhen, Y., Yu, X.-L., Chen, Y.-Y., Luo, R.-C., Li, R., Li, L.-B., Deng, X.-J., Fang, W.-Y., Liu, Z., &amp; Song, X. (2015). Alpha-enolase promotes cell glycolysis, growth, migration, and invasion in non-small cell lung cancer through FAK-mediated PI3K/AKT pathway. Journal of Hematology &amp; Oncology, 8, 22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchesini, M. I., Morrone Seijo, S. M., Guaimas, F. F., &amp; Comerci, D. J. (2016). A T4SS effector targets host cell alpha-enolase contributing to Brucella abortus intracellular lifestyle. Frontiers in Cellular and infection Microbiology, 6, 153.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>