<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36308741</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1545-5017</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>70</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pediatric blood &amp; cancer</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Blood Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Viral infections in pediatric brain tumor patients treated with targeted therapies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e30065</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e30065</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/pbc.30065</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Brain tumors are the most common solid malignancies and the leading cause of cancer-related mortality in children. While numerous studies report on viral infections in children with hematologic malignancies and solid organ transplantation, epidemiologic data on the incidence and outcome of viral infections in pediatric patients with brain tumors treated with targeted therapies are still lacking.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES/STUDY DESIGN">We retrospectively reviewed all children with brain tumors receiving targeted therapies in a primary or recurrent setting at the Medical University of Vienna from 2006 to 2021. Demographic variables, quantitative and qualitative parameters of possible infections, and treatment outcomes were recorded.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">In our cohort (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;117), 36% of the patients developed at least one PCR-proven viral infection. Respiratory and gastrointestinal tract infections were most common, with 31% and 25%, respectively. Central nervous system (CNS) infections occurred in approximately 10%, with an almost equal distribution of varicella-zoster virus, John Cunningham virus (JCV), and enterovirus. Two patients tested PCR-positive for SARS-CoV-2 infection, with one virus-related death caused by a SARS-CoV-2-related acute respiratory distress syndrome. Patients receiving bevacizumab or mTOR inhibitors seem to have a greater susceptibility to viral infections.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Pediatric patients with brain tumors receiving targeted therapies have a higher risk of viral infections when compared to children receiving conventional chemotherapy or the general population, and life-threatening infections can occur. Fast detection and upfront treatment are paramount to prevent life-threatening infections in immunocompromised children suffering from brain tumors receiving targeted therapies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Authors. Pediatric Blood &amp; Cancer published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mayr</LastName><ForeName>Lisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Adolescent Medicine, Comprehensive Cancer Center for Pediatrics, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steinmaurer</LastName><ForeName>Tobias</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Adolescent Medicine, Comprehensive Cancer Center for Pediatrics, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weseslindtner</LastName><ForeName>Lukas</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Virology, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Madlener</LastName><ForeName>Sibylle</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Adolescent Medicine, Comprehensive Cancer Center for Pediatrics, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strassl</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gojo</LastName><ForeName>Johannes</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Adolescent Medicine, Comprehensive Cancer Center for Pediatrics, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azizi</LastName><ForeName>Amedeo A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1347-6644</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Adolescent Medicine, Comprehensive Cancer Center for Pediatrics, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Slavc</LastName><ForeName>Irene</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Adolescent Medicine, Comprehensive Cancer Center for Pediatrics, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peyrl</LastName><ForeName>Andreas</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5736-8231</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Adolescent Medicine, Comprehensive Cancer Center for Pediatrics, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Blood Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101186624</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1545-5009</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2023 Apr;70(4):e30146. doi: 10.1002/pbc.30146</RefSource><PMID Version="1">36495258</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2023 May;70(5):e30220. doi: 10.1002/pbc.30220</RefSource><PMID Version="1">36694406</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014777" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001932" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CNS infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain tumor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">targeted therapies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">viral infection</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36308741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pbc.30065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Tailor J, Jackson EM. Brain and spinal cord tumors in children. Pediatr Clin North Am. 2021;68(4):811-824. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pcl.2021.04.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollack IF, Agnihotri S, Broniscer A. Childhood brain tumors: current management, biological insights, and future directions. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2019;23(3):261-273. https://doi.org/10.3171/2018.10.PEDS18377</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller T, Stucklin ASG, Postlmayr A, et&#xa0;al. Advances in targeted therapies for pediatric brain tumors. Curr Treat Options Neurol. 2020;22(12):43. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11940-020-00651-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunkel IJ, Gardner SL, Garvin JH, Goldman S, Shi W, Finlay JL. High-dose carboplatin, thiotepa, and etoposide with autologous stem cell rescue for patients with previously irradiated recurrent medulloblastoma. Neuro Oncol. 2010;12(3):297-303. https://doi.org/10.1093/neuonc/nop031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih CS, Hale GA, Gronewold L, et&#xa0;al. High-dose chemotherapy with autologous stem cell rescue for children with recurrent malignant brain tumors. Cancer. 2008;112(6):1345-1353. https://doi.org/10.1002/cncr.23305</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koskenvuo M, Rahiala J, Sadeghi M, et&#xa0;al. Viremic co-infections in children with allogeneic haematopoietic stem cell transplantation are predominated by human polyomaviruses. Infect Dis (Lond). 2017;49(1):35-41. https://doi.org/10.1080/23744235.2016.1210821</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soudani N, Caniza MA, Assaf-Casals A, et&#xa0;al. Prevalence and characteristics of acute respiratory virus infections in pediatric cancer patients. J Med Virol. 2019;91(7):1191-1201. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.25432</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye X, Van JN, Munoz FM, et&#xa0;al. Noroviruses as a cause of diarrhea in immunocompromised pediatric hematopoietic stem cell and solid organ transplant recipients. Am J Transplant. 2015;15(7):1874-1881. https://doi.org/10.1111/ajt.13227</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bordon V, Bravo S, Van Renterghem L, et&#xa0;al. Surveillance of cytomegalovirus (CMV) DNAemia in pediatric allogeneic stem cell transplantation: incidence and outcome of CMV infection and disease. Transpl Infect Dis. 2008;10(1):19-23. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1399-3062.2007.00242.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millen GC, Arnold R, Cazier JB, et&#xa0;al. Severity of COVID-19 in children with cancer: report from the United Kingdom Paediatric Coronavirus Cancer Monitoring Project. Br J Cancer. 2021;124(4):754-759. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41416-020-01181-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Y, Mo X, Hu Y, et&#xa0;al. Epidemiology of COVID-19 among children in China. Pediatrics. 2020;145(6):e20200702. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2020-0702</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukkada S, Bhakta N, Chantada GL, et&#xa0;al. Global characteristics and outcomes of SARS-CoV-2 infection in children and adolescents with cancer (GRCCC):a cohort study. Lancet Oncol. 2021;22(10):1416-1426. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1470-2045(21)00454-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peyrl A, Chocholous M, Kieran MW, et&#xa0;al. Antiangiogenic metronomic therapy for children with recurrent embryonal brain tumors. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2012;59(3):511-517. https://doi.org/10.1002/pbc.24006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward CL, Dempsey MH, Ring CJA, et&#xa0;al. Design and performance testing of quantitative real time PCR assays for influenza A and B viral load measurement. J Clin Virol. 2004;29(3):179-188. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1386-6532(03)00122-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heim A, Ebnet C, Harste G, Pring-Akerblom P. Rapid and quantitative detection of human adenovirus DNA by real-time PCR. J Med Virol. 2003;70(2):228-239. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.10382</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry AM, Chittaganpitch M, Baggett HC, et&#xa0;al. The burden of hospitalized lower respiratory tract infection due to respiratory syncytial virus in rural Thailand. PLoS One. 2010;5(11):e15098. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0015098</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X, Holloway B, Dare RK, et&#xa0;al. Real-time reverse transcription-PCR assay for comprehensive detection of human rhinoviruses. J Clin Microbiol. 2008;46(2):533-539. https://doi.org/10.1128/JCM.01739-07</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maertzdorf J, Wang CK, Brown JB, et&#xa0;al. Real-time reverse transcriptase PCR assay for detection of human metapneumoviruses from all known genetic lineages. J Clin Microbiol. 2004;42(3):981-986. https://doi.org/10.1128/JCM.42.3.981-986.2004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corman VM, Landt O, Kaiser M, et&#xa0;al. Detection of 2019 novel coronavirus (2019-nCoV) by real-time RT-PCR. Euro Surveill. 2020;25(3):2000045. https://doi.org/10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2020.25.3.2000045</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watkins-Riedel T, Woegerbauer M, Hollemann D, Hufnagl P. Rapid diagnosis of enterovirus infections by real-time PCR on the LightCycler using the TaqMan format. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis. 2002;42(2):99-105. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0732-8893(01)00330-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weseslindtner L, Hedman L, Wang Y, et&#xa0;al. Longitudinal assessment of the CXCL10 blood and urine concentration in kidney transplant recipients with BK polyomavirus replication-a retrospective study. Transpl Int. 2020;33(5):555-566. https://doi.org/10.1111/tri.13584</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aberle SW, Puchhammer-St&#xf6;ckl E. Diagnosis of herpesvirus infections of the central nervous system. J Clin Virol. 2002;25(1):S79-S85. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1386-6532(02)00037-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez C, Boutolleau D, Manichanh C, Mangeney N, Agut H, Gautheret-Dejean A. Quantitation of HHV-7 genome by real-time polymerase chain reaction assay using MGB probe technology. J Virol Methods. 2002;106(1):11-16. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0166-0934(02)00131-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lustberg MB. Management of neutropenia in cancer patients. Clin Adv Hematol Oncol. 2012;10(12):825-826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolston KVI. Infections in cancer patients with solid tumors: a review. Infect Dis Ther. 2017;6(1):69-83. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40121-017-0146-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majhail NS. Long-term complications after hematopoietic cell transplantation. Hematol Oncol Stem Cell Ther. 2017;10(4):220-227. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hemonc.2017.05.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gea-Banacloche JC, Wade JC. Improvements in the prevention and management of infectious complications after hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Cancer Treat Res. 2009;144:539-573. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-0-387-78580-6_21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young JAH. Management of infectious diseases in stem cell transplantation and hematologic malignancy. Infect Dis Clin North Am. 2019;33(2):xiii-xv. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.idc.2019.02.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young JAH, Logan BR, Wu J, et&#xa0;al. Infections after transplantation of bone marrow or peripheral blood stem cells from unrelated donors. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant. 2016;22(2):359-370. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbmt.2015.09.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexandersson A, Koskenvuo M, Tiderman A, et&#xa0;al. Viral infections and immune reconstitution interaction after pediatric allogenic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Infect Dis (Lond). 2019;51(10):772-778. https://doi.org/10.1080/23744235.2019.1650198</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zitvogel L, Apetoh L, Ghiringhelli F, Kroemer G. Immunological aspects of cancer chemotherapy. Nat Rev Immunol. 2008;8(1):59-73. https://doi.org/10.1038/nri2216</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne DC, Vinj&#xe9; J, Szilagyi PG, et&#xa0;al. Norovirus and medically attended gastroenteritis in U.S. children. N Engl J Med. 2013;368(12):1121-1130. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMsa1206589</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avery RK, Lonze BE, Kraus ES, Marr KA, Montgomery RA. Severe chronic norovirus diarrheal disease in transplant recipients: clinical features of an under-recognized syndrome. Transpl Infect Dis. 2017;19(2):e12674. https://doi.org/10.1111/tid.12674</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ison MG, Hirsch HH. Community-acquired respiratory viruses in transplant patients: diversity, impact, unmet clinical needs. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2019;32(4):e00042-19. https://doi.org/10.1128/CMR.00042-19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koskenvuo M, M&#xf6;tt&#xf6;nen M, Rahiala J, et&#xa0;al. Respiratory viral infections in children with leukemia. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2008;27(11):974-980. https://doi.org/10.1097/INF.0b013e31817b0799</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen MS, Nielsen LP, Hasle H. Few but severe viral infections in children with cancer: a prospective RT-PCR and PCR-based 12-month study. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2005;45(7):945-951. https://doi.org/10.1002/pbc.20469</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindblom A, Bhadri V, S&#xf6;derh&#xe4;ll S, et&#xa0;al. Respiratory viruses, a common microbiological finding in neutropenic children with fever. J Clin Virol. 2010;47(3):234-237. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcv.2009.11.026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan A, Gu Z, Smith T, et&#xa0;al. Prospective detection of respiratory pathogens in symptomatic children with cancer. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2013;32(3):e99-e104. https://doi.org/10.1097/INF.0b013e31827bd619</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin B, Kennedy B, McBride J, et&#xa0;al. Long-term morbidity of respiratory viral infections during chemotherapy in children with leukaemia. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2019;54(11):1821-1829. https://doi.org/10.1002/ppul.24456</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijenthira A, Gong IY, Fox TA, et&#xa0;al. Outcomes of patients with hematologic malignancies and COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of 3377 patients. Blood. 2020;136(25):2881-2892. https://doi.org/10.1182/blood.2020008824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai M, Liu D, Liu M, et&#xa0;al. Patients with cancer appear more vulnerable to SARS-CoV-2: a multicenter study during the COVID-19 outbreak. Cancer Discov. 2020;10(6):783-791. https://doi.org/10.1158/2159-8290.CD-20-0422</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andr&#xe9; N, Rouger-Gaudichon J, Brethon B, et&#xa0;al. COVID-19 in pediatric oncology from French pediatric oncology and hematology centers: high risk of severe forms? Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2020;67(7):e28392. https://doi.org/10.1002/pbc.28392</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hrusak O, Kalina T, Wolf J, et&#xa0;al. Flash survey on severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 infections in paediatric patients on anticancer treatment. Eur J Cancer. 2020;132:11-16. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejca.2020.03.021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf6;tzinger F, Santiago-Garc&#xed;a B, Noguera-Juli&#xe1;n A, et&#xa0;al. COVID-19 in children and adolescents in Europe: a multinational, multicentre cohort study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2020;4(9):653-661. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2352-4642(20)30177-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari A, Zecca M, Rizzari C, et&#xa0;al. Children with cancer in the time of COVID-19: an 8-week report from the six pediatric onco-hematology centers in Lombardia, Italy. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2020;67(8):e28410. https://doi.org/10.1002/pbc.28410</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Rojas T, P&#xe9;rez-Mart&#xed;nez A, Cela E, et&#xa0;al. COVID-19 infection in children and adolescents with cancer in Madrid. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2020;67(7):e28397. https://doi.org/10.1002/pbc.28397</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens RJ, Liang SY. Central nervous system infections in the immunocompromised adult presenting to the emergency department. Emerg Med Clin North Am. 2021;39(1):101-121. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.emc.2020.09.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rantakallio P, Leskinen M, von Wendt L. Incidence and prognosis of central nervous system infections in a birth cohort of 12,000 children. Scand J Infect Dis. 1986;18(4):287-294. https://doi.org/10.3109/00365548609032339</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Abid F, Abukhattab M, Ghazouani H, et&#xa0;al. Epidemiology and clinical outcomes of viral central nervous system infections. Int J Infect Dis. 2018;73:85-90. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2018.06.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Ory F, Avell&#xf3;n A, Echevarr&#xed;a JE, et&#xa0;al. Viral infections of the central nervous system in Spain: a prospective study. J Med Virol. 2013;85(3):554-562. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.23470</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grahn A, Studahl M. Varicella-zoster virus infections of the central nervous system - prognosis, diagnostics and treatment. J Infect. 2015;71(3):281-293. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2015.06.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger JR, Aksamit AJ, Clifford DB, et&#xa0;al. PML diagnostic criteria: consensus statement from the AAN Neuroinfectious Disease Section. Neurology. 2013;80(15):1430-1438. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e31828c2fa1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto M, Dobson S. BK, and JC virus: a review. J Infect. 2014;68(1):S2-S8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2013.09.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demirbu&#x11f;a A, Kaba O, T&#xf6;r&#xfc;n SH, Y&#x131;ld&#x131;z EP, Y&#xfc;cel E, Somer A. Progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy in children with primary and secondary immune deficiency. Pediatr Allergy Immunol Pulmonol. 2021;34(3):109-111. https://doi.org/10.1089/ped.2020.1330</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi Dehcheshmeh L, Makvandi M, Timori A. Prevalence of human polyomavirus JC and BK in normal population. Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2020;21(10):2877-2882. https://doi.org/10.31557/APJCP.2020.21.10.2877</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva Nali LH, de Campose Centrone C, Urbano PR, et&#xa0;al. High prevalence of the simultaneous excretion of polyomaviruses JC and BK in the urine of HIV-infected patients without neurological symptoms in S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil. Rev Inst Med Trop Sao Paulo. 2012;54(4):201-205. https://doi.org/10.1590/s0036-46652012000400004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabrese LH, Calabrese C, Lenfant T, Kirchner E, Strand V. Infections in the era of targeted therapies: mapping the road ahead. Front Med. 2020;7:336. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2020.00336</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia CA, Wu S. Attributable risk of infection to mTOR inhibitors everolimus and temsirolimus in the treatment of cancer. Cancer Invest. 2016;34(10):521-530. https://doi.org/10.1080/07357907.2016.1242009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinwald M, Silva JT, Mueller NJ, et&#xa0;al. ESCMID Study Group for Infections in Compromised Hosts (ESGICH) Consensus Document on the safety of targeted and biological therapies: an infectious diseases perspective (intracellular signaling pathways: tyrosine kinase and mTOR inhibitors). Clin Microbiol Infect. 2018;24(2):S53-S70. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2018.02.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilar-Company J, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Ruiz M, Garc&#xed;a-Campelo R, Garrido-Castro AC, Ruiz-Camps I. ESCMID Study Group for Infections in Compromised Hosts (ESGICH) Consensus Document on the safety of targeted and biological therapies: an infectious diseases perspective (cell surface receptors and associated signaling pathways). Clin Microbiol Infect. 2018;24(2):S41-S52. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2017.12.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keifer JA, Guttridge DC, Ashburner BP, Baldwin AS. Inhibition of NF-kappa B activity by thalidomide through suppression of IkappaB kinase activity. J Biol Chem. 2001;276(25):22382-22387. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M100938200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira AL, Sampaio EP, Zmuidzinas A, Frindt P, Smith KA, Kaplan G. Thalidomide exerts its inhibitory action on tumor necrosis factor alpha by enhancing mRNA degradation. J Exp Med. 1993;177(6):1675-1680. https://doi.org/10.1084/jem.177.6.1675</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franz DN, Agricola K, Mays M, et&#xa0;al. Everolimus for subependymal giant cell astrocytoma: 5-year final analysis. Ann Neurol. 2015;78(6):929-938. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.24523</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>