<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36728816</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical and Health System Impact of Biofire Filmarray Meningitis/Encephalitis Routine Testing of CSF in a Pediatric Hospital: An Observational Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>281</StartPage><EndPage>285</EndPage><MedlinePgn>281-285</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000003812</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Rapid cartridge-based molecular test panels targeting multiple pathogens are increasingly available, improve pathogen detection and reduce turn-around-time but are more expensive than standard testing. Confirmation that these test panels contribute to improved patient or health service outcomes is required.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In March 2021, our pediatric hospital laboratory implemented the BioFire Filmarray&#x2122; meningitis/encephalitis (M/E) panel as an additional routine test for all cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) samples collected from infants &lt;90 days or from any patient in the emergency department. A retrospective chart review was done to ascertain changes in clinical outcomes, antimicrobial prescribing practices, and hospital length of stay, comparing two discrete 6-month periods: preimplementation (March-August 2019) and postimplementation (March-August 2021).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Both pre- and postimplementation groups were similar at baseline, except the preimplementation group had a higher proportion of infants with enterovirus and parechovirus meningitis. There was no significant difference between the groups in terms of median length of stay (2.94 vs 3.47 days, p = 0.41), duration of antibiotic treatment (2.0 vs 2.3 days, p = 0.25), need for central venous access (12.9% vs 17%, p = 0.38) or hospital-in-the-home admission (9.4% vs 9%, p = 0.92). A similar proportion of infants received aciclovir (33% vs 31%), however, a reduction in duration was observed (1.36 vs 0.90 days, p = 0.03) in the postimplementation period.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Introduction of the Biofire Filmarray&#x2122; M/E panel for routine testing of CSF samples reduced the duration of antiviral prescribing but had only a minor impact on antibiotic prescribing practices or health service outcomes in our pediatric hospital. The introduction of new laboratory testing needs to be supported by a comprehensive stewardship program to see optimal outcomes from new testing platforms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berkhout</LastName><ForeName>Angela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6173-7768</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory Services, Royal Children's Hospital, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Royal Children's Hospital, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Queensland, Faculty of Medicine, Brisbane. Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, University of Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infection Management &amp; Prevention Service, The Queensland Children's Hospital, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Daryl R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Royal Children's Hospital, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Queensland, Faculty of Medicine, Brisbane. Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, University of Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McNab</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Royal Children's Hospital, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Queensland, Faculty of Medicine, Brisbane. Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, University of Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Lai-Yang</ForeName><Initials>LY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory Services, Royal Children's Hospital, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daley</LastName><ForeName>Andrew J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory Services, Royal Children's Hospital, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Royal Children's Hospital, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Queensland, Faculty of Medicine, Brisbane. Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clifford</LastName><ForeName>Vanessa</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory Services, Royal Children's Hospital, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Royal Children's Hospital, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Queensland, Faculty of Medicine, Brisbane. Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, University of Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000900">Anti-Bacterial Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004660" MajorTopicYN="Y">Encephalitis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006776" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitals, Pediatric</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008581" MajorTopicYN="Y">Meningitis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000900" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Bacterial Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060885" MajorTopicYN="N">Multiplex Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36728816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000003812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006454-202304000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rogers BB, Shankar P, Jerris RC, et al. Impact of a rapid respiratory panel test on patient outcomes. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 2015;139:636&#x2013;641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liesman RM, Strasburg AP, Heitman AK, et al. Evaluation of a commercial multiplex molecular panel for diagnosis of infectious meningitis and encephalitis. J Clin Microbiol. 2018;56:e01927&#x2013;e01917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tansarli GS, Chapin KC. Diagnostic test accuracy of the BioFire&#xae; FilmArray&#xae; meningitis/encephalitis panel: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2020;26:281&#x2013;290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora HS, Asmar BI, Salimnia H, et al. Enhanced identification of group B streptococcus and escherichia coli in young infants with meningitis using the biofire filmarray meningitis/encephalitis panel. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2017;36:685&#x2013;687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wootton SH, Aguilera E, Salazar L, et al. Enhancing pathogen identification in patients with meningitis and a negative Gram stain using the BioFire FilmArray(&#xae;) Meningitis/Encephalitis panel. Ann Clin Microbiol Antimicrob. 2016;15:26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leber AL, Everhart K, Balada-Llasat JM, et al. Multicenter evaluation of biofire filmarray meningitis/encephalitis panel for detection of bacteria, viruses, and yeast in cerebrospinal fluid specimens. J Clin Microbiol. 2016;54:2251&#x2013;2261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew KL, Lee CK, Cross GB, et al. Culture-confirmed cryptococcal meningitis not detected by Cryptococcus PCR on the Biofire meningitis/encephalitis panel(&#xae;). Clin Microbiol Infect. 2018;24:791&#x2013;792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van TT, Kim TH, Butler-Wu SM. Evaluation of the biofire FilmArray meningitis/encephalitis assay for the detection of Cryptococcus neoformans/gattii. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2020;26:1375&#x2013;1379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rand KH, Tremblay EE, Hoidal M, et al. Multiplex gastrointestinal pathogen panels: implications for infection control. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis. 2015;82:154&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiDiodato G, Bradbury N. Cerebrospinal fluid analysis with the BioFire FilmArray Meningitis/Encephalitis molecular panel reduces length of hospital stay in patients with suspected central nervous system infections. Open forum Infect Dis. 2019;6:ofz119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans M, Merkel KG, Harder J, et al. Impact of the implementation of a rapid meningitis/encephalitis multiplex polymerase chain reaction panel on IV acyclovir duration: multicenter, retrospective cohort of adult and pediatric patients. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis. 2020;96:114935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dack K, Pankow S, Ablah E, et al. Contribution of the BioFire(&#xae;) FilmArray(&#xae;) meningitis/encephalitis panel: assessing antimicrobial duration and length of stay. Kansas J Med. 2019;12:1&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duff S, Hasbun R, Balada-Llasat JM, et al. Economic analysis of rapid multiplex polymerase chain reaction testing for meningitis/encephalitis in adult patients. Infection. 2019;47:945&#x2013;953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soucek DK, Dumkow LE, VanLangen KM, et al. Cost justification of the BioFire FilmArray meningitis/encephalitis panel versus standard of care for diagnosing meningitis in a community hospital. J Pharm Pract. 2019;32:36&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichinger A, Hagen A, Meyer-B&#xfc;hn M, et al. Clinical benefits of introducing real-time multiplex PCR for cerebrospinal fluid as routine diagnostic at a tertiary care pediatric center. Infection. 2019;47:51&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du B, Hua C, Xia Y, et al. Evaluation of the BioFire FilmArray meningitis/encephalitis panel for the detection of bacteria and yeast in Chinese children. Ann Transl Med. 2019;7:437&#x2013;437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Precit MR, Yee R, Pandey U, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid findings are poor predictors of appropriate FilmArray meningitis/encephalitis panel utilization in pediatric patients. J Clin Microbiol. 2020;58:e01592&#x2013;e01519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graf EH, Farquharson MV, Cardenas AM. Comparative evaluation of the FilmArray meningitis/encephalitis molecular panel in a pediatric population. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis. 2017;87:92&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Posnakoglou L, Siahanidou T, Syriopoulou V, et al. Impact of cerebrospinal syndromic testing in the management of children with suspected central nervous system infection. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2020;32:2379&#x2013;2386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naccache SN, et al. (2018) One year in the life of a rapid syndromic panel for meningitis/encephalitis: a pediatric tertiary care facility&#x2019;s experience. J Clin Microbiol. 2018;56:e01940&#x2013;e01917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messacar K, Breazzeale G, Robinson CC, et al. Potential clinical impact of the film array meningitis encephalitis panel in children with suspected central nervous system infections. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis. 2016;86:118&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien MP, Francis JR, Marr IM, et al. Impact of cerebrospinal fluid multiplex assay on diagnosis and outcomes of central nervous system infections in children: a before and after cohort study. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2018;37:868&#x2013;871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trujillo-Gomez J, Tsokani S, Arango-Ferreira C, et al. Biofire FilmArray Meningitis/Encephalitis panel for the aetiological diagnosis of central nervous system infections: a systematic review and diagnostic test accuracy meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;44:101275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pantry SN, Medveczky PG. Latency, integration and reactivation of human herpesvirus-6. Viruses. 2017;9:1941&#x2013;1912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messacar K, Gaensbauer JT, Birkholz M, et al. Impact of FilmArray meningitis encephalitis panel on HSV testing and empiric acyclovir use in children beyond the neonatal period. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis. 2020;97:115085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaensbauer JT, Birkholz M, Pfannenstein K, et al. Herpes PCR testing and empiric acyclovir use beyond the neonatal period. Pediatrics. 2014;134:e6511153&#x2013;e651e656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderpluym C, Tawfik G, Hervas-Malo M, et al. Empiric acyclovir for neonatal herpes simplex virus infection. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med. 2012;25:1278&#x2013;1282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benidir A, Lim R, Salvadori M, et al. Current practice patterns regarding diagnostic investigations and empiric use of acyclovir by Canadian pediatric emergency physicians in febrile neonates. Pediatr Emerg Care. 2013;29:273&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benson PC, Swadron SP. Empiric acyclovir is infrequently initiated in the emergency department to patients ultimately diagnosed with encephalitis. Ann Emerg Med. 2006;47:100&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>